<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_20140219" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Integrating the Parameter Configuration Tool Sample with <ph
            conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Welcome to the sample for integrating a parameter configuration tool with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. The sample tool is implemented in JavaScript. It can be integrated with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> to show you the key aspects involved in the integration process.</p>
            <p>In the following sections, you can find an overview of the resources that make up the sample and a step-by-step description of how to integrate the sample with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Sample Resources</title>
            <p>The resources that make up the sample are provided in the <codeph>oscm-integration-parameter-configurator.zip</codeph> file: </p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><codeph>WebContent</codeph> directory - the source code files of the sample tool.</li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-parameter-configurator.war</codeph> file - the Web archive to be deployed for the sample tool.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>To use the sample, extract the contents of the <codeph>oscm-integration-parameter-configurator.zip</codeph> file to a separate directory on your file system, and proceed as described in the next section.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Using the Sample Tool</title>
            <p>As a prerequisite for using the sample tool, you must have access to a fully functional <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> installation. To use the sample tool with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, proceed as follows:</p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>Deploy the <codeph>oscm-parameter-configurator.war</codeph> archive to any domain on your Web/application server.</li>
                    <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal as a supplier.</li>
                    <li>Select <uicontrol>Marketable Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                                <uicontrol>Define a service</uicontrol>, and create a marketable service. The marketable service may be based on any technical service that defines parameters.<p>Select the <uicontrol>User option</uicontrol> check box for each parameter to offer the parameters to customers when they subscribe to the service.</p><p>In the <uicontrol>URL of a parameter configuration tool</uicontrol> field, enter the URL pointing to the sample tool. Enter the URL in the following format:</p><p><codeph>http://&lt;server&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-parameter-configurator/index.html</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;server&gt;</codeph> is the Web/application server where the sample tool has been deployed. <codeph>&lt;port&gt;</codeph> is the port to address the domain on the Web/application server.</p></li>
                    <li>Define a price model for the service using the <uicontrol>Define for service</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Price model</uicontrol> menu.</li>
                    <li>Select <uicontrol>Marketable Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                            <uicontrol>Define publishing options</uicontrol>, and select the marketplace to which you want to publish the service.</li>
                    <li>Select <uicontrol>Marketable Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                            <uicontrol>Activate or deactivate services</uicontrol>, and make the service available for subscription on the marketplace.</li>
                    <li>Log in to the marketplace as a customer, select the service, and click <uicontrol>Get it now</uicontrol> to start the subscription process.</li>
                    <li>On the <uicontrol>Configuration</uicontrol> page, define the subscription details. In the <uicontrol>Parameters and options</uicontrol> section, click <uicontrol>Configure</uicontrol> to access the sample tool.<p>A modal window is displayed with the sample tool you have integrated. </p><p>If the sample tool is not available at the specified URL, a warning is displayed and the standard <ph
                                conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>
                            <uicontrol>Service parameter</uicontrol> table is displayed instead.</p></li>
                    <li>Modify the parameters as required with the sample tool. For each parameter, you see its price per subscription. The sample tool does not support prices per user, nor stepped prices.</li>
                    <li>Click <uicontrol>Configure</uicontrol> in the modal window to finish. <p>The window is closed.</p></li>
                    <li>Finish the subscription process and confirm your subscription.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>You can now continue with:</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Using the service with the configured parameters.</li>
                    <li>Updating the configured parameters for the subscription, if required. </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
