<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">

<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7">
            <title>Account and Identity Management</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                                    <p>Each registered user logs in and works in <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> in the context of a specific organization. </p>
                                    <p>For each organization, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> maintains a separate account. This <b>organization account</b> can be managed by the administrators of the organization. The user who registers a customer or requests the registration of his organization becomes the first administrator. He can add additional users and assign them administrator privileges for the organization. </p>
                                    <p>In addition to organization accounts, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> maintains a separate account for each registered user. A <b>user account</b> serves to store user data such as the user's name, email address, preferred language, and password. Each user can change this data for his own account. </p>
                                    <p>Instead of maintaining user accounts in <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            />, an organization can also connect to its own identity management system based on LDAP for user authentication. In this case, the user data is maintained in the external system. Basic data can be imported into <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> so that the users can be assigned to subscriptions and receive notification emails sent by <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            />. If user data is changed in the external system, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> automatically synchronizes its information. <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> only stores the user data and is not involved in user authentication.</p>
                                    <p>For each organization, the platform operator can specified the maximum number of users that can be registered for the organization. In case this number is exceeded, the operator is notified accordingly. </p>
                                    <p>The administrators of an organization are allowed to change most of the information for the user accounts in their organization. They are also allowed to delete user accounts, if required. Administrators cannot change another user's password stored in <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            />, but they can reset it to a new password generated by <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. </p>
                                    <p>Administrators can also organize their users in <b>organizational units</b>. A unit can, for example, represent a department in a company, an individual project, a cost center, or a single person. A user can belong to any number of organizational units, and can be removed from them when necessary. Each organization has a default unit to which all users are added automatically.</p>
                                    <p>Administrators can define which services are visible to the members of each organizational unit on a marketplace. When a user logs in to <ph
     conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
    />, he can only access the services that his administrator made visible to the organizational units to which he belongs. Administrators can assign, reassign and deassign organizational units to/from subscriptions, for example, for cost controlling purposes.</p>
   <p>To facilitate the management of multiple organizational units, administrators can appoint one or more OU administrators for each unit. For his units, an OU administrator can change the description and members, define the visible services, create, modify, and terminate subscriptions, as well as generate reports for cost-controlling purposes.</p>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
