<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Auth" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Authentication Mode</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>This is a generic topic for sharing information on authentication. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="auth_internal">
            <p id="auth_internal1"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> is installed as a platform for public access from anywhere in the Internet. Users are authenticated with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and can be managed in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> or an existing LDAP system of an organization. Web service calls are authenticated in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> either by providing a user key or ID and a password in their header, or by certificates.</p>
        </section>
        <section id="auth_saml">
            <title>SAML_SP Authentication Mode</title>
            <p id="auth_saml1"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> is installed as a SAML 2.0 service provider. SAML (Security Assertion Markup Language) is an XML-based protocol that uses SAML assertions to pass information about a user between a SAML IdP and a SAML service provider (<ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />). With SAML 2.0, Web browser single sign-on within a company is provided. </p>
            <p id="auth_saml2"
                    >All users and Web service calls are authenticated against the authentication system underlying the IdP, for example, OpenAM, Cloudminder, or Active Directory Federation Service (ADFS). The IdP provides a Web browser single sign-on profile (SSO profile) and a Security Token Service (STS). This is a Web service that issues security tokens as defined in the WS-Security/WS-Trust specification. A connection to the IdP is always established by the client (Web browser or Web service application), not by <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. The client sends a request for a SAML assertion. The IdP returns an assertion authenticating the calling user. </p>
            <p id="When_a_user_logs_out_of_a_concept_conbody_section_3_p"
                    >Single logout support can also be configured: When a user logs out of an <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> marketplace or the administration portal, a <codeph>logout</codeph> request is sent to the single logout service of the IdP system and the sessions in <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and in the IdP system are invalidated. The user is directed to a Web page that depends on settings in the IdP system and in <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, and he can log in again. </p>
            <p id="auth_saml3">The user data is managed in the IdP. Additionally, all users who are to work with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> must be registered explicitly in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
        </section>
        <section/>
    </conbody>
</concept>
