<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Prerequisites_and_Preparation_59" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Prerequisites and Preparation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>The following prerequisites must be fulfilled before you can create and publish services in <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>To create technical services for the <ph audience="shell">Shell integration</ph><ph audience="aws"
                        >AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware">vSphere</ph><ph audience="azure"
                        >Azure</ph> integration in <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you must have access to <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> as a technology manager. You must be a member of the technology provider organization responsible for the <ph
                        audience="shell">Shell</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
                        audience="vmware">VMware</ph><ph audience="azure"
                    >Azure</ph> service controller as specified in the configuration settings for the installation. </li>
                <li audience="shell">Shell scripts must exist. They form the basis for the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. Shell scripts can be provided in the following ways: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the Shell service controller provides them on an external host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> via HTTP or HTTPS.</li>
                            <li>The <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> operator provides them on an <ph
                                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> via HTTP or HTTPS. </li>
                            <li>The <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> operator provides them on the <ph
                                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> host on the file system where they will be referenced by the absolute file path. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p></li>
                <li audience="shell">Shell Scripts used for provisioning are subject to the following restrictions: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>The Script must return the following command at the end of execution: <codeph>Write-Output "END_OF_SCRIPT"</codeph>. Otherwise the Script execution will run into a timeout. </li>
                            <li>Terminate Scripts without calling <codeph>exit</codeph>. When calling <codeph>exit</codeph>, the Shell is no longer available for other Scripts and will be removed from the pool. This is not a problem, just an ineffective way of using the Shell pool.</li>
                            <li>Interactive Scripts will cause a timeout. Remove all interactive command from the Script, such as <codeph>Out-GridView</codeph>, <codeph>Read-Host</codeph>, <codeph>ShowDialog</codeph>, <codeph>-Confirm</codeph>, <codeph>PromptForChoice</codeph>, and <codeph>Prompt</codeph>. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li audience="aws"
                        >In AWS, appropriate AMIs for virtual servers must exist, to which the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> can be mapped. The AWS user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary credentials to create and configure virtual servers based on these AMIs. </li>
                <li audience="os"
                        >Templates for the virtual systems to be provisioned must exist. They form the basis for the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. <p>Templates can be provided by the technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller by importing the templates into the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database.</p><p><!--ol>
                            <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller provides them on an external host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> via HTTPS.</li>
                            <li>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> operator provides them on the <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> via HTTP or HTTPS.</li>
                            <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller imports the templates into the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database.</li>
                        </ol--></p><ph
                        audience="doc">Refer to <xref
                            href="../../OSIntegrationGuide/Administrating/c_ImportTemplates.xml"/> for details.</ph>
                </li>
                <li audience="os">
                    <p>The user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary credentials to create and configure virtual systems for your organization based on these templates in OpenStack.</p>
                    <p>In FUJITSU Cloud Service K5, the <codeph>cpf_systemowner</codeph> role is required.</p>
                </li>
                <li audience="vmware"
                        >In vSphere, appropriate templates for the provisioning of VMs must exist, to which the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> can be mapped. The vSphere user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary permissions to create and configure VMs based on these templates.</li>
                <li audience="azure">In Azure, the following is required: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>A subscription on the account of which the virtual machines are to be created. </li>
                            <li>An application (service principal) with at least Contributor permissions to the subscription if new resource groups are to be created, or at least Contributor permissions for the resource groups to which new virtual machines are to be added. You need to know the ID of the Azure Active Directory (tenant ID) hosting the application and the application ID (client ID), and have a valid authentication key. For details on how to create and obtain these items, refer to the Microsoft documentation on <i>creating applications and service principles</i>.</li>
                            <li>Appropriate images for the virtual machines to be created. </li>
                            <li>Optionally, resource groups with network configuration to which virtual machines are to be added. </li>
                            <li>Optionally, storage accounts to be used with the virtual machines to be created. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p></li>
                <li audience="azure">
                    <p>Templates in JSON format for the ARM must exist in the environment of the Azure integration software. A template defines the virtual machines as well as other resources to be deployed and the dependencies between them. For each resource manager template, a corresponding parameter definition file in JSON format must exist. It is used to pass the parameter values a user specifies at subscription time to the resource manager template. </p>
                    <p>You can find sample resource manager templates and parameter definition files on <xref
                            href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app/tree/master/oscm-app-azure/resources"
                            scope="external"
                                ><u>https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app/tree/master/oscm-app-azure/resources</u></xref>. You can use these files as a basis and adapt them as required. Additional templates can be defined with ARM. For details, refer to the Microsoft documentation. </p>
                    <p>The templates and parameter definition files need to be available in a location that can be accessed from <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> and the Azure integration software by HTTP or HTTPS at runtime.</p>
                    <p>It is important to end the base template URL with a slash (/) since the template file name is concatenated with this base URL. For example: </p>
                    <p>Base URL: <codeph>https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app/tree/master/oscm-app-azure/resources/</codeph></p>
                    <p>Template file name: <codeph>SampleTemplate.json</codeph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Template parameters file name: <codeph>SampleTemplate.parameters.json</codeph>
                    </p>
                </li>
                
                <li>To create marketable services for the <ph audience="shell">Shell</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph
                        audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware">vSphere</ph><ph audience="azure"
                        >Azure</ph> integration in <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you must have access to <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> as a service manager of an organization with the supplier role. This may be the same organization as the technology provider organization or a different one.</li>
                <li>To publish your marketable services, you must have access to an appropriate marketplace in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in your service manager role.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
