<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept
                id="controller">
  <title>Components Involved in Integrating Controllers (AWS, OpenStack, etc.)</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p><b>This topic is used for sharing parts for the IaaS controller implementations.</b>
            </p>
      <p id="cmp1">In <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          />, customer subscriptions are managed by means of the <b>Subscription service</b>. When a customer <ph
          audience="aws">creates or terminates </ph><ph audience="os">creates or terminates </ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >creates, modifies, or terminates </ph>a subscription for <ph audience="aws"
          >an Amazon EC2 instance in AWS</ph><ph audience="os">a virtual system in OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >a VM in vSphere</ph>, the Subscription service asynchronously triggers the corresponding actions in <ph
          audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >vSphere</ph> through the <b>Asynchronous Provisioning Platform (APP)</b> and the <ph audience="aws"
            ><b>AWS service controller</b></ph><ph audience="os"><b>OpenStack service controller</b></ph><ph
          audience="vmware"><b>VMware service controller</b></ph>: <ph audience="aws">Virtual servers</ph><ph
          audience="os">Virtual systems</ph><ph audience="vmware">VMs</ph> are <ph audience="aws"
          >created or deleted </ph><ph audience="os">created or deleted </ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >created, modified, or deleted </ph>in <ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
          audience="vmware">vSphere</ph>. </p>
      <p id="cmp2"
          >APP is a framework which provides a provisioning service, an operation service, as well as functions, data persistence, and notification features which are required for integrating applications with <ph
          conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> in asynchronous mode. The actual communication with the applications is carried out by service controllers. <ph
          audience="app">For each application, a specific and dedicated service controller is required.</ph>
        <ph audience="aws"
          >APP and the AWS service controller are the main components that make up the AWS integration software.</ph><ph
          audience="os"
          >APP and the OpenStack service controller are the main components that make up the OpenStack integration software.</ph><ph
          audience="vmware"
          >APP and the VMware service controller are the main components that make up the vSphere integration software.</ph>
      </p>
     
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
