<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Prerequisites_and_Preparation_59" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Prerequisites and Preparation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>The following prerequisites must be fulfilled before you can create and publish services in <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>To create technical services for the <ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
                        audience="vmware">vSphere</ph> integration in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, you must have access to <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> as a technology manager. You must be a member of the technology provider organization responsible for the <ph
                        audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                    >VMware</ph> service controller as specified in the configuration settings for the installation. </li>
                <li audience="aws"
                        >In AWS, appropriate AMIs for virtual servers must exist, to which the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> can be mapped. The AWS user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary credentials to create and configure virtual servers based on these AMIs. </li>
                <li audience="os"
                        >Templates for the virtual systems to be provisioned must exist. They form the basis for the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />. <p>Templates can be provided by the technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller by importing the templates into the &lt;codeph>bssapp&lt;/codeph> database.</p><p><!--ol>
                            <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller provides them on an external host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> via HTTPS.</li>
                            <li>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> operator provides them on the <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> host in a location whose URL can be reached from <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> via HTTP or HTTPS.</li>
                            <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller imports the templates into the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database.</li>
                        </ol--></p><ph
                        audience="doc">Refer to <xref
                            href="../../OSIntegrationGuide/Administrating/c_ImportTemplates.xml"/> for details.</ph>
                </li>
                <li audience="os">
                    <p>The user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary credentials to create and configure virtual systems for your organization based on these templates in OpenStack.</p>
                    <p>In FUJITSU Cloud Service K5, the <codeph>cpf_systemowner</codeph> role is required.</p>
                </li>
                <li audience="vmware"
                        >In vSphere, appropriate templates for the provisioning of VMs must exist, to which the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> can be mapped. The vSphere user specified in the configuration settings for the installation must have the necessary permissions to create and configure VMs based on these templates.</li>
                <li>To create marketable services for the <ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
                        audience="vmware">vSphere</ph> integration in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, you must have access to <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> as a service manager of an organization with the supplier role. This may be the same organization as the technology provider organization or a different one.</li>
                <li>To publish your marketable services, you must have access to an appropriate marketplace in <ph
                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in your service manager role.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
