<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Handling Communication Problems Between APP and <ph
            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
            <p>When the communication between APP and <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> is no longer possible, for example, because <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> is stopped, APP suspends the processing of requests. An internal flag is set in the APP database: <codeph>APP_SUSPEND=true</codeph>, and an email is sent to the address specified in the <codeph>APP_ADMIN_MAIL_ADDRESS</codeph> configuration setting.</p>
            <p>Contact the <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> operator to make sure that <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> is up and running again correctly. </p>
            <p>You then have the following possibilities to resume the processing of requests by APP: </p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Click the link provided in the email. </li>
                <li>Log in to APP. <p>APP is restarted instantly. In the APP database, the <codeph>APP_SUSPEND</codeph> key is set to <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
            </ol>
            <p>As an alternative, you can proceed as follows:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>In a Web browser, access the Web interface (base URL) of APP.<p>The access URL has the following format: </p><p><codeph>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8881/oscm-app</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> is the fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, <codeph>8881</codeph> is the port of APP. <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> is the default context root of APP and cannot be changed. </p></li>
                <li>Log in with the ID and password of the user and organization defined by the platform operator in the <codeph>BSS_USER_ID</codeph> and <codeph>BSS_USER_PWD</codeph> configuration settings.<p>A message is shown that APP has been suspended due to a communication problem with <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p></li>
                <li>Click <b>Restart</b>.<p>APP is restarted instantly. In the APP database, the <codeph>APP_SUSPEND</codeph> key is set to <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
            </ol>
        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
