<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept
                id="controller">
  <title>Components Involved in Integrating Controllers (AWS, OpenStack, etc.)</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p><b>This topic is used for sharing parts for the IaaS controller implementations.</b>
      </p>
      <p id="cmp1">In <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          />, customer subscriptions are managed by means of the <b>Subscription service</b>. When a customer <ph
          audience="shell">creates or terminates </ph><ph audience="aws">creates or terminates </ph><ph audience="os"
          >creates or terminates </ph><ph audience="vmware">creates, modifies, or terminates </ph><ph audience="azure"
          >creates or terminates </ph>a subscription<ph audience="aws"> for an Amazon EC2 instance in AWS</ph><ph
          audience="os"> for a virtual system in OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"> for a VM in vSphere</ph><ph
          audience="azure"
          > for a virtual machine in Azure</ph>, the Subscription service asynchronously triggers the corresponding actions in <ph
          audience="shell">a Shell</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >vSphere</ph><ph audience="azure"
          >Azure</ph> through the <b>Asynchronous Provisioning Platform (APP)</b> and the <ph audience="shell"
            ><b>Shell service controller</b></ph><ph audience="aws"><b>AWS service controller</b></ph><ph audience="os"
            ><b>OpenStack service controller</b></ph><ph audience="vmware"><b>VMware service controller</b></ph><ph
          audience="azure"><b>Azure service controller</b></ph>: <ph audience="shell"
          >Scripts are executed in a Shell</ph><ph audience="aws">Virtual servers are created or deleted in AWS</ph><ph
          audience="os">Virtual systems are created or deleted in OpenStack</ph><ph audience="vmware"
          >VMs are created, modified, or deleted in vSphere</ph><ph audience="azure"
          >The virtual machine and - if requested - additional resources are created or deleted in Azure</ph>. </p>
      <p id="cmp2"
          >APP is a framework which provides a provisioning service, an operation service, as well as functions, data persistence, and notification features which are required for integrating applications with <ph
          conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> in asynchronous mode. The actual communication with the applications is carried out by service controllers. <ph
          audience="app"
          >For each application, a specific and dedicated service controller is required. </ph>When APP is deployed (<codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container), <ph
          audience="shell">a Shell service controller</ph><ph audience="aws">an AWS service controller</ph><ph
          audience="os">an OpenStack service controller</ph><ph audience="vmware">a VMware service controller</ph><ph
          audience="azure"
          >an Azure service controller</ph> is also deployed and initialized. It is preconfigured and registered with APP. This service controller can be used for integrating <ph
          audience="shell">a Shell</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS services</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack services</ph><ph
          audience="vmware">vSphere services</ph><ph audience="azure">Azure services</ph> with <ph
          conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          />. Refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i> for details on APP.</p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
