<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="concept2311" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Components</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> comprises the following technical components which provide the business framework for software applications in the Cloud:</p>
            <fig>
                <image align="center" alt="Components.png" href="../_images/Components.png" placement="break"/>
            </fig>
            <p><b>Service Provisioning</b> is the interface for making applications available in service offerings on a marketplace. Marketplaces are created and managed through the <b>Catalog Management</b> component. Customers can subscribe to the available services and manage their subscriptions through <b>Subscription Management</b>. </p>
            <p><b>Account Management</b> provides for the registration of organizations and the management of the organization accounts. The individual users of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, their accounts, roles, and logins are handled by the <b>Identity Management</b> component. As users work with the services and underlying applications, <b>Event Management</b> collects specific events, which serve as the basis for reporting and billing. </p>
            <p>The <b>Billing</b> and <b>Payment</b> components are involved when it comes to calculating the charges for the customers depending on the services their users have consumed and to preparing the creation of invoices and payment collection. These components also serve to calculate the revenue shares of all participating parties.</p>
            <p><b>Process Control</b> allows for integrating organization-specific processes. Usually, such processes include approval processes and are modeled and automated with a process control system. </p>
            <p id="The_concept_conbody_section_p_6">The <b>Reporting</b> facilities offer <ph
                    id="comprehensive_reports_for_dif_concept_conbody_section_p_6"
                    >comprehensive reports for different purposes and at different levels of detail. Different types of report satisfy the needs of all participating parties.</ph></p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> provides a state-of-the-art <b>User Interface</b> for all participating parties. This includes the marketplaces, where customers work with services and subscriptions, as well as an administration portal, where technology providers, suppliers, resellers, brokers, marketplace owners, and operators perform their tasks.</p>
            <p>Some of the components mentioned above are available as public Web services and provide APIs which applications can use to integrate with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
