<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Purpose and Usage</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>This section contains a description of the purpose and usage of each platform service. For details on the interfaces and resources, refer to the Javadoc and YAML documentation. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Account Management Service </title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.AccountService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing the account data of organizations, including billing and payment information and custom attributes.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Billing Service </title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.BillingService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for exporting billing data and revenue share data. </p>
            <p>Operators, suppliers, resellers, brokers, and marketplace owners can export customer billing data and revenue share data from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and process it using accounting, billing, and payment facilities that have already been established in their organization. This is useful, for example, to create invoices for customers who decide to pay on receipt of invoice, or for managing the revenue shares of the different organizations involved in offering and selling services. </p>
            <p>The results of export operations are stored in XML files.<ph audience="doc"> For detailed information on the elements of the XML files, refer to <xref
                    href="../Reference/r_BillingData.xml"/> and <xref href="../Reference/r_RevenueShareIntro.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Categorization Service </title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.CategorizationService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for defining and managing service categories.</p>
            <p>A marketplace owner organization can create any number of categories for its marketplace. Suppliers, brokers, and resellers can assign these categories to the services they publish on the marketplace. Customers can use the categories for browsing the service catalog and searching for services on the marketplace. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Discount Service </title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.DiscountService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for retrieving discount values.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Event Management Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.EventService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for recording events which are generated during the operation of applications that are integrated with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Events can be used for billing and reporting. Examples of events are the completion of a specific transaction, or the creation or deletion of specific data.</p>
            <p audience="doc">For details on how to integrate an application with the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> event management, refer to <xref href="../Implement/t_ImplementEvents.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Identification Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.IdentityService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing user accounts, user roles, and logins.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Marketplace Management Service</title>
            <p>Java interface name: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.MarketplaceService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing marketplaces and the marketable services published on them. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Organizational Unit Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.OrganizationalUnitService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for creating and managing organizational units, their members, and the services they can access. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Reporting Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.ReportingService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for retrieving a list of available reports. </p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> offers <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_Components.xml#concept2311/comprehensive_reports_for_dif_concept_conbody_section_p_6"
                    /> Reports can be displayed at the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user interface and exported to different file formats.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Review Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.ReviewService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for creating and retrieving service reviews and ratings on a marketplace.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Search Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.SearchService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for searching for services published on a marketplace. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Service Provisioning Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.ServiceProvisioningService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing technical and marketable services in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> in order to make applications available in service offerings. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Session Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.SessionService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for storing, retrieving, and deleting <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> session data. If you need to implement your own token handler and logout listener for an application integrated with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, you have to implement calls to methods of this service.<ph audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref
                    href="../Implement/t_ImplIdentManag.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Subscription Management Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.SubscriptionService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing subscriptions. Depending on the instance provisioning mechanism of your applications integrated with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            />, you may have to implement calls to methods of this service in the provisioning service.<ph audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref
                    href="../Implement/t_ImplProvServDetails.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Tag Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.TagService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for retrieving the tags (search terms) of the tag cloud of a marketplace. The tag cloud is the area of a marketplace containing defined search terms (tags). </p>
            <p>The operator can set a value for the maximum number of tags composing the tag cloud, and the minimum number of times a tag must be used in services to be shown in the tag cloud. The more often a specific tag is used for services, the bigger the characters of the tag are displayed at the user interface. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Trigger Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.TriggerService</codeph></p>
            <p>REST API: <codeph>trigger-service-rest-api.yaml</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for retrieving and manipulating trigger process data. These data are used in a notification service to approve or reject <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            /> actions in a process control system.<ph audience="doc"> For details on how to integrate external process control systems, refer to <xref
                    href="../ProcessControl/c_ProcessMgmtIntegration.xml"/> and the online help.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Trigger Definition Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.TriggerDefinitionService</codeph></p>
            <p>REST API: <codeph>trigger-service-rest-api.yaml</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for managing the definitions of triggers which are used to interact with external process control systems. The triggers are defined and managed by the administrator of the affected organization. For details, refer to the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> online help.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>VAT Service</title>
            <p>Java interface: <codeph>org.oscm.intf.VatService</codeph></p>
            <p>This service is used for handling VAT-related tasks.</p>
            <p>Suppliers can enable VAT rate support for their services and customers in order to invoice usage charges for subscriptions as gross prices. The suppliers are responsible for setting the correct VAT rates. For details on billing and payment, refer to the <i>Supplier's Guide</i>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
