<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_E68E2024B1F6403AAA1130A39B1D4DCD" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Subscribing to Services</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>Users of customer organizations can subscribe to the services you have created for Azure on the marketplace where you have published them. This results in the provisioning of virtual machines in Azure, as defined in the underlying technical service.</p>
            <p>The following scenarios are supported:</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><b>Provisioning of virtual machines in existing resource groups</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service, the ARM is triggered to deploy one or several virtual machines to a given resource group. Within the resource group, the virtual machines are assigned to a network and subnet which must already exist. Depending on the service parameters, a new storage account can be created for the virtual machines, or an existing one can be used. <p>The customer can enter a name for the virtual machines, and - if applicable - the storage account. If more than one virtual machine is to be provisioned, a consecutive number is appended to this name, for example, <codeph>mymachine1</codeph>, <codeph>mymachine2</codeph>, etc. </p><p>Other parameters, such as the resource group or network to which the new virtual machines are to be added, are usually specified in the technical service only or provided as options for the customer to select. </p><p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the new virtual machines are ready to use. The IP addresses of the virtual machines and the initial user IDs and passwords for accessing them are output in the subscription details on the marketplace.</p></li>
                    <li><b>Provisioning of resource groups with virtual machines</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service, the ARM is triggered to deploy a new resource group with the specified network configuration, storage account, and virtual machines. <p>The customer can enter names for the resource group, storage account, network, subnet, and virtual machines. If more than one virtual machine is to be provisioned, a consecutive number is appended to the given name, for example, <codeph>mymachine1</codeph>, <codeph>mymachine2</codeph>, etc. </p><p>Technical parameters, such as network interfaces, are specified only in the resource manager template that belongs to the underlying technical service and are used for provisioning of the resources. </p><p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the resources are ready to use. The IP addresses of the virtual machines and the initial user IDs and passwords for accessing them are output in the subscription details on the marketplace.</p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>The provisioning operations are carried out in asynchronous mode. As long as the provisioning is not complete, the status of the subscription is <b>pending</b>. The status changes to <b>ready</b> as soon as the provisioning has been finished successfully. </p>
            <p>The users assigned to the subscription in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> can access the virtual machines using the information indicated in the subscription details. Azure provides different ways to access the virtual machines. For details, refer to the Microsoft documentation. </p>
            <p>In Azure, the virtual machines, resource groups, and storage accounts created for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> subscriptions are managed in the same way as other resources. They can be viewed and monitored with the standard Azure tools. Changes, however, should not be made as this may cause problems and inconsistencies between Azure and <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
