<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Required Information From the IdP</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>As is the case with the default IdP set up when installing the platform, for every other IdP associated with a tenant, you require the following:</p>
                        <p>
                                <ul compact="no">
                                        <li>A contractual relationship with the IdP operator so that the IdP can allow for Web browser SSO and secure Web service calls using a Security Token Service (STS).</li>
                                        <li>Information on the following service endpoints. Ask the IdP operator for the following information: <p>
                                                        <ul>
                                                            <li>For Web browser SSO: the SAML Redirect URL of the IdP as well as the URL of the single logout service endpoint.</li>
                                                            <li>For STS communication: STS service endpoint URL as well as the URL pointing to the MEX address (Issuer Metadata Exchange) of the STS. </li>
                                                        </ul>
                                                </p><p>In a multi-tenancy environment and when several tenants are associated with one and the same IdP system, one relying party per tenant must be defined and communicated.</p></li>
                                        <li>
                                                <p>The entity ID of the IdP system. The IdP administrator can find out the ID by retrieving the federation metadata on his IdP system. </p>
                                        </li>
                                        <li>Length of the encryption key used by the IdP. </li>
                                        <li>Information on whether the IdP can process <codeph>GET</codeph> or <codeph>POST</codeph> authentication requests.</li>
                                        <li>The public key certificate from the IdP. Request this certificate from the IdP operator and import it into the application server truststore where the platform is deployed. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </li>
                                </ul>
                        </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
