<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Required Information by the IdP</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>The administrator of the IdP system that is to be used for authenticating users requires the following information from the platform operator: </p>
                        <p>
                                <ul>
                                        <li>The unique identifier of the tenant that issues authentication requests. This ID is generated when you create the tenant. The IdP system uses this ID for identifying incoming authentication requests.</li>
                                        <li>The signature verification certificate of <ph platform="print"><ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /></ph><ph platform="help"
                                                >the platform</ph>. This is the same for all tenants.</li>
                                </ul>
                        </p>
                        <p><b>Required configuration steps in the IdP system:</b></p>
                        <p>
                                <ol>
                                        <li>The IdP operator must ensure that the correct endpoints for the Web UI SSO and STS connections are activated. </li>
                                        <li>For each tentant, the IdP operator must create a relying party in the IdP system. </li>
                                        <li>Each tenant must be registered with the IdP. For this, the generated tenant ID and the manually created ID as specified in the <codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph> parameter must be provided to the IdP administrator, as well as the URL to which the IdP is to send its responses (as specified in the <codeph>SSO_IDP_URL</codeph> parameter). The IdP administrator also requires the logout URL (as specified in the <codeph>SSO_LOGOUT_URL</codeph> parameter).</li>
                                        <li>The IdP administrator requires the signature verification certificate of <ph
                                                        platform="print"><ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /></ph><ph platform="help"
                                                >the platform</ph>. The IdP system needs this certificate for handling logout requests. </li>
                                        <li>The assertions returned to <ph platform="print"><ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></ph><ph
                            platform="help"
                            >the platform</ph> must contain user IDs and the corresponding tenant ID for each user. This is required for <ph
                            platform="print"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /></ph><ph platform="help">the platform</ph> to map the users to the <ph platform="print"
                                ><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></ph><ph
                            platform="help"
                                >the platform</ph> user roles (such as administrator, service manager, marketplace manager), and to ensure the uniqueness of user IDs.<p>To achieve this, the IdP system must be configured such that its assertions contain two <codeph>&lt;AttributeStatement></codeph> elements. The first <codeph>&lt;Attribute></codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="userid"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue></codeph> subelement must specify the user ID that matches the ID of the calling user in <ph
                                platform="print"><ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></ph><ph
                                platform="help"
                                >the platform</ph>. The second <codeph>&lt;Attribute></codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="tenantID"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue></codeph> subelement must specify the ID of the tenant associated with the organization the corresponding user belongs to.</p><p>Example: </p><p>
                            <codeblock>&lt;saml:Assertion ...>
    ...
    &lt;saml:AttributeStatement>
      &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="userid"</b>>
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue>administrator&lt;/saml:AttributeValue></b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute>
    &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="tenantID"</b>>
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue>34ffd098&lt;/saml:AttributeValue></b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute>
    &lt;/saml:AttributeStatement>
  &lt;/saml:Assertion>
</codeblock>
                        </p><note>
                            <p>Be aware that the SAML assertions returned from the IdP always need to contain the default tenant ID, even if you do not want to make use of the multi-tenancy functionality. </p>
                        </note></li>
                                </ol>
                        </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
