<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>GlassFish Configuration Settings for the Search Indexer Application Domain</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>The <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file located in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/indexer_domain</codeph> contains the configuration settings for the GlassFish application server. The settings are required for configuring the domain where the search indexer application is deployed. </p>
            <p>Below you find a detailed description of the settings. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>GLASSFISH_HOME</title>
            <p>The absolute path and name of the GlassFish installation directory.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>JDBC_DRIVER_JAR_NAME</title>
            <p>The name of the PostgreSQL JDBC driver jar file as available after installation.</p>
            <p>Example: <codeph>postgresql-9.1-903.jdbc4.jar</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.portbase</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The base number for all ports used by the domain of the search indexer application. Make sure that the port base setting differs from the <codeph>glassfish.domain.portbase</codeph> setting for the <codeph>bes_domain</codeph> domain by at least 200.</p>
            <p>Example: <codeph>8400</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.jms.port</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The port of the JMS broker used by the domain of the search indexer application.</p>
            <p>Example: <codeph>8476</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.portadmin</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The administration port of the search indexer domain.</p>
            <p>Example: <codeph>8448</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.name</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The name of the domain for the search indexer application.</p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>master-indexer-domain</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.admin.user</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The user name of the search indexer application domain administrator. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>admin</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.admin.pwd</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The password of the search indexer application domain administrator. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>adminadmin</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.admin.master.pwd</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The master password required for accessing the keystore and truststore files of the application server domain. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>changeit</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>hibernate.search.shared.sourceBase</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The shared directory hosting the search index for the master indexer node and the slave nodes, if any. From this directory, the master search index is replicated to the slave nodes, if any.</p>
            <p>On Windows, double-escape the colon in the drive specification of the path to the shared directory. </p>
            <p>Example: <codeph>C\\:/glassfish/masterSourceBase</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>hibernate.search.default.refresh</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The interval in seconds between refresh operations. At this interval, the search index is replicated and copied to the shared directory hosting the search index for the master indexer node. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>300</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.stop.waitSeconds</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The time in seconds the application server waits until a stop domain operation is executed. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>60</codeph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>glassfish.domain.start.maxWaitSeconds</title>
            <p>Mandatory. The maximum time in seconds the application server waits until it checks whether a domain is started. </p>
            <p>Default: <codeph>600</codeph></p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
