<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph platform="print">Initial Configuration Settings</ph><ph platform="help"
            >Initial configuration settings</ph></title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <title>.env File</title>
            <p platform="print">The following configuration settings must be set in the <codeph>.env</codeph> file: </p>
            <p platform="print">
                <ul>
                    <li>The Docker images to use and the registry from which they are to be fetched:<ul>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_DB</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-db</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_CORE</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-core</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_APP</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_BIRT</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-birt</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_BRANDING</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-branding</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_INITDB</codeph>: image for the temporary, stateless <codeph>oscm-initdb</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_HELP</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-help</codeph> container</li>
                            <li><codeph>IMAGE_IDENTITY</codeph>: image for the <codeph>oscm-identity</codeph> container</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>The directory where <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> data is persisted on your Docker host. The default directory is <codeph>/docker</codeph> as defined with the <codeph>DOCKER_PATH</codeph> configuration setting. </li>
                    <li>HTTP timeout for Docker Compose. You need to adjust this value if you get timeout errors during high load or network congestion.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>var.env File</title>
            <p platform="print"
                >The following configuration settings must be set in the <codeph>var.env</codeph> file:</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Connecting to the Databases</title>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PORT_CORE</codeph><p>The port of the PostgreSQL database (<codeph>bss</codeph>) where the configuration settings for the <codeph>oscm-core</codeph> container are stored. </p><p>Must be set to <codeph>5432</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PORT_JMS</codeph><p>The port of the PostgreSQL database (<codeph>bssjms</codeph>) where the JMS messages are stored. </p><p>Must be set to <codeph>5432</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PORT_APP</codeph><p>The port of the PostgreSQL database (<codeph>bssapp</codeph>) where the configuration settings for the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container are stored. </p><p>Must be set to <codeph>5432</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PWD_CORE</codeph><p>The password of the user to connect to the <codeph>bss</codeph> database. </p><p>Default: <codeph>bssuser</codeph></p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PWD_APP</codeph><p>The password of the user to connect to the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. </p><p>Default: <codeph>bssappuser</codeph></p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_SUPERPWD</codeph><p>The password of the PostgreSQL database superuser.</p><p>Default: <codeph>postgres</codeph></p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Authentication</title>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>
                    <p><codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph></p>
                    <p>The authentication mode. The value can be one of the following: </p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: Users are managed and authenticated by <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> or an existing LDAP system of an organization.</li>
                        <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: Users are managed and authenticated by an external provider such as Microsoft Azure Active Directory based on OpenID Connect.</li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>The authentication mode cannot be changed after the first database initialization of <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
                </li>
                <li><codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph><p>The initial administrator account, depending on the authentication mode:</p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: <codeph>administrator</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: A user existing in the OIDC provider system configured as the default tenant and assigned to the <codeph>OSCM_PLATFORM_OPERATOR</codeph> group in this system.</li>
                    </ul></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Connecting to the Mail Server</title>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_HOST</codeph><p>The host name or IP address of your mail server used for notifications by <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_PORT</codeph><p>The port used by your mail server. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_FROM</codeph><p>The email address to be used for emails sent by <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_USER</codeph><p>If your mail server requires authentication, the name of the user allowed to access the mail server. If no authentication is required, set to <codeph>none</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_PWD</codeph><p>If your mail server requires authentication, the password of the user allowed to access the mail server. If no authentication is required, set to <codeph>none</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_AUTH</codeph><p>Defines whether your mail server requires authentication. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>SMTP_TLS</codeph><p>Defines if TLS (Transport Layer Security) is to be used for mail server communication. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>APP_ADMIN_MAIL_ADDRESS</codeph><p>The email address used for emails sent by the Asynchronous Provisioning Platform (APP). For example, this is the email address of the administrator of the technology provider organization responsible for the OpenStack service controller. </p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Connecting with APP</title>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>APP_USER_NAME</codeph><p>The user for accessing <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> from APP. The user specified here must have the administrator role for a technology provider organization in <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. The user account is used for carrying out actions on behalf of APP in <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> and for registering service controllers.</p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, the value must be set as follows depending on the authentication mode (<codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph> setting):</p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: <codeph>administrator</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: The initial administrator specified in the <codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph> setting</li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><codeph>APP_USER_PWD</codeph><p>The password of the user specified in <codeph>APP_USER_NAME</codeph>. The password is encrypted when it is stored in the database. </p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                            conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, the value must be set as follows depending on the authentication mode (<codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph> setting):</p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: <codeph>admin123</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: The password of the initial administrator specified in the <codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph> setting. It must be identical to the user's password in the OIDC provider system.</li>
                    </ul></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Connecting to the Service Controllers</title>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><codeph>CONTROLLER_ORG_ID</codeph><p>The ID of the organization in <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> responsible for the service controller. The organization must have the technology provider role.</p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    />, the value must be set to <codeph><codeph>PLATFORM_OPERATOR</codeph></codeph>. The operator can then log in to the service controller and define the technology provider organization that is to be responsible. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>CONTROLLER_USER_KEY</codeph><p>The identifier of the user for accessing the service controller specified in <codeph>CONTROLLER_USER_NAME</codeph>. </p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    />, the value must be set to <codeph><codeph>1000</codeph></codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>CONTROLLER_USER_NAME</codeph><p>The name of the user for accessing the service controller. The user specified here must have the technology manager role in <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> and belong to the organization specified in the <codeph>CONTROLLER_ORG_ID</codeph> setting. It is recommended that the user account is used only for carrying out actions on behalf of the service controller in <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />.</p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, the value must be set as follows depending on the authentication mode (<codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph> setting):</p><ul>
                            <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: <codeph>administrator</codeph></li>
                            <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: The initial administrator specified in the <codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph> setting</li>
                        </ul></li>
                    <li><codeph>CONTROLLER_USER_PASS</codeph><p>The password of the user for accessing the service controller. The password is encrypted when it is stored in the database. </p><p>For the first deployment of <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, the value must be set as follows depending on the authentication mode (<codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph> setting):</p><ul>
                            <li><codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>: <codeph>admin123</codeph></li>
                            <li><codeph>OIDC</codeph>: The password of the initial administrator specified in the <codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph> setting. It must be identical to the user's password in the OIDC provider system.</li>
                        </ul></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Settings for Connecting the VMware Service Controller with the vSphere Server</title>
            <p>The VMware service controller requires the following additional settings: <ul>
                    <li><codeph>DB_USER_VMWARE</codeph><p>The name of the user to connect to the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database. This database stores the vSphere configuration.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DB_PWD_VMWARE</codeph><p>The password of the user to connect to the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database. This database stores the vSphere configuration.</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>VCENTER_NAME</codeph><p>The name of the vCenter running on the vSphere server. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>DATACENTER_NAME</codeph><p>The name of data center managed by the vCenter specified above. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>CLUSTER_NAME</codeph><p>The name of the cluster where VMs are to be provisioned. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>LOADBALANCER_NAME</codeph><p>The name of the load balancer used by vSphere. Usually, you can use the name of the VM Network in vSphere: <codeph>VM Network</codeph>. </p></li>
                </ul><note>Be aware that the configuration of an entire vSphere environment including, for example, various data centers and clusters, requires the uploading of <codeph>.csv</codeph> files using the instance status interface of the VMware service controller. Refer to the <i>VMware vSphere Integration</i> guide for details. The initial configuration settings specified in the <codeph>var.env</codeph> file set up a connection to one vSphere vCenter, with one data center and one cluster only where the VMs will be provisioned. </note></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Additional Settings</title>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li><codeph>KEY_SECRET</codeph><p>A string which will be used in the <codeph>bss</codeph> database as a seed for encryption and decryption of service parameters with data type <codeph>PWD</codeph> and custom attributes marked for encryption. Make sure not to forget this string so that your database is persisted. </p><note>Be aware that you must use the same key when updating the database. Otherwise, encryption and decryption is no longer possible after an update. </note></li>
                    <li><codeph>HOST_FQDN</codeph><p>The fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>REPORT_ENGINEURL</codeph><p>The URL of the report engine used to generate the <ph
                                platform="print"><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /></ph><ph platform="help"
                                >platform's</ph> reports. If you do not specify a correct URL template, <ph
                                platform="print"><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /></ph><ph platform="help"
                            >the platform</ph> will not be able to generate any reports, since the Report Web service cannot be called correctly.</p><p>The setting must be as follows: </p><codeblock>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8681/birt/frameset?
   __report=\${reportname}.rptdesign&amp;SessionId=\${sessionid}&amp;
   __locale=\${locale}&amp;WSDLURL=\${wsdlurl}&amp;SOAPEndPoint=\
   ${soapendpoint}&amp;wsname=Report&amp;wsport=ReportPort</codeblock><p>Replace <codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> with the value entered for the <codeph>HOST_FQDN</codeph> setting. The other values must not be changed. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>TOMEE_DEBUG</codeph><p>Defines if the application server is to generate log files for <ph
                                platform="print"><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /></ph><ph platform="help"
                                >the platform</ph>. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Application Server Settings</title>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li><codeph>CONTAINER_CALLBACK_THREADS</codeph><p>The number of threads for constructing and destroying beans. Required for the stateless <codeph>init-db</codeph> container.</p><p>Default: <codeph>50</codeph></p></li>
                    <li><codeph>CONTAINER_MAX_SIZE</codeph><p>The size of the instance pool for the stateless <codeph>init-db</codeph> container.</p><p>Default: <codeph>50</codeph></p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>The following settings are used for the Docker environment, which needs access to the Docker registry, as well as for the <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> containers which access the Internet. They are also used for the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container, which means that every HTTP request made by APP is processed using these settings.</p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_ENABLED</codeph><p>Defines whether the proxy is enabled in the containers. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. </p></li>
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_HTTP_HOST</codeph><p>Host of the proxy used for HTTP connections</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_HTTP_PORT</codeph><p>Port of the proxy used for HTTP connections</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_HTTPS_HOST</codeph><p>Host of the proxy used for HTTPS connections</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_HTTPS_PORT</codeph><p>Port of the proxy used for HTTPS connections</p></li>
                    <li><codeph>PROXY_NOPROXY</codeph><p>Pipe-separated list of hosts for which the proxy is to be bypassed. By default, this list already contains localhost, 127.0.0.1, and the IP address of the <ph
                                conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> installation.</p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
