<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph platform="print">User Data File for Multiple User Import</ph><ph platform="help"
            >User data file for multiple user import</ph>
    </title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>An administrator can import multiple users of his organization and register them with the platform. A platform operator can import multiple users of his own organization as well as of any organization managed on his platform. </p>
            <p>The user data must be provided in a file in <codeph>csv</codeph> (comma-separated values) format. This file can then be imported into <ph
                    platform="print"><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></ph><ph
                    platform="help">the system</ph>.</p>
            <p>The following rules apply:</p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>The data for one user is provided in one line. Empty lines are ignored.</li>
                    <li>
                        <p>The user data file is saved in UTF-8 encoding. </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>The user data is provided in the following sequence: <p>
                            <ol>
                                <li>User ID (mandatory) </li>
                                <li>Email address (mandatory)</li>
                                <li>Language (mandatory)</li>
                                <li>Title (optional)</li>
                                <li>First name (optional)</li>
                                <li>Last name (optional)</li>
                                <li>One or several user roles to be assigned to the imported user (mandatory if no marketplace is selected at the user interface)</li>
                            </ol>
                        </p></li>
                    <li>The user data fields are separated by a comma each. If an optional field does not contain any data, it must be empty and separated by a comma from the next field. </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>The fields can take on the following values: </p>
            <p>
                <table frame="all" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="3.96*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Field</entry>
                                <entry>Value(s)</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>User ID</entry>
                                <entry>Mandatory. ID with which the user is to log in to the platform. <p>User IDs are restricted to 100 characters and must not contain any of the following characters:</p><p><codeph>! " # $ % &amp; ' * + , / : ; &lt; = > ? \ ^ `</codeph>
                                    </p></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Email address</entry>
                                <entry>Mandatory. Email address of the user. It is used for notifying the user about the registration.<p>The system checks whether the syntax of the given email address is valid, and whether the domain name corresponds to the standards as defined and maintained by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA). </p><p>Examples: <codeph>user.name@domain.arpa</codeph>, <codeph>user.name@domain.org</codeph>, <codeph>user@mycompany.lan.uk</codeph></p></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Language</entry>
                                <entry>Mandatory. ISO code of the language in which the user will work by default, for example, <codeph>en</codeph> (English). </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Title</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. Salutation.<p>Allowed values: <codeph>MR</codeph> or <codeph>MS</codeph></p><p>Observe that the value is case-sensitive and must be specified as indicated.</p></entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>First name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Last name</entry>
                                <entry>Optional. </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>User role</entry>
                                <entry>Mandatory if no marketplace is selected at the user interface. If a marketplace is selected and no role is specified, a standard user without any privileges is registered.<p>The user roles that can be specified depend on the role of the organization for which the users are to be imported. Valid user roles are: </p><p><codeph>ORGANIZATION_ADMIN</codeph> (administrator) for organizations with any role.</p><p><codeph>SUBSCRIPTION_MANAGER</codeph> (subscription manager) for organizations with any role.</p><p><codeph>PLATFORM_OPERATOR</codeph> (operator) for platform operator organizations.</p><p><codeph>MARKETPLACE_OWNER</codeph> (marketplace manager) for marketplace owner organizations.</p><p><codeph>SERVICE_MANAGER</codeph> (service manager) for supplier organizations.</p><p><codeph>TECHNOLOGY_MANAGER</codeph> (technology manager) for technology provider organizations.</p><p><codeph>BROKER_MANAGER</codeph> (broker manager) for broker organizations.</p><p><codeph>RESELLER_MANAGER</codeph> (reseller manager) for reseller organizations.</p><p>Observe the following: </p><p>
                                        <ul compact="no">
                                            <li>
                                                <p>The role names are case-sensitive and must be specified as indicated above.</p>
                                            </li>
                                            <li>If several user roles are specified, they must be separated by a comma and enclosed in double quotes (Example: <codeph>"ORGANIZATION_ADMIN, RESELLER_MANAGER"</codeph>). Blanks between role names and fields are ignored.</li>
                                            <li>
                                                <p>If one user role is specified that is not available for the organization for which to import users, it is ignored and the affected users are not registered. </p>
                                            </li>
                                            <li>
                                                <p>If several roles are specified for a user, and at least one of these roles is valid for the organization, the user is imported and registered successfully, invalid roles are ignored.</p>
                                            </li>
                                        </ul>
                                    </p></entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </p>
            <p><b>Sample user data file</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>user1,user1@company.com,en,MS,Jane,Smith,ORGANIZATION_ADMIN
user2,user2@company.com,de,MR,John F.,Cool,SUBSCRIPTION_MANAGER
user3,user3@company.com,en,,,,ORGANIZATION_ADMIN
user4,user4@company.com,en,,,Admin,"SERVICE_MANAGER,ORGANIZATION_ADMIN"
user5,user5@company.com,en,MR,,Mueller-Siegel,SERVICE_MANAGER
user6,user6@company.com,en,MR,Joe,StandardUser,</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
