<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph platform="print">Online Help and FAQs</ph><ph platform="help">Online help and FAQs</ph>
    </title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>In the administration portal, online help is available in the language the user has set in his profile. The same applies to the FAQs that can be opened on a marketplace. </p>
            <p>The online help and FAQ files are provided after installation in a separate container: <codeph>oscm-help</codeph>.</p>
            <p>You can update the existing online help and FAQ files and/or provide the files in another language. <ph
                    platform="print">Refer to <xref href="../../OperationsGuide/Configuration/c_AddLanguage.xml"
                        /> for details on how to add a language to <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </ph></p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Log in to the Docker host where <ph platform="help">the platform</ph><ph platform="print"><ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></ph> is deployed. </li>
                <li>Log in to the <codeph>oscm-help</codeph> container:<p>
                        <codeblock>docker exec –it oscm-help /bin/bash </codeblock>
                    </p></li>
                <li>Copy the <codeph>/opt/oscm-portal-help.war</codeph> archive file to a temporary directory on the Docker host. </li>
                <li>Extract the <codeph>oscm-portal-help.war</codeph> file on the Docker host. <p>You see the following directory structure: </p><p
                        platform="help"><image href="../_images/HelpFAQ.png" alt="HelpFAQ.png" width="415" height="372"
                        /></p><p platform="print"><image href="../_images/HelpFAQ.png" alt="HelpFAQ.png" width="320"
                            height="287"
                        /></p><p>The languages provided after installation are English (en), German (de), and Japanese (ja). You can update the texts in their respective directories. The procedure is the same as when providing the texts in a different language (see below). </p></li>
                <li>Copy the <codeph>help/en</codeph> directory and name it <codeph>help/<i>&lt;ISO code></i></codeph>. <p>Copy the <codeph>faq/en</codeph> directory and name it <codeph>faq/<i>&lt;ISO code></i></codeph>.</p><p>The ISO language code denotes the language for which you want to provide translations. For example, add a <codeph>cs</codeph> directory to the <codeph>help</codeph> as well as to the <codeph>faq</codeph> directory. <ph
                            platform="help"><ph audience="doc">Click <xref
                                    href="../../Shared/reference/r_Language_Codes.xml"
                                >here</xref> for the list of supported language codes.</ph></ph></p><p>The directory structure now looks as follows: </p><p
                        platform="help"><image href="../_images/HelpFAQ_sample.png" alt="HelpFAQ_sample.png" width="415"
                            height="381"/></p><p platform="print"><image href="../_images/HelpFAQ_sample.png"
                            alt="HelpFAQ_sample.png" width="320" height="293"/></p></li>
                <li>Translate the HTML files. <p>Be aware of the following: </p><p>
                        <ul compact="no">
                            <li>Make sure not to change any style sheet or icon. </li>
                            <li>Do not remove any files that you do not translate. </li>
                            <li>In the HTML files, make sure not to enter tags or invalid HTML code that may affect the page layout. </li>
                            <li>Use a separate test environment for testing your translations. </li>
                            <li>Images used in the online help topics can be translated as follows: <p>
                                    <ol>
                                        <li>Create the image with an image drawing tool. </li>
                                        <li>Save the image with the file name referenced in the related HTML file to the <codeph>Shared/_images</codeph> directory. </li>
                                        <li>Check the size of the image in the HTML topic and adapt it, if required. </li>
                                    </ol>
                                </p></li>
                        </ul>
                    </p></li>
                <li>Create a zipped archive file named <codeph>oscm-portal-help.tar.gz</codeph> containing the additional subdirectories for the new language, and copy this archive to the following directory on the Docker host: <p><codeph>/docker/config/oscm-help</codeph></p></li>
                <li>Stop the <codeph>oscm-help</codeph> container: <p>
                        <codeblock>docker stop oscm- help</codeblock>
                    </p></li>
                <li>Remove the <codeph>oscm-help</codeph> container: <p>
                        <codeblock>docker-compose -f docker-compose-oscm.yml rm oscm-help</codeblock>
                    </p></li>
                <li>Recreate and restart the <codeph>oscm-help</codeph> container: <p>
                        <codeblock>docker-compose -f docker-compose--oscm.yml up -d oscm-help</codeblock>
                    </p><p>By the deployment, existing HTML files are overwritten. </p></li>
            </ol>
            <p>
                <note>You are responsible for keeping the directory structures and files consistent!</note>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
