<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph platform="print">Free Trial Period</ph><ph platform="help">Free trial period</ph>
    </title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>A free trial period defines a limited period of time in which a service is offered for free. <ph
                    platform="help">A supplier</ph><ph platform="print"
                    >You</ph> can, for example, define a free trial period to give <ph platform="help">his</ph><ph
                    platform="print"
                    >your</ph> customers time for testing a service. After this period, the customers are automatically charged according to the price model elements <ph
                    platform="help">the supplier</ph><ph platform="print">you</ph>
                <ph platform="help">defines</ph><ph platform="print">define</ph>.</p>
            <p>If a subscription is suspended and resumed during the free trial period, the free trial period is not prolonged although the users cannot work with the underlying service during this time.</p>
            <p>If the charges for a service are calculated per time unit, the time unit in which the free trial period ends is always fully charged, no matter how much of the time unit falls into the free trial period. The charges for this time unit are calculated based on the price model elements that apply after the end of the free trial period, for example, the number of users assigned at that point of time, the defined parameter values, or the roles that are assigned to the users.</p>
            <p>A free trial period that is defined for a service <ph platform="help">a supplier</ph><ph platform="print"
                    >you</ph>
                <ph platform="help">provides</ph><ph platform="print"
                >provide</ph> as upgrade or downgrade option starts immediately after an upgrade or downgrade. It is independent of whether the service from which the customer migrates also defines a free trial period.</p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
