<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="id_116">
          <title>Introduction</title>
          <conbody>
                    <section>
                        <p
                                conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_WhatIsBES_Controller.xml#concept2311/is_a_set_of_services_which_concept_conbody_p_1"/>
                        <p>OpenStack is an open-source cloud operating system that controls large pools of processing, storage, and networking resources throughout a data center. It is managed by the OpenStack Foundation. </p>
                        <p>OpenStack allows users to deploy virtual systems which handle different tasks for managing a cloud environment. It makes horizontal scaling easy, which means that tasks which benefit from running concurrently can easily serve users by spinning up more resources. For example, a mobile application which needs to communicate with a remote server might be able to divide the work of communicating with each user across many different resources, all communicating with one another but scaling quickly and easily as the application gains more users.</p>
                        <p>The integration of OpenStack with <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> provides for an Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS) solution that leverages the features of both products: Through services, which are published on a marketplace in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, users can request and use virtual systems in OpenStack. The usage costs can be calculated and charged by means of the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> billing and payment services.</p>
                        <p>When <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> is deployed, it includes all components to connect with OpenStack. This manual describes how to create and use services for OpenStack on an <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> marketplace. </p>
                        <p>FUJITSU Cloud Service K5 is a cloud platform based on OpenStack and integrated with <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />. The descriptions of services and usage scenarios also apply to this platform. </p>
                </section>
          </conbody>
</concept>
