<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="id_112">
  <title>Usage Scenarios</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /> OpenStack integration supports the following usage scenarios: </p>
      <ul compact="no">
        <li><b>Provisioning of a virtual system</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service on a <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> marketplace, the service controller triggers OpenStack to create an OpenStack instance based on a specific template. </li>
        <li><b>Suspending and resuming a virtual system</b>: A customer can explicitly suspend and resume an OpenStack instance by executing a service operation at the corresponding subscription. </li>
        <li><b>Starting and stopping servers</b>: A customer can explicitly start and stop all the servers in an OpenStack instance by executing a service operation at the corresponding subscription. </li>
        <li><b>Deletion of a virtual system</b>: When a customer terminates a subscription for an OpenStack instance, the service controller triggers OpenStack to delete the instance. The subscription is terminated in <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> independent of whether the deletion is successful in OpenStack. </li>
      </ul>
      <p>In OpenStack, the virtual systems created for <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> subscriptions are managed in the same way as other virtual systems. They can be viewed and monitored with the available OpenStack tools.</p>
      <p>Modifying a subscription and thereby triggering modifications of the virtual system in OpenStack is not supported. For more details on the supported usage scenarios, refer to <xref
          href="../Using/c_UsingIntro.xml"/>.</p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
