<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="id_112">
  <title>Usage Scenarios</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /> AWS integration supports the following usage scenarios: </p>
      <ul compact="no">
        <li><b>Provisioning of a virtual server</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service on an <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> marketplace, the service controller triggers AWS to create an Amazon EC2 instance based on a specific AMI. </li>
        <li><b>Automatic execution of user-specific configuration data</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service on an <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> marketplace, he has the option of passing user-specific configuration data to the Amazon EC2 instance to be provisioned. The data can be used to modify the static information defined in the underlying AMI. Thus, the customer can, for example, perform automated configuration tasks or run scripts.</li>
        <li><b>Starting and stopping a virtual server</b>: A customer can explicitly start and stop an Amazon EC2 instance by executing a service operation at the corresponding subscription. </li>
        <li><b>Deletion of a virtual server</b>: When a customer terminates a subscription for an Amazon EC2 instance, the service controller triggers AWS to delete the instance. The subscription is terminated in <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> independent of whether the deletion is successful in AWS. </li>
      </ul>
      <p>In Amazon EC2, the virtual servers created for <ph
          conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /> subscriptions are managed in the same way as other virtual servers. They can be viewed and monitored with the available AWS tools.</p>
      <p>Modifying a subscription and thereby triggering modifications of the virtual server in AWS is not supported. <ph audience="doc">For more details on the supported usage scenarios, refer to <xref
          href="../Using/c_UsingIntro.xml"/>.</ph></p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
