<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Customizing Marketplaces</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                                    <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> offers various features and functions that allow a marketplace owner to adapt a marketplace to his organization's standards. </p>
                                    <p>A marketplace owner is responsible for providing legal information to visitors of his marketplace. This includes, for example, the terms and conditions and the privacy policy of the marketplace that must be read and accepted by customers when they register. A marketplace owner can enter and update these texts and provide them in all languages supported by <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />.</p>
                                    <p>To suit the standards of the marketplace owner organization, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> allows for customizing and localizing the texts presented at the user interface and used in automatically generated emails. In addition, a marketplace owner can customize the stage of the marketplace. The stage is the area on the marketplace where, for example, advertisements, eye catchers, or further information can be placed. <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> allows marketplace owners to provide a separate stage for each of the supported languages. </p>
                                    <p>To adapt the layout and branding of a marketplace to his organization's requirements, the marketplace owner can customize the colors, fonts, background images, and logos displayed to the marketplace visitors. The layout and branding is defined in a style sheet and in files and images referenced by it. <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> provides a default style sheet that can be used as a basis and adapted as required. Next, an archive containing the modified files needs to be created and provided to the platform operator. The operator will upload the changes so that they are applied to the marketplaces of the owner organization. The customized style sheet must be configured by the marketplace owner in <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> to become effective for the marketplace visitors.</p>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
