<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Administrating Marketplaces</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Administrating a marketplace includes the following:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Change the marketplace features and settings. This includes the access and seller policy for the marketplace as well as the availability of tags, reviews, <!--social bookmarks, -->and categories to visitors of the marketplace.</li>
                <li>Define categories that can be used for organizing and classifying the services on the marketplace. Categories may, for example, group different types of application software, such as word processing, desktop publishing, or spreadsheet software.</li>
                <li>Define featured services which are displayed on the marketplace home page. This allows the marketplace owner to control the initial service list seen by marketplace visitors and to promote specific services. The marketplace owner can individually select services for the marketplace home page, or choose to display services and subscriptions grouped by the categories that are defined for the marketplace.</li>
                <li>Remove customer ratings and comments on services which are not to be read by visitors. This enables the marketplace owner to moderate customer reviews.</li>
                <li>Deactivate a service published on the marketplace. This may be required under exceptional circumstances, for example, in the case of an infringement of the terms and conditions. When the problem is solved the service can be reactivated.</li>
                <li>Add tracking code for monitoring the traffic on the marketplace.</li>
                <li>Change the name of the marketplace.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
