<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Containers</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p id="container"><ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> is provided in Docker containers and deployed in a container environment such as OpenStack or a Kubernetes cluster, providing for optimum performance, scalability, fail-over, and non-stop operation. The applications integrated with <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and their data may be hosted on the same system (Docker host) as <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> or in different locations.</p>
            <p id="container"
                    >The <codeph>oscm-deployer</codeph> container is used for configuring and deploying the following <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> containers:<ul>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-core</codeph>: The <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> core application. </li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-db</codeph>: Database SQL server providing the database schema required for running <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and APP. </li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-identity</codeph>: Services for authenticating users against an external authorization server based on OpenID Connect (OIDC) and providing for Web browser single sign-on.</li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-app</codeph>: The Asynchronous Provisioning Platform (APP) together with an OpenStack, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure, VMware, and Shell service controller. </li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-birt</codeph>: The report engine that <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> uses for generating reports. </li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-branding</codeph>: A static Web server providing an empty directory structure for customizing the layout and branding of <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> marketplaces.</li>
                    <li><codeph>oscm-help</codeph>: A static Web server providing the online help for the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal and marketplaces. </li>
                </ul></p>
            <p>
                <fig>
                    <image href="../_images/Containers.png" alt="Containers.png" width="400" height="195"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and APP store their data in PostgreSQL databases. For the databases, a directory on the Docker host where <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> is deployed is mounted as a volume for persistent storage during the deployment process. In this way, the data is preserved in case of container and database updates. </p>
            <p>The directory on the Docker host and the path to which it is mounted as a volume in the <codeph>oscm-db</codeph> container are the following: </p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;docker>/data/oscm-db/data:/var/lib/postgresql/data</codeph></p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;docker></codeph> is the <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> data directory on the Docker host specified when <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> is installed.</p>
        </section>
        <section><title>Container Communication</title><p>The following figure provides an overview of the container communication on a Docker host:</p><p><image
                    href="../_images/ContainerCommunication.png" alt="ContainerCommunication.png" width="400"
                    height="213"
                /></p><p>The internal communication between the Docker containers relies on the HTTP protocol, whereas calls from the outside are secured by HTTPS. The platform operator is responsible for opening the indicated ports. The containers can be addressed by their FQDN or their floating IP address. </p>To look inside a container:<p>
                <ol>
                    <li>List all containers (even stopped ones) to show the container names:<p>
                            <codeblock>docker ps -a </codeblock>
                        </p></li>
                    <li>Log in to a container using the following command:<p>
                            <codeblock>docker exec -it &lt;container name> /bin/bash</codeblock>
                        </p><p>For example: </p><p>
                            <codeblock>docker exec -it oscm-core /bin/bash</codeblock>
                        </p></li>
                </ol>
            </p></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
