<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_E68E2024B1F6403AAA1130A39B1D4DCD" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Accessing APP</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>The OpenStack and AWS service controllers are automatically registered with APP when the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container is deployed. Registration means entering the controller with its ID and its responsible organization in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. Initially, this is the platform operator organization. </p>
            <p>The platform operator can access APP and define the organization responsible for the service controller. This is usually your own organization as a technology provider. However, it may also be another organization with the technology provider role registered with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
            <p>Proceed as follows: </p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>In a Web browser, access the Web interface (base URL) of APP in the following format:<p>
                        <codeph>https://&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-app</codeph>
                    </p><p><codeph>&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;</codeph> is the fully qualified domain name of the machine where APP has been deployed. <codeph>&lt;port&gt;</codeph> is the port to address the machine (default: 8881), <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> is the default context root of APP and cannot be changed.</p></li>
                <li>Log in with the ID and password of the user which you received with the confirmation email for your user account or as another administrator of the same organization. </li>
                <li>Specify the ID of the technology provider organization that is to be responsible for the respective service controller (<codeph>ess.openstack</codeph> or <codeph>ess.aws</codeph>).</li>
                <li>Click <uicontrol>Save Configuration</uicontrol> to save the settings.</li>
            </ol>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
