<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Price Model Scope</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>Price models can have different scopes. </p>
                        <p><ph id="Service_price_models_concept_conbody_section_p_1"
                                        ><b>Service price models</b> are the basic price models. A service price model must be defined for every marketable service.</ph> Without defining a service price model, you cannot publish a service. You can define exactly one service price model for each service. </p>
                        <p>The service price model defines the prices to which brokers and resellers are bound if they offer and sell a service. </p>
                        <p><ph>In addition to service price models, <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> allows you to define <b>customer price models</b>. A customer price model can be used, for example, to offer lower charges to a long-time customer, or to make a new service available to a pilot customer at no charge.</ph>
                        </p>
                        <p><ph id="A_customer_price_model_is_spe_concept_conbody_section_p_3"
                                        >A customer price model is specific to one customer and to one service that is used by the customer. It is not available for any other services offered to the same or a different customer.</ph> When you define a customer price model, <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> automatically creates a marketable service for this specific customer only. </p>
                        <p><ph>For even greater flexibility, you can define <b>subscription price models</b>. A subscription price model is specific to one subscription of an individual customer. It is not available for any other subscriptions of the same or a different customer.</ph>
                        </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
