<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_E68E2024B1F6403AAA1130A39B1D4DCD" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Subscribing to Services</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>Users of customer organizations can subscribe to the services you have created for AWS on the marketplace where you have published them. This results in the provisioning of a virtual server in Amazon EC2, as defined in the underlying technical service.</p>
            <p>To enable the provisioning of a virtual server, the customer has to enter the name of the key pair of the virtual server when subscribing to the corresponding service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. The key pair name and the associated private key are used to securely access the Amazon EC2 instance. For details on creating key pairs, refer to the user documentation of Amazon Web Services.</p>
            <p>In addition, the customer has to enter a name for the virtual server when subscribing to the corresponding service. The technical service may specify a prefix which is preprended to this name, as well as a pattern against which the name is checked before the provisioning operation is started.</p>
            <p>Depending on the parameters defined for the technical service, the customer can choose from different options to configure the virtual server to be provisioned. </p>
            <p>The provisioning operations are carried out in asynchronous mode. As long as the provisioning is not complete, the status of the subscription is <b>pending</b>. The status changes to <b>ready</b> as soon as the provisioning has been finished successfully. </p>
            <p>As soon as the provisioning is complete, the users assigned to the subscription can access the virtual server provided by AWS using the IP address indicated in the subscription details on the marketplace in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. The users can access the virtual server according to the connection processes specified by Amazon. For details, refer to the user documentation of Amazon Web Services.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
