<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Updating APP and Controller Settings</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                                    <p>The <ph audience="app"
                    >APP</ph> software requires a number of settings for configuring its container environment. These settings are provided as environment variables in Docker files when deploying the containers. Before the deployment, the platform operator adapted the initial settings to your environment, in particular server names, ports, paths, and user IDs. The platform operator is also responsible for updating the APP settings. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details. </p>
                                    <p>You can <b>view the configuration settings </b>on the Web interface of APP, where you can also <b>change the organization that is to be responsible for a service controller</b>: </p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>In a Web browser, access the Web interface (base URL) of APP.<p>The access URL has the following format: </p><p><codeph>https://&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-app</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;</codeph> is the name and the fully qualified domain name of the machine where the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container has been deployed, <codeph>&lt;port&gt;</codeph> is the port to address the machine (default: <codeph>8881</codeph>), <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> is the default context root of APP and cannot be changed. </p></li>
                    <li>
                        <p>Log in with the ID and password of the administrator of the technology provider organization specified by the  platform operator.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li>Specify another technology provider organization for a service controller, <codeph>ess.aws</codeph>, <codeph>ess.openstack</codeph>,<ph
                            audience="azure">
                            <codeph>ess.azureARM</codeph>, </ph>or <codeph>ess.vmware</codeph>).<p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p><p>
                            <note>When changing the password for a technology provider responsible for a service controller (<codeph>BSS_USER_PWD</codeph>), make sure to change it first in the APP Web interface before the technology provider changes it in the <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal. Otherwise, he can no longer in to the service controller interface to change it there.</note>
                        </p></li>
                    <li>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> to save the settings.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>Refer to the <i>AWS Integration</i>, <i>OpenStack Integration</i>, <ph audience="azure"><i>Microsoft Azure Integration</i>, </ph>or <i>VMware vSphere Integration</i> guides for details on the available service controllers. </p>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
