<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<reference id="reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Technical Service Definition XML File</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>A service definition contains the information required to register an application as a technical service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. It is specified in an XML file which needs to conform to the <codeph>TechnicalServices.xsd</codeph> XML schema.</p>
            <p>This section describes the meaning of the elements and attributes that can be defined. For information on the syntax, refer to the <codeph>TechnicalServices.xsd</codeph> schema.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>TechnicalServices</title>
            <p>Top-level element of a service definition file.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>TechnicalService</title>
            <p>Contains all the information required to register an application as a technical service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
            <p><b>Attributes:</b></p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the application (required). <p>The <codeph>id</codeph> is the key that uniquely identifies your application as a technical service. The ID must be unique across all your applications registered as technical services.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>build</b></codeph> - Build number of the application (optional).<p>You can use this number to specify the build number or patch level of the application underlying the technical service.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>provisioningType</b></codeph> - Specifies whether instance provisioning is performed in synchronous or asynchronous mode (optional). The default is synchronous mode.<p>For details on provisioning modes, refer to <xref
                            href="../Implement/t_ImplProvServ.xml"/>. </p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>provisioningTimeout</b></codeph> - Specifies the time in milliseconds after which an asynchronous provisioning operation is considered to have failed (optional). By default, no timeout occurs. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>provisioningUrl</b></codeph> - URL of the WSDL document that defines the provisioning service you implemented for your application (optional for the <codeph>EXTERNAL</codeph> access type, otherwise required). <p>Be aware that for asynchronous provisioning, you need to use the HTTPS protocol. </p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>provisioningVersion</b></codeph> - Version number of your provisioning service (optional).</li>
                <!--li><codeph><b>provisioningUsername</b></codeph> - Name of the user who is authorized to access the provisioning service (optional). <p>Only required if you secure your provisioning service by basic user authentication (authentication with user ID and password without certificates). Basic user authentication must ensure that the provisioning service can be called by <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> only.</p><p>For details on securing the communication between <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> and the provisioning service and for details on authentication methods, refer to the <i>Developer's Guide</i>.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>provisioningPassword</b></codeph> - Password of the user specified in <codeph>provisioningUserName</codeph> (optional).</li-->
                <li><codeph><b>accessType</b></codeph> - Specifies how users access your application (required). <p>Use <codeph>DIRECT</codeph> if users log in directly to your application without involving <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />.</p><p>Use <codeph>LOGIN</codeph> if users log in to your application through <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. Subsequent interactions take place directly between the client and the application without involving <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />.</p><p>Use <codeph>USER</codeph> if the user-specific methods of the provisioning service should be used. With this access type, the application login can be controlled completely by the application.</p><p>Use <codeph>EXTERNAL</codeph> if users should be able to access an application directly via the URL specified in the <codeph>baseUrl</codeph> attribute. The application ID (<codeph>id</codeph> attribute) is appended to the URL when accessing the service.</p><p>For details on access types, refer to <xref
                            href="../AccessTypes/c_AccessTypes.xml"
                    />.</p><!-- p><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> offers the following additional access types: <codeph>PLATFORM</codeph> and <codeph>PROXY</codeph>. The usage of these access types is discouraged since time or data-sensitive applications put a considerable load on <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> and cause a significant resource consumption. If you want to use platform or proxy access nevertheless, contact your platform operator.</p--></li>
                <li><codeph><b>baseUrl</b></codeph> - URL of the remote interface of your application. Users are forwarded to this URL for service access. <p>Required for the <codeph>LOGIN</codeph> and <codeph>EXTERNAL</codeph> access type. For the <codeph>EXTERNAL</codeph> access type, you specify the external URL here. In the sample below (<codeph>baseUrl="https://myserver:7777/myservice"</codeph>), your Web application is running on <codeph>myserver</codeph> at port <codeph>7777</codeph>.</p><p>Optional for the <codeph>DIRECT</codeph> and <codeph>USER</codeph> access type. At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal, a marketplace owner can define featured services for his marketplace home page. If a marketplace owner decides to display services and subscriptions grouped by category on his home page, the specification of the <codeph><b>baseUrl</b></codeph> is recommended. It allows the home page visitor to directly use the service if his organization has subscribed to it.</p><p>Your application should provide some default content for the base URL, since this URL specifies the application's remote interface. </p><p>Be aware that internet domain names must follow the following rules: <ul>
                            <li>
                                <p>They must start with a letter and end with a letter or number.</p>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <p>They may contain letters, numbers, or hyphens only. Special characters are not allowed. </p>
                            </li>
                            <li>
                                <p>They may consist of a maximum of 63 characters.</p>
                            </li>
                        </ul></p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>loginPath</b></codeph> - Path to the token handler, a module of your application that handles login requests containing a user token (optional). Required for the <codeph>LOGIN</codeph> access type. <p>The path must be relative to the URL specified as <codeph>baseUrl</codeph> and start with a<codeph> /</codeph>.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>billingIdentifier</b></codeph> - Identifier of the billing system which is to be used for providing price models and calculating charges for the service (optional). If not specified, the default billing system is used. <p>The <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> operator defines the available billing systems and sets the default one. As a technology manager, you can view the available billing systems, their identifiers, and details at the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> administration portal (<b>View billing systems</b> option in the <b>Technical service</b> menu). </p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>onlyOneSubscriptionPerUser</b></codeph> - Defines whether an organization can subscribe only once to a service. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. If set to <codeph>false</codeph> (default), an organization can subscribe to several marketable services based on your technical service. If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, an organization can subscribe to one marketable service based on your technical service only. In this case, the supplier can still define several marketable services, but as soon as a customer subscribes to one of these services, the other marketable services will no longer be available to him for subscription.<p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal, a marketplace owner can define featured services for his marketplace home page. If a marketplace owner decides to display services and subscriptions grouped by category on his home page, it is recommended that you set <codeph><b>onlyOneSubscriptionPerUser</b></codeph> to <codeph>true</codeph>. This allows the home page visitor to start using the service directly from the marketplace home page without the need to select the subscription from the list of existing subscriptions.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>allowingOnBehalfActing</b></codeph> - Defines whether an organization can act on behalf of another organization. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph> (default). If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, an organization with the technology provider and the supplier role can act in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> on behalf of a customer organization. This is achieved via a customer's subscription whose underlying technical service has the <codeph>allowingOnBehalfActing</codeph> attribute set to <codeph>true</codeph>.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;TechnicalService   
   accessType="LOGIN" 
   baseUrl="https://myserver:7777/myservice"
   build="25.01.2010"
   id="SampleService"   
   loginPath="/login"
  provisioningType="SYNCHRONOUS"   
   provisioningUrl=
       "https://myserver:8090/axis/services/MyProvisioningService?wsdl"
   onlyOneSubscriptionPerUser="false"&gt;</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>AccessInfo</title>
            <p>Only required for the <codeph>DIRECT</codeph> or <codeph>USER</codeph> access type.</p>
            <p>Contains a textual description of how users can access your application in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. The access information may consist of up to 4096 characters. The description is required because users do not access the application through <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
            <p>For example, if your application has a Web user interface, you could provide some introductory text and the URL of the login page.</p>
            <p>The description is displayed at the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> user interface and included in the email that is sent to users of services based on your technical service. The description can be specified for multiple languages. Make sure that you always specify the access information at least for the default language, English (<codeph>locale=en</codeph>). This is also used for any language for which no separate text has been stored. </p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>locale</b></codeph> - Locale code, for example <codeph>en</codeph> for English or <codeph>en-US</codeph> for English - United States.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>LocalizedDescription</title>
            <p>Contains a description of the item's purpose in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified for multiple languages.</p>
            <p>
                <codeph>LocalizedDescription</codeph> elements are contained in the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>TechnicalService</codeph><p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface, the service description is visible to you as the technology provider and to any supplier, reseller, or broker who sells your service.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>ParameterDefinition</codeph><p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface, the parameter description is visible to you as the technology provider, to any supplier, reseller, or broker who sells your service, and to the customers subscribing to the service.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>Event</codeph><p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface, the event description is visible to you as the technology provider, to any supplier, reseller, or broker who sells your service, and to the customers subscribing to the service. </p></li>
                <li><codeph>Role</codeph><p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface, the role description is visible to you as the technology provider and to any supplier, reseller, or broker who sells your service. </p></li>
                <li><codeph>Operation</codeph><p>At the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface, the operation description is visible to you as the technology provider when updating the technical service definition and to customers when they select an operation to be executed for your service. </p></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>locale</b></codeph> - Locale code, for example <codeph>en</codeph> for English or <codeph>en-US</codeph> for English - United States.</p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
      Our Service supports you in ...
   &lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>LocalizedLicense</title>
            <p>Contains the license agreement for the customer in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified in multiple languages.</p>
            <p>At the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user interface, the license agreement is visible to you as the technology provider, to any supplier, reseller or broker who sells your service, and to the customers subscribing to your service. It can be changed by suppliers and resellers.</p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>locale</b></codeph> - Locale code, for example <codeph>en</codeph> for English or <codeph>en-US</codeph> for English - United States.</p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;LocalizedLicense locale="en"&gt;
      Please read this software license agreement ... The license terms
      are applied for the concession of the rights ...
   &lt;/LocalizedLicense&gt;</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>LocalizedTag</title>
            <p>Contains tags (search terms) to be associated with the technical service in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified in multiple languages.</p>
            <p>At the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> administration portal, the tags are visible to you as the technology provider. On a marketplace, customers can use the tags to search for marketable services based on the technical service, provided that the tag display is enabled for the marketplace by the marketplace owner.</p>
            <p>You can enter up to five terms, separated by commas. The tags are not case-sensitive. They must not consist of more than 20 characters.</p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>locale</b></codeph> - Locale code, for example <codeph>en</codeph> for English or <codeph>en-US</codeph> for English - United States.</p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;LocalizedTag locale="en"&gt;
      Documentation
   &lt;/LocalizedTag&gt;</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>LocalizedName</title>
            <p>Contains the name of a service role, operation, or operation parameter in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified for multiple languages.</p>
            <p>At the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user interface, the role name is visible to you as the technology provider, to any supplier, reseller, or broker who sells your service, and to the customers when they assign users to subscriptions. The operation and operation parameter name is visible to customers when they start to use your service and to you as the technology provider when updating the technical service definition. </p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>locale</b></codeph> - Locale code, for example <codeph>en</codeph> for English or <codeph>en-US</codeph> for English - United States.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>ParameterDefinition</title>
            <p>Declares a parameter that is passed to your application during instance provisioning.</p>
            <p>Suppliers can use parameters to make different values available to customers as different options, for example, different feature configurations or service restrictions. For parameters of type <codeph>ENUMERATION</codeph>, you can define specific options. For example, for a <codeph>MEMORY_STORAGE</codeph> parameter that may take a value of 1 GB, 2 GB, or 4 GB, you could define three options: one for minimum space, one for medium space, and one for maximum space. The options are available to a supplier when defining a price model; a customer can choose between the options when subscribing to a service. </p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> passes all parameters that you declare in the service definition to your application through the instance provisioning call. Any further processing must be carried out by your application. Especially if parameters are used to impose restrictions on service usage, the application needs to ensure that the restrictions are met. For example, if you declare a <codeph>MAX_FILE_NUMBER</codeph> parameter that restricts the maximum number of files created by a user, the application needs to track the actual number and ensure that the maximum number is not exceeded.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> offers the following predefined parameters:</p>
            <table colsep="1" frame="all" rowsep="1">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colnum="1" colwidth="1.0*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.42*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Parameter</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1"><codeph>NAMED_USER</codeph></entry>
                            <entry colname="col2"
                                >This parameter is used to restrict the maximum number of users per subscription. It is relevant for login and user access. </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1"><codeph>CONCURRENT_USER</codeph></entry>
                            <entry colname="col2"
                                >This parameter is used to restrict the maximum number of concurrent users. It is relevant for login and user access. </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1"><codeph>PERIOD</codeph></entry>
                            <entry colname="col2"
                                >This parameter is used to define the maximum lifetime of a subscription. As soon as this period has expired, the instances related to the subscription are deactivated. The parameter is relevant for all access types except external access. </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <p>Predefined parameters are controlled by <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and can be set for any marketable service. No implementation effort is required from your side.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> offers an additional predefined parameter, <codeph>VMS_NUMBER</codeph>. This parameter is used to store the number of virtual machines booked within the scope of subscriptions to IaaS services. It must be specified in a technical service definition if the number of VMs is to be retrieved. </p>
            <p><b>Attributes:</b></p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the parameter. The ID must be unique across the parameters of a technical service.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>valueType</b></codeph> - Data type of the parameter: <codeph>BOOLEAN</codeph>, <codeph>INTEGER</codeph>, <codeph>LONG</codeph>, <codeph>STRING</codeph>, <codeph>ENUMERATION</codeph>, <codeph>PWD</codeph>. The latter one can be used to encrypt parameter values such as passwords. The values will be encrypted in the database, in reports, and log files, as well as hidden from the user interface.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>mandatory</b></codeph> - Defines whether a value for the parameter must be set for a subscription. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>configurable</b></codeph> - Defines whether the parameter is visible to suppliers. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>. If set to <codeph>false</codeph>, only you can see and modify the parameter. If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the supplier can define whether to provide this parameter with different options to customers. Only if the supplier defines the parameter as configurable for his customers, he can define a price for it and the customer can choose an option when subscribing to the service. Irrespective of any setting, the parameter will be sent to the service during the provisioning.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>modificationType</b></codeph> - Defines whether the parameter can be set only at the time a customer subscribes to a service (one-time parameter), or whether it can be set or modified when updating a subscription (standard parameter). Can be set to <codeph>ONE_TIME</codeph> or <codeph>STANDARD</codeph>. If set to <codeph>ONE_TIME</codeph> or left empty, parameter options cannot be changed once a subscription to the marketable service based on this technical service has been created. If a customer upgrades to a service with a parameter with the <codeph>modificationType</codeph> set to <codeph>ONE_TIME</codeph>, the parameter options defined by the customer during the initial subscription apply. <p>If set to <codeph>STANDARD</codeph>, the parameter options can be changed when a subscription to the marketable service based on this technical service is updated. Irrespective of any setting, the parameter will be sent to the service during the provisioning.</p></li>
                <li><codeph><b>default</b></codeph> - Defines the default value for the parameter. Values for the data types <codeph>INTEGER</codeph>, <codeph>LONG</codeph>, and <codeph>BOOLEAN</codeph> are evaluated by native Java mechanisms. For boolean values, this means, for example, that all values except <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>TRUE</codeph> are converted to <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>minValue</b></codeph> - For parameters of type <codeph>INTEGER</codeph> and <codeph>LONG</codeph>, defines the minimum value for the parameter.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>maxValue</b></codeph> - For parameters of type <codeph>INTEGER</codeph> and <codeph>LONG</codeph>, defines the maximum value for the parameter.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>Options</b></codeph> - For parameters of type <codeph>ENUMERATION</codeph>, declares the possible options that can be passed to the application for this parameter during instance provisioning. The <codeph>Options</codeph> element contains various <codeph><b>Option</b></codeph> elements that have the following attributes: <ul>
                        <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the option. The ID must be unique across the options of a parameter.</li>
                        <li><codeph><b>LocalizedOption</b></codeph> - Contains a description of the option's purpose in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified in multiple languages. </li>
                    </ul></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;ParameterDefinition 
      configurable="true"
      default="2"
      id="MEMORY_STORAGE"
      mandatory="false"
      valueType="ENUMERATION"&gt;

      &lt;Options&gt;
         &lt;Option id="1"&gt;
            &lt;LocalizedOption locale="en"&gt;Minimum space (1GB)
            &lt;/LocalizedOption&gt;
         &lt;/Option&gt;
         &lt;Option id="2"&gt;
            &lt;LocalizedOption locale="en"&gt;Medium space (2GB)
            &lt;/LocalizedOption&gt;
         &lt;/Option&gt;
         &lt;Option id="3"&gt; 
            &lt;LocalizedOption locale="en"&gt;Maximum space (4GB)
            &lt;/LocalizedOption&gt;
         &lt;/Option&gt;
      &lt;/Options&gt;
   &lt;/ParameterDefinition&gt;

   &lt;ParameterDefinition 
       configurable="true"
       modificationType="STANDARD" 
       default="200" 
       id="MAX_FOLDER_NUMBER2" 
       mandatory="true" 
       maxValue="500" 
       minValue="12" 
       valueType="INTEGER"&gt;
    &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
       Number of folders that can be created.&lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;
   &lt;/ParameterDefinition&gt;

	&lt;ParameterDefinition 
       configurable="true" 
       id="API_USER_NAME" 
       default="User name of HEAT API" 
       mandatory="true" 
       valueType="STRING" 
       modificationType="ONE_TIME">
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en">User name&lt;/LocalizedDescription>
    &lt;/ParameterDefinition>

	&lt;ParameterDefinition 
       configurable="true" 
       id="API_USER_PWD" 
       default="Password for HEAT API" 
       mandatory="true" 
       valueType="PWD" 
       modificationType="ONE_TIME">
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en">Password&lt;/LocalizedDescription>
    &lt;/ParameterDefinition>

	&lt;ParameterDefinition 
       configurable="true" 
       id="VMS_NUMBER" 
       default="0" 
       mandatory="true" 
       valueType="LONG" 
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en">
        Number of VMs of IaaS subscriptions&lt;/LocalizedDescription>
    &lt;/ParameterDefinition></codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>Event</title>
            <p>Declares an event type. The application can notify <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> about its occurrence. Only required if you implemented the notification of events. For details, refer to <xref
                    href="../Implement/t_ImplementEvents.xml"/>.</p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the event. The ID must be unique across the events of a technical service.</p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Event id="FILE_DOWNLOAD"&gt;
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
         File Download
      &lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;
   &lt;/Event&gt;
</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>Role</title>
            <p>Declares a service role. Service roles provide different types of access to the underlying application. Each service role can be mapped to corresponding access rights or privileges in the application. </p>
            <p><b>Attribute:</b></p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the service role. The ID must be unique across the service roles of a technical service.</p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Role id="ADMIN"&gt;
      &lt;LocalizedName locale="en"&gt;Administrator&lt;/LocalizedName&gt; 
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
        Administrators have full access to all data entities 
        and can execute administrative tasks such as 
        role assignments and user creation.
      &lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;
   &lt;/Role&gt;

   &lt;Role id="GUEST"&gt;
      &lt;LocalizedName locale="en"&gt;Guest&lt;/LocalizedName&gt; 
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
         Guests only have limited read access.
      &lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;
   &lt;/Role&gt;
</codeblock>
            </p></section>
        <section>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <p>Declares an operation that can be executed on a technical service. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../TechProvGuide/Implement/t_ImplementOperations.xml#task_7867C3B8F2DB44B9A0965F23E1AAC43C/You_may_wish_that_your_techni_task_taskbody_context_p_1"/>
            <p>To provide for technical service operations, a Web service based on the operation service API must be implemented. </p>
            <p><b>Attributes:</b></p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the operation. The ID must be unique across the operations of a technical service.</li>
                <!--li><codeph><b>type</b></codeph> - Type of transaction to be invoked by the operation. Can only be set to <codeph>SYNCHRONOUS</codeph>. </li-->
                <li><codeph><b>actionURL</b></codeph> - URL of the WSDL document defining the implemented operation service. The server and port to be used must match the ones where the provisioning service of the application is running. Be aware that for asynchronous provisioning, you need to use the HTTPS protocol. In addition, for ensuring correct communication between <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> and APP, certificates must have been exchanged, and the server given in the <codeph>actionURL</codeph> attribute must be specified as the host name whose certificate has been registered. Refer to the APP documentation for details on certificate handling. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>OperationParameter</b></codeph> - For every operation, declares the possible parameters and their values that can be passed to the operation during service provisioning. The <codeph>OperationParameter</codeph> element has the following attributes: <ul>
                        <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - ID of the parameter. The ID must be unique across the operation parameters.</li>
                        <li><codeph><b>mandatory</b></codeph> - Defines whether a value for the operation parameter must be specified. Can be set to <codeph>true</codeph> or <codeph>false</codeph>.</li>
                        <li><codeph><b>type</b></codeph> - Defines whether the value for the operation parameter is retrieved from the technical service or from a text string. Can be set to <codeph>REQUEST_SELECT</codeph> (users can select from a list of options retrieved from the techical service) or <codeph>INPUT_STRING</codeph> (users can enter a text string for further information). </li>
                        <li><codeph><b>LocalizedName</b></codeph> - Contains the name of the parameter in the language specified by the <codeph>locale</codeph> attribute. Can be specified in multiple languages. </li>
                    </ul></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section><b>Example</b>: <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Operation id="SNAPSHOT"
      actionURL="https://oscm-app:8881/oscm-app/
                  webservices/oscm-app/oscm-app/
                  org.oscm.app.v2_0.service.AsynchronousOperationProxy?wsdl">
      &lt;LocalizedName locale="en">Create snapshot&lt;/LocalizedName> 
      &lt;LocalizedDescription locale="en"&gt;
        Creates a snapshot of the system.
      &lt;/LocalizedDescription&gt;
      &lt;OperationParameter
         id="SERVER" mandatory="true" type="REQUEST_SELECT">
         &lt;LocalizedName locale="en">Server&lt;/LocalizedName>
      &lt;/OperationParameter>
      &lt;OperationParameter 
         id="COMMENT" mandatory="false" type="INPUT_STRING">
         &lt;LocalizedName locale="en">Comment&lt;/LocalizedName>
      &lt;/OperationParameter>
&lt;/Operation>
</codeblock>
            </p></section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
