<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Getting Started</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>After having successfully deployed <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, you can follow the instructions on the <xref format="html"
                    href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/development/wiki/Getting-Started" scope="external"
                            ><u><i>Getting Started</i></u></xref> page for creating and publishing your first service to an <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> marketplace. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Accessing <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
            <p>After the deployment, you have access to the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> administration portal where you can specify configuration settings that do not match your environment:</p>
            <p>You can access the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> administration portal in a Web browser using an URL in the following format: </p>
            <p><codeph>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8081/oscm-portal</codeph></p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> is the fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, <codeph>8081</codeph> is the port. <codeph>oscm-portal</codeph> is the default context root of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and cannot be changed. </p>
            <p>You are prompted for the user ID and password. The initial credentials are as follows: </p>
            <p>User ID: <codeph>administrator</codeph>
            </p>
            <p>Password: <codeph>admin123</codeph>
            </p>
            <p>It is recommended that you change the initial password in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal (<b>Change Password</b> page in the <b>Account</b> menu). </p>
            <p>After login, the operator functionality is available in the <b>Operation</b> menu.</p>
            <p>In order for a supplier to be able to define price models and for the rating and billing engine of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> to be able to calculate usage costs, you need to add one or several currencies to the system.<ph
                    audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref href="../Configuration/c_AddCurrency.xml"/>.</ph></p>
            <p>In the next step, you can create technology provider and seller organizations (suppliers, resellers, brokers), and set up marketplaces so that services can be offered to customers.<ph
                    audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref href="../Organizations/c_Organizations.xml"/> and <xref
                        href="../Marketplace/c_ManageMP.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Startup and Shutdown</title>
            <p>When you have completed the installation of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and provided the required resources ???</p>
            <p>The containers and applications can be started and accessed using the standard utilities of ???</p>
            <p>###Any sequence to be observed???</p>
            <p> </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
