<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Controller Configuration Settings</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>This appendix describes the controller configuration settings as stored in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. For details on how to update them, refer to <xref
                    href="../Administrating/c_UpdateConfiguration.xml"/> and <xref
                    href="../Administrating/c_ChangeOrg.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>CONTROLLER_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>CONTROLLER_ID=ess.openstack</codeph></p>
            <p>The identifier of the service controller. This setting cannot be changed.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_ORGANIZATION_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_ORGANIZATION_ID=&lt;organizationID></codeph></p>
            <p>The ID of the organization in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> responsible for the service controller. The organization must have the technology provider role. It is created and initially assigned to the OpenStack service controller by the platform operator.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_ID=&lt;userId></codeph>
            </p>
            <p>The identifier of the user specified in <codeph>BSS_USER_KEY</codeph> for accessing <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_KEY</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_KEY=&lt;userKey></codeph>
            </p>
            <p>The user key for accessing <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. You receive this key with the confirmation email for your user account. The user must have the technology manager role in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and belong to the technology provider organization responsible for the service controller. </p>
            <p>It is recommended that the user account is used only for carrying out actions on behalf of the service controller in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_PWD</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_PWD=_crypt:&lt;password></codeph></p>
            <p>The password of the user for accessing <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>API_USER_NAME</title>
            <p><codeph>API_USER_NAME=&lt;userName></codeph></p>
            <p>The user name to be used to access the tenant for your organization in OpenStack. Once authenticated, this user is authorized to access the Heat API.</p>
            <p>The user must have the necessary credentials to create and configure virtual systems for the tenant.  In FUJITSU Cloud Service K5, the <codeph>cpf_systemowner</codeph> role is required.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>API_USER_PWD</title>
            <p><codeph>API_USER_PWD=_crypt:&lt;password></codeph></p>
            <p>The password of the user for accessing the tenant in OpenStack.</p>
            <p>Replace <codeph>&lt;password></codeph> with the plain text password which is valid for the user given in <codeph>API_USER_NAME</codeph>. The password is encrypted when it is stored in the database.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>KEYSTONE_API_URL</title>
            <p><codeph>KEYSTONE_API_URL=https://&lt;keystone endpoint>/&lt;version>/auth</codeph></p>
            <p>The URL of the Keystone API for authenticating the user specified in <codeph>API_USER_NAME</codeph>. Keystone is the identity service used by OpenStack.</p>
            <p>Replace <codeph>&lt;keystone endpoint></codeph> with the URL leading to the Keystone API. Replace <codeph>&lt;version></codeph> with the API version to use, currently <codeph>v3</codeph>. HTTP and HTTPS are supported.</p>
            <p>The URL of the Keystone API can also be specified as a parameter in technical service definitions. The technical service parameter overrides the setting you specify here.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</title>
            <p><codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL=https://&lt;app>/templates/</codeph></p>
            <p>The URL leading to the templates that are mapped to technical service definitions. The file names of the templates to be used are specified when customers subscribe to a corresponding service on an <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> marketplace.</p>
            <p>Replace <codeph>&lt;app></codeph> with an URL that can be reached from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> by HTTP or HTTPS (when stored on an external host).</p>
            <p>The template URL can also be specified as a parameter in technical service definitions. The technical service parameter overrides the setting you specify here. </p>
            <note>
                <p>First, the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database is searched for the template specified with the <codeph>TEMPLATE_NAME</codeph> service parameter in the technical service definition. Only if the template is not found in the database, the <codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</codeph> setting is evaluated.</p>
            </note>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>TENANT_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>TENANT_ID=&lt;tenant></codeph></p>
            <p>The identifier of the tenant for your organization in OpenStack. The tenant is specified in each request to the Heat API.</p>
            <p>The tenant ID can also be specified as a parameter in technical service definitions. The technical service parameter overrides the setting you specify here. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>DOMAIN_NAME</title>
            <p><codeph>DOMAIN_NAME=&lt;domain></codeph></p>
            <p>Optional. The name of the Keystone domain to use. A domain is a container for projects, users, and groups in the OpenStack environment. If not specified, the default Keystone domain is used (name: <codeph>default</codeph>). </p>
            <p product="oscm_ee"
                >In FUJITSU Cloud Service K5, the domain name corresponds to the contract number.</p>
            <p>The domain name can also be specified as a parameter in technical service definitions. The technical service parameter overrides the setting you specify here. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>READY_TIMEOUT</title>
            <p><codeph>READY_TIMEOUT=300000</codeph></p>
            <p>The number of milliseconds to wait for the completion of an operation to start or stop the servers in a stack. If the operation is not completed within the given time, it is aborted with a timeout error. The administrators of the customer organization owning the subscription from which the operation was started are informed by email. After the problem has been sorted out, the start or stop operation can be repeated by the customer. This setting cannot be changed. </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
