<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd" >
<reference id="Service_Parameters_114">
  <title>Service Parameters and Operations</title>
  <refbody>
    <section>
      <p>The following sections describe the technical service parameters and service operations which are supported by the OpenStack service controller. </p>
      <p audience="os">You find several sample services on GitHub: <xref
          href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm/tree/master/oscm-app-openstack/resources" scope="external"
            ><u>https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm/tree/master/oscm-app-openstack/resources</u></xref>. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Service Parameters</title>
      <p>The OpenStack service controller supports the parameters below.</p>
      <p>
        <note>All parameters defined in the technical service definition must be one-time parameters since the modification of parameters is not supported. Be sure to set their <codeph>modificationType</codeph> to <codeph>ONE_TIME</codeph>.</note>
      </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>APP_CONTROLLER_ID</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The ID of the service controller as defined in its implementation.</p>
                <p>Default (must not be changed): <codeph>ess.openstack</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>STACK_NAME</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The name of the virtual system to be instantiated. This name must be specified by customers when they subscribe to a corresponding service. </p>
                <p>The name is restricted to 30 characters. It must start with a letter and only contain the following characters: Letters <codeph>A-Z</codeph> and <codeph>a-z</codeph>, numbers <codeph>0-9</codeph>, hyphen <codeph>-</codeph>, underscore <codeph>_</codeph>, period <codeph>.</codeph>
                </p>
                <p>OpenStack generates a random number that is appended to the name to make it unique.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>MySystem</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>STACK_NAME_PATTERN</b></p>
                <p>Optional. A regular expression specifying a pattern for the stack names entered by the users when they subscribe to a corresponding service. If the names do not match the pattern, the subscription is rejected. </p>
                <p>Stack names must comply with both, the pattern specified here and the general naming conventions (see the description of <codeph>STACK_NAME</codeph>). If no pattern is given, the general conventions apply. </p>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>(host_[0-9]*){1,30}</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TEMPLATE_NAME</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The name or relative path and name of the template file which forms the basis for the OpenStack instance to be instantiated. The <codeph>TEMPLATE_NAME</codeph> is added to the <codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</codeph> specified in the technical service definition or in the controller configuration settings.</p>
                <p>The template file details everything needed to carry out the resource orchestration in OpenStack. The template must be specified by customers when they subscribe to a corresponding service.</p>
                <p>Users should not be able to enter a value for this parameter. This means the parameter should not be configurable for customers or, in case you specify more than one template, have fixed parameter options for selection. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>template.json</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TENANT_ID</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The identifier of the tenant for your organization in OpenStack. The tenant is specified in each request to the Heat API. </p>
                <p>If not specified, the tenant ID is obtained from the controller configuration settings. </p>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>6f4c1e4cbfef4d5a8a1345882fbca110</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>ACCESS_INFO_PATTERN</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The access information to be output in the subscription details on the marketplace as soon as the provisioning is complete. This information must give all the details the customer needs to access a provisioned instance, e.g. an IP address and a key pair name. </p>
                <p>The information must correspond to the output parameters specified in the template file. If the values do not match, the subscription is rejected.</p>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>Key pair name: {KP_Out}; IP: {IP_Out}</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TP_ImageId</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The virtual machine image for the instance to be instantiated. Any valid OpenStack image can be specified.</p>
                <p>Users should not be able to enter a value for this parameter. This means the parameter should not be configurable for customers or, in case you specify more than one template, have fixed parameter options for selection. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>cedarish</codeph> for a cedar image. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TP_InstanceType</b> (OpenStack) / <b>TP_flavor</b> (FUJITSU Cloud Service K5)</p>
                <p>Mandatory. The flavor for the instance to be instantiated. The flavor defines the compute, memory, and storage capacity. Any valid OpenStack flavor can be specified.</p>
                <p>Users should not be able to enter a value for this parameter. This means the parameter should not be configurable for customers or, in case you specify more than one flavor, have fixed parameter options for selection.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>m1.small</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TP_KeyName</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The key pair name of the instance to be instantiated. </p>
                <p>The key pair name must be specified by the customer when subscribing to an OpenStack service. To log in to the instance, the customer must enter the key pair name and the associated private key.</p>
                <p>For details on creating key pairs, refer to the user documentation of OpenStack.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>my-key-pair</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TP_*</b></p>
                <p>Optional. Any number of parameters that are mapped from the parameters defined in the template file. The parameters in the template file detail everything needed to carry out the resource orchestration in OpenStack. For each parameter in the template file, there must be a corresponding parameter in the technical service definition.</p>
                <p>The parameter names must correspond to the names in the template file. The string <codeph>TP_</codeph> must be prepended to the name. If the names do not match this pattern, the subscription is rejected.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>MAIL_FOR_COMPLETION</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The address to which emails are to be sent that describe manual steps required to complete an operation. If you specify this parameter, the service controller interrupts the processing of each operation before its completion and waits for a notification about the execution of a manual action. Omit this parameter if you do not want to interrupt the processing. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>info@company.com</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The URL leading to the template file or files specified in the <codeph>TEMPLATE_NAME</codeph> parameter. Specify a URL that can be reached from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                  /> by HTTP or HTTPS (when stored on an external host). </p>
                <p>If not specified, the URL is obtained from the controller configuration settings.</p>
                <note>
                  <p>First, the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database is searched for the template specified with the <codeph>TEMPLATE_NAME</codeph> service parameter in the technical service definition. Only if the template is not found in the database, the <codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</codeph> setting is evaluated. </p>
                </note>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>https://myserver:8881/oscm-app/docroot/templates/</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>KEYSTONE_API_URL</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The URL of the Keystone API for authenticating the user specified to access the tenant for your organization in OpenStack. Keystone is the identity service used by OpenStack.</p>
                <p>Specify the URL according to the following format:</p>
                <p><codeph>https://&lt;keystone endpoint>/&lt;version>/auth</codeph></p>
                <p><codeph>&lt;keystone endpoint></codeph> is the URL leading to the Keystone API, <codeph>&lt;version></codeph> the API version to use, currently <codeph>v3</codeph>. </p>
                <p>If not specified, the URL is obtained from the controller configuration settings. </p>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>https://my.keystone.com:5000/v3/auth</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DOMAIN_NAME</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The name of the Keystone domain to use. A domain is a container for projects, users, and groups in the OpenStack environment. </p>
                <p product="oscm_ee"
                  >In FUJITSU Cloud Service K5, the domain name corresponds to the contract number.</p>
                <p>If not specified, the domain is obtained from the controller configuration settings. If it is not specified there either, the default Keystone domain is used (name: <codeph>default</codeph>).</p>
                <p>Customers should not be able to enter a value for this parameter, i.e. it should not be configurable.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>mydomain</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Service Operations for OpenStack Instances</title>
      <p>The OpenStack service controller supports the service operations below for the OpenStack instances.</p>
      <p>The <codeph>actionURL</codeph> for each operation is:</p>
      <p>
        <codeblock>http://oscm-app:8880/oscm-app/webservices/oscm-app/oscm-app
         /org.oscm.app.v2_0.service.AsynchronousOperationProxy?wsdl</codeblock>
      </p>
      <p><codeph>&lt;oscm-app></codeph> and <codeph>&lt;8880></codeph> are the server and port of the container where the OpenStack service controller is deployed.</p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SUSPEND_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</b></p>
                <p>Suspends the OpenStack instance.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>RESUME_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</b></p>
                <p>Resumes the OpenStack instance if it was suspended.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>START_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</b></p>
                <p>Starts all servers in the OpenStack instance that were stopped. For this operation, a timeout value can be configured in the controller configuration settings.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>STOP_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</b></p>
                <p>Stops all servers in the OpenStack instance that were started. For this operation, a timeout value can be configured in the controller configuration settings.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <note>If you provision virtual systems that do not support some of these operations or do not contain servers that can be started and stopped, make sure that you remove the corresponding service operations from the technical service definition. <p>FUJITSU Cloud Service K5 does not support the <codeph>SUSPEND_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</codeph> and <codeph>RESUME_VIRTUAL_SYSTEM</codeph> operations.</p></note>
    </section>
  </refbody>
</reference>
