<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE topic PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Topic//EN" "topic.dtd"
[
<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC "-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc" "entities.dtd">
]>
<topic id="bkinfoa">
  <title/>
  <body>
    <table frame="none">
      <tgroup cols="2">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="2.04*"/>
        <tbody valign="top">
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1"/>
            <entry colname="col2"/>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1">Trademarks</entry>
            <entry colname="col2"
                >LINUX is a registered trademark of Linus Torvalds. <p>Open Service Catalog Manager is a registered trademark of FUJITSU LIMITED. </p><p>The OpenStack Word Mark and OpenStack logo are registered trademarks/service marks or trademarks/service marks of the OpenStack Foundation in the United States and other countries and are used with the OpenStack Foundation's permission.</p><p>Apache Tomcat, Tomcat, and Apache are trademarks of The Apache Software Foundation.</p><p>Java is a registered trademark of Oracle and/or its affiliates. </p><p>UNIX is a registered trademark of the Open Group in the United States and in other countries. </p><p>Other company names and product names are trademarks or registered trademarks of their respective owners. </p></entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1"/>
            <entry colname="col2"/>
          </row>
          <row product="oscm_ee">
            <entry colname="col1">Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE  TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018</entry>
            <entry colname="col2"
              >All rights reserved, including those of translation into other languages. No part of this manual may be reproduced in any form whatsoever without the written permission of FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
      <tgroup product="oscm_ce" cols="1">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="*"/>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1"/>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
      <tgroup cols="1">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1">High Risk Activity</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1"
              >The Customer acknowledges and agrees that the Product is designed, developed and manufactured as contemplated for general use, including without limitation, general office use, personal use, household use, and ordinary industrial use, but is not designed, developed and manufactured as contemplated for use accompanying fatal risks or dangers that, unless extremely high safety is secured, could lead directly to death, personal injury, severe physical damage or other loss (hereinafter "High Safety Required Use"), including without limitation, nuclear reaction control in nuclear facility, aircraft flight control, air traffic control, mass transport control, medical life support system, missile launch control in weapon system. The Customer shall not use the Product without securing the sufficient safety required for the High Safety Required Use. In addition, FUJITSU (or other affiliate's name) shall not be liable against the Customer and/or any third party for any claims or damages arising in connection with the High Safety Required Use of the Product. </entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
      <tgroup cols="1">
        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="*"/>
        <thead>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1">Export Restrictions</entry>
          </row>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry colname="col1"
              >Exportation/release of this document may require necessary procedures in accordance with the regulations of your resident country and/or US export control laws.</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </body>
</topic>
