<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_CC3DFA9536824295B364E161B9DCC6F1" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Preparing Applications for Usage in a SaaS Model</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>An application that is to be offered in a SaaS model should take the following aspects into consideration:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>A remote interface by which users can access the application from anywhere in the Web (Internet/Intranet). This may be, for example, a Web user interface or a Web service.</li>
                <li>Multi-tenancy at least with respect to the management of data: <ph
                        conref="../../TechProvGuide/Intro/c_Prepare.xml#concept_CC3DFA9536824295B364E161B9DCC6F1/The_data_of_different_custome_concept_conbody_section_3_p"
                            /><p><ph
                            conref="../../TechProvGuide/Intro/c_Prepare.xml#concept_CC3DFA9536824295B364E161B9DCC6F1/In_concept_conbody_section_3_p"/>
                        <ph
                            conref="../../TechProvGuide/Intro/c_Prepare.xml#concept_CC3DFA9536824295B364E161B9DCC6F1/Possible_solutions_range_from_concept_conbody_section_3_p"
                        /></p></li>
                <li>High scalability, because the number of users, performance, and space requirements may differ to a great extent for each customer.</li>
                <li>High availability, ideally 24x7. It is usually required to host an application in a professional data center that takes care of non-stop operation, backup, data security, and regular maintenance.</li>
                <li>Security aspects such as the following: Web service calls between <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and an application can be sent as plain text containing a user ID and password. For secure communication, the usage of certificates is recommended. </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Technology providers may have to adapt their applications to fulfill these recommendations. They do this in their own development environments using their own tools and facilities. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
