<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Layout and Branding</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> allows you to customize the layout and branding of a marketplace to suit your organization's standards and requirements. This includes the colors, fonts, background images, and logos displayed to the marketplace visitors. </p>
            <p>You define the layout and branding of a marketplace in a style sheet and in files and images referenced by it. <ph
                    conref="../../help/tasks/shop_customizeBrand.xml#task55550/The_best_way_to_create_an_app_task_taskbody_context_p_1_ph"
                /></p>
            <p
                conref="../../help/tasks/shop_customizeBrand.xml#task55550/The_platform_s_default_style_task_taskbody_context_p_2"/>
            <p>Proceed as follows: </p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal. </li>
                    <li>Download the branding package by using the <uicontrol>Customize layout</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal. The branding package is provided as a ZIP file. </li>
                    <li>Extract the ZIP file to a local directory.</li>
                    <li>Adapt the files as desired. </li>
                    <li>Create an archive (ZIP) containing your customized files. <p>The customized branding must have the same structure as the original branding in the <codeph>branding-package.zip</codeph> file.</p></li>
                    <li>Provide this archive to the platform operator so that he can deploy your customized branding package. </li>
                    <li>Ask the platform operator for the URL of the deployed customized style sheet. </li>
                    <li>To load the customized layout: <ol>
                            <li>On the <uicontrol>Customize layout</uicontrol> page, select the marketplace and enter the URL provided by the platform operator pointing to your customized style sheet. If no URL is set, the default style sheet is used. <p>By default, the URL is as follows: </p><p><codeph>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8443/&lt;new-folder-name>/css/mp.css</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> is the fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, <codeph>8443</codeph> is the port. Omit the port if <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> is operated with its proxy. <codeph>&lt;new-folder-name></codeph> is the name of the folder containing the customized files. </p></li>
                            <li>To verify the branding, go to the respective marketplace and log in again. </li>
                        </ol></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
