<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Texts</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> allows you to customize various texts that are provided on a marketplace. You can adapt the following:<ul>
                                        <li>User interface texts, email texts, messages</li>
                                        <li>Terms and conditions and privacy policy</li>
                                        <li>Imprint</li>
                                </ul></p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>User Interface Texts, Email Texts, Messages</title>
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> supports you in customizing the texts used at the user interface, such as menu options, dialog fields, buttons, or messages. This includes:</p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>The user interface your customers work with when they visit your marketplace, register with <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, and use services on your marketplace.</li>
                                <li>The administration portal you use to manage a marketplace. </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>In addition, <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> allows you to customize the texts used in automatically generated emails. </p>
                        <p>Translations for the texts can be provided in all languages supported by <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />. If a language is to be added to <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, contact the platform operator. </p>
                        <p>You can export the current texts to a Microsoft Excel file, and change or translate them in the file as desired. To apply your changes, you just import the customized and localized file to <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />. As soon as you have saved the file contents in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, the changes are visible.</p>
                        <!--note><ph
                                        conref="../../help/tasks/shop_translations.xml#task634/The_customized_texts_of_the_u_task_taskbody_result_note_ph"
                                />
                        </note-->
                        <p>To export and later import the texts, use the <uicontrol>Customize texts</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal.</p>
                        <p>
                                <note>
                                        <p>When an operator upgrades to a new release of the platform, new keys may have been added to the system, others may have been changed or deleted. Your customized texts are not overwritten by the upgrade. However, be aware that you need to check for changes, and it may be necessary to update your customizations. </p>
                                        <p>Make sure to have a backup of your changes. After the upgrade, export the texts again and save them to a new file. Compare the new file with the one containing your previous customizations and make the necessary changes. Then import your customized file again. </p>
                                </note>
                        </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy</title>
                        <p>The terms and conditions and the privacy policy have to be accepted by users when they register with <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> on a marketplace. Links to the terms and conditions and the privacy policy are provided at the bottom of each marketplace Web page.</p>
                        <p>You can enter the texts for the terms and conditions and the privacy policy directly in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />. The texts can be provided in all languages supported by <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
                        <p>To enter, update, or localize the terms and conditions and the privacy policy, use the <uicontrol>Customize texts</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal. </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Imprint</title>
                        <p>The imprint of a marketplace can be accessed by users via a link at the bottom of each marketplace Web page.</p>
                        <p>You can enter the URL of a Web page that shows the imprint. Different URLs can be specified for different languages.</p>
                        <p>To enter, update, or localize the URL pointing to the imprint, use the <uicontrol>Customize texts</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal.</p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
