<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Retrieving Logging Information</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>For each running container, <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> writes its logging information into a dedicated log file on the storage volume for each container. New messages are continually appended to the log file at runtime.</p>
            <p>
                <note>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> deployer creates empty log files in a dedicated directory on the Docker host: <p><codeph>/docker/logs/&lt;container_name>/&lt;container_name>.out.log</codeph></p>Log information is, however, only written to these files if you configure <codeph>docker-compose</codeph> and <codeph>syslog</codeph> on your Docker host to write the container logs to these files. By default, Docker uses the <codeph>json-file</codeph> driver to record the logs of your containers. The log output in JSON format can be found in <codeph>/var/lib/docker/containers/&lt;container-id>/&lt;container-id>-json.log.</codeph> For more information on log handling, refer to the Docker documentation.</note>
            </p>
            <p>To show all running containers, execute the following command on the VM where <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> has been deployed: </p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>docker ps</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>To show the logs of a specific container: <p>
                <codeblock>docker logs -f &lt;container name></codeblock>
            </p><p>For example: </p><p>
                <codeblock>docker logs -f oscm-core</codeblock>
            </p><p>In addition to entries in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> log files, you can find application server-specific log entries by logging in to the individual containers. Be aware that these are available only if you set the <codeph>TOMEE_DEBUG</codeph> configuration setting in the <codeph>.env</codeph> configuration file to <codeph>true</codeph>. To view the logs, log in to the respective container as follows: </p><p>
                <codeblock>docker exec -it &lt;container name> /bin/bash</codeblock>
            </p><p>For example:</p><p>
                <codeblock>docker exec -it oscm-core /bin/bash</codeblock>
            </p><p>You find the logs in the following directory: </p><p><codeph>/opt/apache-tomee/logs</codeph></p></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
