<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring the Log Level</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> supports the following types of log information with their corresponding log level: <ul>
                    <li><b>ERROR</b>: Problems that do not allow to continue working with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> in the current transaction or that indicate an issue which must be solved. With the <codeph>ERROR</codeph> log level set, the log file contains all exceptions that occurred at runtime with a complete stack trace. </li>
                    <li><b>WARN</b>: Problems that allow for the completion of an operation, irrespective of whether the operation is completed fully or only partially. For example, an email could not be sent. With the <codeph>WARN</codeph> log level set, the log file comprises all messages of type <codeph>WARN</codeph> and <codeph>ERROR</codeph>. </li>
                    <li><b>INFO</b>: Basic information such as the state of the server, whether it was started or stopped, whether a user logged in. With the <codeph>INFO</codeph> log level set, the log file comprises all messages of type <codeph>INFO</codeph>, <codeph>WARN</codeph>, and <codeph>ERROR</codeph>. </li>
                    <li><b>DEBUG</b>: Detailed information with references to the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> implementation, mainly start and exit of methods as well as proposals of how to solve the problem. With the <codeph>DEBUG</codeph> log level set, the log file comprises all messages.</li>
                </ul></p>
            <p><b>To change the log level</b>: </p>
            <p>Proceed as described in <xref href="../Configuration/c_UpdateConfiguration.xml"
                    /> and add the <codeph>LOG_LEVEL</codeph> configuration setting to the <codeph>var.env</codeph> file. You can set its value to <codeph>INFO</codeph>, <codeph>DEBUG</codeph>, <codeph>WARNING</codeph>, or <codeph>ERROR</codeph> respectively.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
