<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Relational_Database_63" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Relational Database<ph audience="BSS">s</ph></title>
    <conbody>
        <section><ph audience="BSS"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> stores its data in relational databases.</ph><ph audience="app"
                >APP stores its data in a relational database.</ph><ph audience="aws"
                >The AWS integration software stores its data in a relational database.</ph><ph audience="os"
                >The OpenStack integration software stores its data in a relational database.</ph><ph audience="ror"
                >The ROR integration software stores its data in a relational database.</ph><ph audience="tps5"
                >The TPS5 integration software stores its data in a relational database.</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                >The vSphere integration software stores its data in a relational database. An additional relational database is used to store the vSphere configuration for use by the VMware service controller.</ph> The following database management system (DBMS) is supported:<p>PostgreSQL, version 9.1.12.</p><p>Install the DBMS as described in its documentation. </p><p
                audience="BSS">It is recommended that you use a separate machine for the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> databases. </p><p
                audience="app">If required, you can use a separate machine for the APP database.</p><p audience="aws"
                >If required, you can use a separate machine for the AWS integration database.</p><p audience="os"
                >If required, you can use a separate machine for the OpenStack integration database.</p><p
                audience="ror">If required, you can use a separate machine for the ROR integration database.</p><p
                audience="tps5">If required, you can use a separate machine for the TPS5 integration database.</p><p
                audience="vmware"
            >If required, you can use a separate machine for the vSphere integration databases.</p></section>
        <section>
            <title>Setup and Configuration</title>
            <p>Edit the file</p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;postgres_dir>/data/postgresql.conf</codeph></p>
            <p>as follows (<codeph>&lt;postgres_dir></codeph> is the PostgreSQL installation directory): </p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>Set the <codeph>max_prepared_transactions</codeph> property value to <codeph>50</codeph>.</li>
                    <li>Set the <codeph>max_connections</codeph> property value to <codeph>210</codeph>. <p>This property determines the maximum number of concurrent connections to the database server.</p><p>Note the following: This setting is used in combination with the JDBC pool size settings for the domains on your application server. If you change the JDBC pool size, you might need to adapt the <codeph>max_connections</codeph> setting. Refer to the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>
                            <i>Operator's Guide</i>, section <i>Tuning Performance</i>, for details.</p></li>
                    <li>Set the <codeph>listen_addresses</codeph> property value: <p>Specify the IP addresses of all application servers on which the database server is to listen for connections from client applications. If you use the entry <codeph>'*'</codeph>, which corresponds to all available IP addresses, you must be aware of possible security holes. </p></li>
                    <li>Save the file. </li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>If you use a server name in all configuration files instead of <codeph>localhost</codeph> during installation, edit the file </p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;postgres_dir>/data/pg_hba.conf</codeph>
            </p>
            <p>as follows (<codeph>&lt;postgres_dir></codeph> is the PostgreSQL installation directory):</p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li><ph>Add the IP address of the application server that is to host </ph><ph audience="BSS">the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> application</ph><ph audience="app">APP</ph><ph audience="ror"
                            >the ROR integration software</ph><ph audience="aws">the AWS integration software</ph><ph
                            audience="os">the OpenStack integration software</ph><ph audience="tps5"
                            >the TPS5 integration software</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                            >the vSphere integration software</ph>.<p>For example:</p><p>
                            <codeblock>host all all 123.123.12.1/32 md5 </codeblock>
                        </p><p>Also add the application server's IPv6 address. </p><p>For example: </p><p>
                            <codeblock>host all all fe80::cdfb:b6ed:9b38:cf17/128 md5</codeblock>
                        </p><p>There are authentication methods other than <codeph>md5</codeph>. For details, refer to the PostgreSQL documentation. </p></li>
                    <li><ph>Save the file.</ph></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>Restart your PostgreSQL server for the changes to take effect.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
