<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Application_Server_62"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Application Server<ph audience="BSS">s</ph></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <title><ph audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
        </section>
        <section id="must_be_deployed_on_an_appli_concept_conbody_section">
            <p><ph audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph
                    audience="app">APP</ph><ph audience="ror">The ROR integration software</ph><ph audience="aws"
                    >The AWS integration software</ph><ph audience="os">The OpenStack integration software</ph><ph
                    audience="tps5">The TPS5 integration software</ph>
                <ph audience="vmware">The vSphere integration software</ph>
                <ph id="must_be_deployed_on_an_applic_concept_conbody_section_p_1"
                    >must be deployed on an application server compatible with Java EE version 7. The following application server is supported:</ph></p>
            <p id="Oracle_GlassFish_Server_vers_concept_conbody_section_p_2">Oracle GlassFish Server, version 4.1.1.</p>
            <p audience="app">You can deploy APP on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <p audience="ror">You can deploy the ROR integration software on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <p audience="aws">You can deploy the AWS integration software on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <p audience="os">You can deploy the OpenStack integration software on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <p audience="tps5">You can deploy the TPS5 integration software on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <p audience="vmware"
                    >You can deploy the vSphere integration software on the application server you use for <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. Alternatively, you can use a separate application server installation.</p>
            <note>Before installing GlassFish, make sure that the <codeph>JAVA_HOME</codeph> environment variable points to a Java Development Kit (JDK), version 8, 64 bit. </note>
            <p>Proceed as follows: </p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Install the application server as described in its documentation, and configure it as required by your environment. <p>
                        <note>Make sure that the path of the GlassFish installation directory does not contain blanks. </note>
                    </p></li>
                <li>
                    <p>After you have configured GlassFish, make a backup copy of the GlassFish installation. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>Make sure that GlassFish is running in a JDK 8 environment. Also, make sure that no other applications (e.g. Tomcat) are running on your GlassFish ports.</p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            <p audience="app"
                    >The installation of APP creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="ror"
                    >The installation of the ROR integration software creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="aws"
                    >The installation of the AWS integration software creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="os"
                    >The installation of the OpenStack integration software creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="tps5"
                    >The installation of the TPS5 integration software creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="vmware"
                    >The installation of the vSphere integration software creates the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server. If required, you can change the domain name in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file before starting the installation.</p>
            <p audience="BSS"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> requires two domains in the application server: <ul>
                    <li>One for the actual <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> application (<codeph>bes-domain</codeph>).</li>
                    <li>One for the search indexer application (<codeph>master-indexer-domain</codeph>). <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> applies a master/slave search architecture: Every slave node delegates its index-related work to the master node. The slave node is where the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> application runs; the master node is where the search indexer application runs. </li>
                </ul></p>
            <p audience="BSS">Both domains can be created by running the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> installation scripts.</p>
            <p>In the subsequent sections, <codeph>&lt;GLASSFISH_HOME&gt;</codeph> is the installation directory of GlassFish.</p>
            <p>
                <note audience="BSS"><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> can be operated in a multi-node environment: You can install several <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> domains communicating with one search indexer application domain. In this case, a load balancer must be configured for handling and distributing the load on the various nodes. In case you want to set up a multi-node environment, refer to the relevant documentation (application server, load balancer)<ph
                        product="oscm_ee">, or contact your Fujitsu support organization</ph>.</note>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section audience="BSS">
            <title>BIRT Report Engine</title>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            /> uses BIRT to generate reports. <ph product="oscm_ce">BIRT is not included in the <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            /> packages.</ph><ph product="oscm_ee">BIRT is included in the <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            /> packages.</ph> BIRT needs to be deployed on a different application server than <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. The following application servers are supported: </p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Oracle GlassFish Server, version 3</li>
                    <li>Apache Tomcat, version 8</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>Install the application server as described in its documentation, and configure it as required by your environment.</p>
            <p>In the subsequent sections, <codeph>&lt;GLASSFISH3_HOME></codeph> is the installation directory of GlassFish, version 3, and <codeph>&lt;TOMCAT_HOME></codeph> is the installation directory of Apache Tomcat, respectively.</p>
        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
