<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Prerequisites_and_Preparation_59" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and <ph audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph
            audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph audience="vmware"
            >vSphere</ph></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <ul>
                <li>You must have access to a fully functional <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> installation. You can install the <ph audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph
                        audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                    >vSphere</ph> integration software in the same environment or on a different server. </li>
                <li>
                    <p>You must have access to <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> as an administrator and as a technology manager of an organization that has at least the technology provider role.</p>
                </li>
                <li audience="ror">You must have access to a fully functional ROR installation.<p>In ROR, a tenant must have been set up for your organization. You must have the necessary credentials to access this tenant and to create and configure virtual platforms (L-Platforms) for it. This means that you must have the role of a tenant administrator.</p></li>
                <li audience="aws">You must have an AWS account.</li>
                <li audience="os"
                        >You must have access to a fully functional OpenStack installation. <p>The OpenStack integration requires the following API versions:</p><p>Orchestration API (Heat) v1</p><p>Compute API (Nova) v2.1</p><p>Identity API (Keystone) v3</p><p>For secure connections, the OpenStack integration supports the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol, v1.2.</p></li>
                <li audience="tps5"
                        >You must have access to the TPS5 platform. <p>You have to register as a service subscriber in the Service Portal of your TPS5 region. As a registered service subscriber, you receive an Administrator ID and an initial password. With these credentials, you can log in to the Service Portal to download the client certificate that is needed for accessing the TPS5 platform. For details on the certificates, refer to the TPS5 documentation.</p></li>
                <li audience="vmware"
                        >You must have access to a fully functional vSphere installation via the URL of its vCenter.<p>The vSphere integration requires the following vSphere API version: v5.5.</p>
                </li>
                <li audience="vmware">In vSphere, a technical user must exist for accessing the vSphere API. This user must have the following permissions in vSphere: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Virtual machine/*: A set of privileges that allow the user to interact with a VM's console, insert media, and perform power operations. </li>
                            <li>Resource: Assign VM to resource pool</li>
                            <li>Datastore: Allocate space</li>
                            <li>Network: Assign network</li>
                        </ul>
                    </p><p>For details on vCenter, users, and their privileges in vSphere, refer to the vSphere documentation.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
