<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Updating Configuration Settings</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                                    <p>The <ph audience="app">APP</ph><ph audience="ror">ROR integration</ph><ph
                    audience="aws">AWS integration</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack integration</ph><ph audience="tps5"
                    >TPS5 integration</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                >vSphere integration</ph> software and setup utilities require a number of settings. In the installation, you adapted the settings, in particular server names, ports, paths, and user IDs, to your environment.</p>
                                    <p>The configuration settings are provided in the following subdirectories and files of <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir></codeph>:</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p><codeph><b>databases/app_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>db.properties</codeph>: Settings for the <ph audience="vmware"
                                    >APP </ph>database setup and access.</li>
                                <li><codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for APP. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database, where you can change them later, if required. An update installation overwrites the settings. If you don't want existing settings to be overwritten, delete them from the properties file. In case that mandatory settings are missing in the properties file and not yet stored in the database, an exception will occur. </p></li>
                                <li audience="ror"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="ror"
                                            >ROR</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface.</p></li>
                                <li audience="app"
                                    ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for a service controller integrated with APP, if any.</li>
                                <li audience="aws"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="aws"
                                            >AWS</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface.</p></li>
                                <li audience="os"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="os"
                                            >OpenStack</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface. </p></li>
                                <li audience="tps5"
                                    ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="os"
                                        >TPS5</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface. </p></li>
                                <li audience="vmware"
                                            ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the VMware service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database, where you can change them later, if required, by means of an update installation. Refer to <xref
                                            href="c_Update.xml"/> for details. </p></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li audience="vmware">
                        <p><codeph><b>databases/controller_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>db.properties</codeph>: Settings for the VMware service controller database setup and access.</li>
                                <li><codeph>csv/*</codeph>: <codeph>.csv</codeph> files for specifying the vSphere configuration.<p>The initial import stores the vSphere configuration in the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database. If you want to update the installation, you need to delete the configuration settings and import the <codeph>.csv</codeph> files again. Refer to <xref
                                            href="c_Update.xml"/> for details.  </p></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p><codeph><b>domains/app_domain</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>The configuration settings for setting up the application server domain to which APP is deployed are provided in the following file:</p>
                        <p><codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph></p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
                                    <p>For details on the configuration settings, refer to <ph><xref
                        href="../../Shared/Installation/r_ConfigSettings.xml"/></ph>.</p>
                                    <p>If you need to change the settings, proceed as described in the following sections.</p>
                                    <p><b>To update the configuration settings for database access:</b>
                                <ol compact="no">
                                        <li>Log in to the administration console of the application server. </li>
                                        <li>Adapt the settings as required. </li>
                                </ol></p>
                                    <p><b>To update the configuration settings for the application server:</b>
                                <ol compact="no">
                                        <li>Open the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file located in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain</codeph> with an editor.</li>
                                        <li>Check the settings in the file and adapt them to your environment if required.</li>
                                        <li>Save the file to its original location in <ph><codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;/domains/app_domain</codeph></ph>. </li>
                                        <li>Update the settings and resources in the application server by executing the <codeph>build-glassfish.xml</codeph> file in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;/install</codeph> as follows:<p>
                            <codeblock>&lt;ANT_HOME&gt;/bin/ant -f build-glassfish.xml 
   SETUP.configureDomains</codeblock>
                        </p></li>
                                </ol></p>
                                    <p><b>To update the configuration settings for APP:</b>
                                <ol compact="no">
                                        <li>Edit the content of the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file as required. </li>
                                        <li>Execute the <codeph>build-db.xml</codeph> file in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;/install</codeph> as follows:<p>
                            <codeblock>&lt;ANT_HOME&gt;/bin/ant -f build-db.xml
   UPDATE.configSettings</codeblock>
                        </p></li>
                                </ol></p>
            <p audience="app"
                ><b>To update the configuration settings for a service controller integrated with APP:</b></p>
            <p audience="ror"><b>To update the configuration settings for the ROR service controller:</b></p>
            <p audience="tps5"><b>To update the configuration settings for the TPS5 service controller:</b></p>
            <p audience="aws"><b>To update the configuration settings for the AWS service controller:</b></p>
            <p audience="os"><b>To update the configuration settings for the OpenStack service controller:</b></p>
            <p audience="vmware"><b>To update the settings of the vSphere configuration:</b></p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                                        <li>In a Web browser, access the URL of the <ph audience="ror">ROR </ph><ph
                            audience="aws">AWS </ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack </ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5 </ph><ph
                            audience="vmware">VMware </ph>service controller, for example: <ph audience="app"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-aws</codeph></ph><ph audience="ror"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-ror</codeph></ph><ph audience="aws"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-aws</codeph></ph><ph audience="os"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-openstack</codeph></ph><ph audience="tps5"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-tps5</codeph></ph><ph audience="vmware"
                                ><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-vmware/vcenter.jsf</codeph></ph>.</li>
                    <li>Log in with the ID and password of the user specified in the configuration settings for the <ph
                            audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
                            audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                            >VMware</ph> service controller (<codeph>BSS_USER_ID</codeph> and <codeph>BSS_USER_PWD</codeph>) or as another technology manager registered for the same organization.</li>
                    <li audience="app">Enter the required settings.</li>
                    <li audience="ror">Enter the required settings.</li>
                    <li audience="tps5">Enter the required settings.</li>
                    <li audience="aws">Enter the required settings.</li>
                    <li audience="os"
                            >Enter the required settings. Be aware that some of them can also be set in the technical service definition. In this case, the technical service parameter overrides the setting you specify here. Refer to <xref
                            href="../../OSIntegrationGuide/Appendix/r_ConfigSettingsController.xml"/> and <xref
                            href="../../OSIntegrationGuide/Appendix/r_ServiceParameters.xml"
                                /> for details on the settings and parameters.<p>Apart from updating the configuration settings, you can import templates for the provisioning of VMs into the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. Refer to <xref
                                href="../../OSIntegrationGuide/Administrating/c_ImportTemplates.xml"
                        /> for details.</p></li>
                    <li audience="vmware">You can change the following settings for accessing the vCenter: <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li><b>Connection URL</b>: The URL for accessing the vSphere API.</li>
                                <li><b>User ID</b>: The ID of the technical user in vSphere for accessing the vSphere API.</li>
                                <li><b>Password</b>: The password of the technical user in vSphere for accessing the vSphere API. </li>
                            </ul>
                        </p></li>
                    <li>Save the settings.</li>
                                </ol>
            </p>
                                    <p>If you want to change the technology provider organization responsible for the <ph
                    audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph
                    audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                >VMware</ph> service controller, you can use the Web interface of APP: </p>
                                    <ol compact="no">
                                <li>In a Web browser, access the base URL of APP, for example: <codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app</codeph>
                </li>
                                <li>Log in with the ID and password of the user specified for <codeph>BSS_USER_KEY</codeph> in the configuration settings for APP or as another administrator of the same organization. </li>
                                <li>Specify the technology provider organization for the <ph audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph
                        audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph
                        audience="vmware">VMware</ph> service controller, <ph audience="ror"
                        ><codeph>ess.ror</codeph></ph><ph audience="aws"><codeph>ess.aws</codeph></ph><ph audience="os"
                            ><codeph>ess.openstack</codeph></ph><ph audience="tps5"><codeph>ess.tps5</codeph></ph><ph
                        audience="vmware"><codeph>ess.vmware</codeph></ph>.</li>
                                <li>Save the settings.</li>
                <li audience="app"
                            >Make sure that the configuration settings for the service controller are updated. <p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p></li>
                <li audience="aws"
                            >Make sure that the configuration settings for the AWS service controller are updated. <p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p></li>
                <li audience="tps5"
                            >Make sure that the configuration settings for the TPS5 service controller are updated. <p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p></li>
                <li audience="os"
                            >Make sure that the configuration settings for the OpenStack service controller are updated. <p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p></li>
                <li audience="ror">Make sure that the configuration settings for the <ph audience="ror"
                            >ROR</ph> service controller are updated. <p>Any technology manager registered for the technology provider organization you specified can log in to the graphical user interface for updating the controller configuration settings (see above). At least the ID and password of the user to be used for accessing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> must be changed in the controller configuration settings.</p></li>
                        </ol>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
