<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="Configuring"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring <ph audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph
            audience="app">APP</ph></title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>The <ph audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph
                    audience="app"
                    >APP</ph> software and setup utilities require a number of settings. These settings are provided in the following subdirectories and files of <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;</codeph>:</p>
            <p id="Cfg2">
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>
                        <p audience="BSS"><codeph><b>databases/bes_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p audience="app"><codeph><b>databases/app_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>db.properties</codeph>: Settings for the database setup and access. <ph
                                        audience="app">For details, refer to <xref
                                            href="../../Shared/reference/r_ConfigSettings_db.xml"/>.</ph></li>
                                <li><codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="BSS"
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph
                                        audience="app">APP</ph> services. <ph audience="app">For details, refer to <xref
                                            href="../../APPInt/APP/r_ConfigSettings.xml"/>.</ph>
                                    <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <ph audience="BSS"
                                                ><codeph>bss</codeph></ph><ph audience="app"
                                            ><codeph>bssapp</codeph></ph> database, where you can change them later, if required. An update installation only adds new settings to the database but does not overwrite existing ones. In the case that mandatory settings are missing, an error is thrown, and you need to add these settings manually before executing the installation scripts again. </p></li>
                                <li audience="app"
                                            ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: In this file, you can specify settings for a service controller which you want to register when installing APP. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface. </p>For details, refer to <xref
                                        href="../../APPInt/APP/t_RegisterAPP.xml"/>. </li>
                                <li audience="BSS"
                                        ><codeph>sso.properties</codeph>: Configuration setting for creating the first platform operator in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> (<codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph>). Only required when installing <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> in SAML_SP authentication mode.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li audience="BSS">
                        <p><codeph><b>domains/bes_domain</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>The configuration settings for setting up the application server domain to which the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> applications will be deployed are provided in the following files: </p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the application server.</li>
                                <li><codeph>glassfishJMSBroker.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the Java Message Service (JMS) in the application server.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li audience="BSS">
                        <p><codeph><b>domains/indexer_domain</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>The configuration settings for setting up the application server domain to which the search indexer application will be deployed are provided in the following files: </p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the application server.</li>
                                <li><codeph>glassfishJMSBroker.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the Java Message Service (JMS) in the application server.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li audience="app">
                        <p><codeph><b>domains/app_domain</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>The configuration settings for setting up the application server domain to which APP will be deployed are provided in the following file:</p>
                        <p><codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph></p>
                        <p><ph audience="app">For details, refer to <xref
                                    href="../../Shared/reference/r_ConfigSettings_glassfish_BESDomain.xml"/>.</ph></p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>Additional configuration files contained in other subdirectories are used internally and must not be changed.</p>
            <p><ph>You need to adapt the settings in the files above to your environment. In particular, server names, ports, paths, user IDs, and passwords require adaptation.</ph>
                <ph id="Cfg7_BSS" audience="BSS"
                    >If installed in SAML_SP authentication mode, additional settings are required.</ph></p> 
                <p>Proceed as follows to view and adjust the configuration settings:</p>
            </context>
        
        <steps>
            
            <step>
                <cmd>Open each of the configuration files listed above with an editor. </cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Check the settings in each file and adapt them to your environment.</cmd>
                <info audience="BSS">For details on the individual settings, refer to <xref
                        href="../../Shared/reference/r_ConfigSettings.xml"/>.</info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Save the files to their original location in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;/&lt;subdirectory></codeph>. For future reference, it is a good idea to create a backup of the files.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
        
        
        <result>
            <p><b>Observe the following configuration issues</b>:</p>
            
                <ul compact="no">
                <li>The specified ports are suggestions and work with the default settings used in the files. </li>
                <li audience="BSS"
                        > If you install everything on the local system, use either the server name or <codeph>localhost</codeph> in all configuration files for all URLs that need to be resolved by <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />. <p><b>Do not mix the specification of server names and <codeph>localhost</codeph>.</b></p><p>The <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> setting, and, if specified, the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> setting in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file must be resolved by clients. They always require that the server name be specified. </p><p>Specify the settings as follows:</p><p>
                        <codeblock>BASE_URL_HTTPS=https://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-portal
BASE_URL_HTTP=http://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-portal</codeblock>
                    </p></li>
                <li audience="app"
                        >If you install everything on the local system, use either the server name or <codeph>localhost</codeph> in all configuration files for all URLs that need to be resolved by APP. <p><b>Do not mix the specification of server names and <codeph>localhost</codeph>.</b></p><p>The <codeph>APP_BASE_URL</codeph> setting in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file must be resolved by clients. They always require that the server name be specified. </p><p>Specify the <codeph>APP_BASE_URL</codeph> setting as follows:</p><p>
                        <codeblock>APP_BASE_URL=http://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-app</codeblock>
                    </p><p>If you have changed the <codeph>glassfish.domain.portbase</codeph> setting in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file, you must change the port here accordingly.</p>
                </li>
                <li audience="BSS"
                        >On Windows, in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> files, double-escape the colon in the drive specification of the path to the search indexer application (<codeph>hibernate.search.shared.sourceBase</codeph>). Otherwise the search indexer application may not work properly. The directory you specify for the search indexer application is created automatically.<p>Example: </p><p>
                        <codeblock>hibernate.search.shared.sourceBase=
C\\:/glassfish/masterSourceBase</codeblock>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li audience="BSS">
                    <p>The following settings in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file are mandatory when installing <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> in <b>SAML_SP</b> authentication mode:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_DEFAULT_TENANT_ID</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD</codeph></li>
                    </ul>
                    <p>The following settings are also mandatory and require the respective information to be provided by the IdP operator. Refer to <xref
                            href="../../InstallationGuide/Preparation/c_AuthenticationMode.xml"/> for details.</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_SAML_ASSERTION_ISSUER_ID</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_STS_ENCKEY_LEN</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_AUTHENTICATION_REQUEST_HTTP_METHOD</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_URL</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_LOGOUT_URL</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_STS_URL</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>SSO_STS_METADATA_URL</codeph></li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>

<!-- for APP and ROR only -->
    
            <p audience="app"><b>Configuration for SAML_SP authentication mode</b>:</p>
            <p audience="app">If the <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> installation you want to work with is configured for SAML_SP authentication mode, Web service calls to it are secured and authenticated by a Security Token Service (STS). This is a Web service that issues security tokens as defined in the WS-Security/WS-Trust specification. The STS is usually provided by the Identity Provider (IdP) system in use (for example, Active Directory Federation Service, Cloudminder, or OpenAM).</p>
            <p audience="app"
                >For using an STS for APP calls, you must perform the following steps before installing APP: </p>
            <p audience="app">
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>From the IdP or <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator, obtain a metadata exchange file in WSDL format generated with and for the IdP system in use. The metadata include namespace information required for connecting to the STS. </li>
                    <li>Save the metadata exchange file to the following file, overwriting the existing empty file:<p><codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/wsit/STSService.xml</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Open the <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file and retrieve the value of <codeph>targetNamespace</codeph>, for example:<p>
                            <codeph>http://schemas.microsoft.com/ws/2008/06/identity/securitytokenservice</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Open the following file:<p><codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/wsit/wsit-client.xml</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Replace the placeholder in the <codeph>namespace</codeph> tag of the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file with the <codeph>targetNamespace</codeph> value copied from the <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file. </li>
                    <li>Close and save the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file to its original location. <p>During the installation process, an <codeph>OSCM-wsit.jar</codeph> file is created containing your adapted <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file as well as the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file; the <codeph>.jar</codeph> file is then copied to <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/lib</codeph>. </p></li>
                    <li>Make sure to enter correct values for the SAML_SP authentication mode in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/databases/app_db</codeph>: <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li><codeph>BSS_AUTH_MODE=SAML_SP</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>BSS_WEBSERVICE_URL_STS_PORT=https://<i>&lt;server></i>:<i>&lt;port></i>/{SERVICE}/STS?wsdl</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>APP_KEYSTORE_PASSWORD=changeit</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>APP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD=changeit</codeph></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p></li>
                </ol>
            </p>


        </result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
