<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="Configuring"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring the <ph audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph
            audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="vmware">vSphere</ph> Integration</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context><p id="Cfg1">The <ph audience="os">OpenStack integration</ph><ph audience="ror">ROR integration</ph><ph
                    audience="aws">AWS integration</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5 integration</ph><ph audience="vmware"
                    >vSphere integration</ph> software and setup utilities require a number of settings. These settings are provided in the following subdirectories and files of <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;</codeph>:</p><p
                id="Cfg2">
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <p><codeph><b>databases/app_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>db.properties</codeph>: Settings for the<ph audience="vmware"
                                    > APP</ph> database setup and access.</li>
                                <li><codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for APP. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database, where you can change them later, if required. An update installation only adds new settings to the database, but does not overwrite existing ones.</p></li>
                                <li audience="ror"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="ror"
                                            >ROR</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface.</p><p>The <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> file specifies the organization ID and user credentials for accessing <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> as well as the required credentials for accessing the tenant for your organization in ROR. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the ROR integration software.</p></li>
                                <li audience="app"
                                    ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for a service controller integrated with APP, if any.</li>
                                <li audience="aws"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="aws"
                                            >AWS</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface.</p><p>The <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> file specifies the organization ID and user credentials for accessing <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> as well as the AWS access keys. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the AWS integration software.</p></li>
                                <li audience="os"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="os"
                                            >OpenStack</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface. </p><p>The <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> file specifies the organization ID and user credentials for accessing <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> as well as the required credentials for accessing the tenant for your organization in OpenStack. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the OpenStack integration software.</p></li>
                                <li audience="tps5"
                                        ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the <ph
                                        audience="tps5"
                                            >TPS5</ph> service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later using a graphical user interface. </p><p>The <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> file specifies the organization ID and user credentials for accessing <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> as well as the account settings for accessing the TPS5 platform. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the TPS5 integration software.</p></li>
                                <li audience="vmware"
                                            ><codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph>: Configuration settings for the VMware service controller. <p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. You can change them later, if required.</p><p>The <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> file specifies the organization ID and user credentials for accessing <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the vSphere integration software.</p></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li audience="vmware">
                        <p><codeph><b>databases/controller_db</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>
                            <ul compact="no">
                                <li><codeph>db.properties</codeph>: Settings for the VMware service controller database setup and access.</li>
                                <li><codeph>csv/*</codeph>: <codeph>.csv</codeph> files for specifying the vSphere configuration.<p>The initial installation stores these settings in the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database. Usually, you do not need to change them once they have been imported into the database. </p><p>The <codeph>vcenter.csv</codeph> file specifies the URL and user credentials for accessing the vSphere server. For security reasons, it is recommended that you delete the file as soon as you have successfully installed and configured the vSphere integration software.</p></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <p><codeph><b>domains/app_domain</b></codeph></p>
                        <p>The configuration settings for setting up the application server domain to which APP is deployed are provided in the following file:</p>
                        <p><codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph></p>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p><p>Additional configuration files contained in other subdirectories are used internally and must not be changed.</p><p>For details on the configuration settings, refer to <ph><xref
                        href="../../Shared/Installation/r_ConfigSettings.xml"
                    /></ph>. For details on updating the configuration settings, refer to <xref
                    href="c_UpdateConfiguration.xml"
                />.</p><p>You need to adapt the settings in the files above to your environment. In particular, server names, ports, paths, user IDs, and passwords require adaptation.</p>Proceed as follows to view and adjust the configuration settings:<p
                id="Steps">
                <ol>
                    <li>Open each of the configuration files listed above with an editor.</li>
                    <li>Check the settings in each file and adapt them to your environment.</li>
                    <li>Save the files to their original location in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir&gt;/&lt;subdirectory></codeph>. For future reference, it is a good idea to create a backup of the files.</li>
                </ol>
            </p></context>
        
        
        <result>
            <p id="Result1"><b>Observe the following configuration issues</b>:</p>
            
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>The specified ports are suggestions and work with the default settings used in the files. </li>
                    
                    <li>If you install everything on the local system, use either the server name or <codeph>localhost</codeph> in all configuration files for all URLs that need to be resolved by APP.  <p>The <codeph>APP_BASE_URL</codeph> setting in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file for the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain must be resolved by clients. They always require that the server name be specified. </p>
                    <p>Specify the <codeph>APP_BASE_URL</codeph> setting as follows:</p>
                    <p>
                        <codeblock>APP_BASE_URL=http://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-app</codeblock>
                    </p>
                    <p>If you have changed the <codeph>glassfish.domain.portbase</codeph> setting in the <codeph>glassfish.properties</codeph> file, you must change the port here accordingly.</p>
                </li>
                </ul>
    
            <p><b>Configuration for SAML_SP authentication mode</b>:</p>
            <p>If the <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> installation you want to work with is configured for SAML_SP authentication mode, Web service calls to it are secured and authenticated by a Security Token Service (STS). This is a Web service that issues security tokens as defined in the WS-Security/WS-Trust specification. The STS is usually provided by the Identity Provider (IdP) system in use (for example Active Directory Federation Service, Cloudminder, or OpenAM).</p>
            <p>To use an STS for Web service calls, you must perform the following steps before installing the <ph
                    audience="os">OpenStack</ph><ph audience="ror">ROR</ph><ph audience="tps5">TPS5</ph><ph
                    audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="vmware">vSphere</ph> integration software: </p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>From the IdP or <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> operator, obtain a metadata exchange file in WSDL format generated with and for the IdP system in use. The metadata includes namespace information required for connecting to the STS. </li>
                    <li>Save the metadata exchange file to the following file, overwriting the existing empty file:<p><codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/wsit/STSService.xml</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Open the <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file and retrieve the value of <codeph>targetNamespace</codeph>, for example:<p>
                            <codeph>http://schemas.microsoft.com/ws/2008/06/identity/securitytokenservice</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Open the following file:<p><codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/wsit/wsit-client.xml</codeph></p></li>
                    <li>Replace the placeholder in the <codeph>namespace</codeph> tag of the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file with the <codeph>targetNamespace</codeph> value copied from the <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file. </li>
                    <li>Close and save the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file to its original location.<p>During the installation process, an <codeph>OSCM-wsit.jar</codeph> file is created containing the <codeph>STSService.xml</codeph> file as well as the <codeph>wsit-client.xml</codeph> file; the <codeph>.jar</codeph> file is then copied to <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/app_domain/lib</codeph>.</p></li>
                    <li>Make sure that you enter correct values for the SAML_SP authentication mode in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/databases/app_db</codeph>: <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li><codeph>BSS_AUTH_MODE=SAML_SP</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>BSS_STS_WEBSERVICE_URL=https://&lt;server>:&lt;port>/{SERVICE}/STS</codeph>
                                </li>
                                <li><codeph>BSS_STS_WEBSERVICE_WSDL_URL= https://&lt;server>:&lt;port>/oscm/v1.9/{SERVICE}/STS?wsdl</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>APP_KEYSTORE_PASSWORD=changeit</codeph></li>
                                <li><codeph>APP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD=changeit</codeph></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p></li>
                    <li audience="vmware"
                            >In the <codeph>configsettings_controller.properties</codeph> located in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/databases/app_db</codeph>, set the <codeph>BSS_USER_SSO</codeph> property to <codeph>true</codeph>. </li>
                </ol>
            </p>


        </result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
