<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd"

[
<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC "-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc" "entities.dtd">
]>

<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95">
    <title>Provisioning Applications as Services in <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>After the required adaptations of your application are finished, you register your application as a technical service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <p>There are two possibilities for achieving this task: </p>
            <p><ol>
                    <li>If the application does not provide any parameters, options, roles, events, or operations, register the application as a technical service using the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> user interface. Here, you can define the basic features for the technical service you want to provide. </li>
                    <li>If an application is more complex and provides parameters, options, etc., create an XML file containing the technical service definition and import this file into <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </li>
                </ol>The figure below provides an overview of the two possibilities: </p>
            <fig>
                <image placement="break" align="center" href="../_images/RegisterService.png" width="435" height="326"/>
            </fig>
            <p>Possibility 1 consists of registering the application and then updating the service definition. Possibility 2 consists of creating an XML file and importing this file into <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <p>You can also combine both ways. For example:</p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Register the service using the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> user interface.</li>
                    <li>Export the service definition and save it to an XML file.</li>
                    <li>Edit the XML file: Specify descriptions, license information, parameters, options, events, roles, operations, etc. </li>
                    <li>Import the XML file into <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> again.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>After registering your application as a technical service, you need to appoint suppliers for it in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> so that marketable services can be defined and published. </p>
            <p>The following sections describe the individual steps in detail. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
