<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd"

[
<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC "-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc" "entities.dtd">
]>

<task xml:lang="en-us" id="task_3ED29BA87B2F438A84EF9B425DEFFB17">
    <title>Appointing Suppliers for a Technical Service</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>After registering a technical service either by importing the technical service definition XML file or by providing the required information at the user interface, you appoint one or more suppliers for it. Suppliers are the companies, departments, or people who offer your technical service as marketable services. Your organization may act as a supplier of its own, if it is granted the corresponding role by the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator.</p>
            <p>To appoint suppliers:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> &gt;
                    <uicontrol>Manage suppliers</uicontrol> and select the technical service for which you want to appoint a supplier. </cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Specify the organization ID of the supplier to be appointed and click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>You can only specify suppliers that have previously been registered by the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> operator. You can obtain the organization IDs from your suppliers.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>The suppliers can now start defining marketable services for the technical services they are appointed for. These can be different editions of the technical services with individual price models, configurations, upgrade options, and restrictions.</p>
            <p>You can also delete suppliers from the list of appointed suppliers. If customer subscriptions exist for the marketable services of a supplier, a corresponding message is displayed. It lists the instance IDs of the underlying application instances. If you want to view the instance IDs for your technical services, you can create an instance report.</p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
