<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN" "task.dtd"

[
<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC "-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc" "entities.dtd">
]>

<task xml:lang="en-us" id="task_AFABF05A11F84613BECB358A0D6F3138">
    <title>Updating and Maintaining the Service Definition</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>You can update the descriptive texts and the license agreement text for a technical service either by editing the XML service definition file, or - in a more convenient way - at the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user interface. The changes are effective for all newly defined marketable services based on this technical service.</p>
            <p>To update the texts for the technical service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal.</cmd>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select <uicontrol>Technical Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                        <uicontrol>Update service definition</uicontrol>, and edit the texts as desired. </cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>You can also update an existing technical service by editing the technical service definition and importing it again:</p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal.</li>
                    <li>Select <uicontrol>Technical Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                            <uicontrol>Import service definition</uicontrol>.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>Observe the following:</p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>If there is no marketable service and no subscription based on the technical service, you can change all properties of the technical service. </li>
                    <li>If there is a marketable service or a subscription based on the technical service, you cannot: <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li>Change parameters and their options</li>
                                <li>Change event types</li>
                                <li>Remove parameters, options, or event types</li>
                            </ul>
                        </p></li>
                    <li>Roles cannot be removed if prices are defined for them or users having one of the roles are assigned to a related subscription.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>You can also delete an existing technical service. If marketable services exist for the technical service, and if there are active subscriptions, it cannot be deleted. The technical service definition XML file is not deleted physically, and you can import it again on demand.</p>
            <p>To delete a technical service:</p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal.</li>
                    <li>Select <uicontrol>Technical Service</uicontrol> &gt;
                            <uicontrol>Delete service definition</uicontrol>. </li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
</task>
