<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Billing and Payment</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p id="As_users_work_with_the_servic_concept_conbody_section_p_1"
                                        >As users work with the services, <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> automatically calculates the charges based on the related price models. It aggregates all the events, users, and configuration data associated with a subscription and rates them according to the associated price model. </p>
                        <p id="calculation1"
                                >At daily intervals, the database content is checked for organizations which have produced billing-relevant data. The data is collected and stored in the database. At monthly intervals (billing periods), the billing data is calculated. These checks and calculations are called "billing runs for customer billing data". The costs for all customer subscriptions that were produced in the course of a billing period are calculated by the billing run executed on the start day of the next billing period plus the offset defined by the operator. </p>
                        <p id="calculation_samples">Examples: <ul>
                                        <li>You define that the billing period is to start on the 8th of a month, and the offset is set to 5 days and 4 hours. In this case, the billing run is executed on the 13th of each month at 04:00:00.000. The start day of the billing period, and thus the billing period itself, may be different for each supplier and reseller.</li>
                                        <li>Assume, the offset is set to 0 and the billing period starts on the 8th of a month. On January 5th, a customer subscribes to a service. The price model of this service defines per time unit calculation with charges based on MONTH as well as a one-time fee. On January 20th, the customer terminates this subscription. <p>In this case: <ul>
                                                            <li>The billing run executed on January 8th calculates the one-time fee only. </li>
                                                            <li>The billing run executed on February 8th calculates the time unit that ended on January 31st, i.e. the month of January is fully charged. </li>
                                                        </ul></p></li>
                                </ul></p>
                        <p id="The_customer_billing_data_can_concept_conbody_section_p_3"
                                >The customer billing data can be used for creating invoices. You are responsible for charging your customers and for collecting the payments. </p>
                        <p>If you grant a reseller the permission to sell your services, it is the reseller's responsibility to manage billing and payment for his customers. If you grant a broker the permission to offer your services, it is your responsibility to manage billing and payment for your broker's customers.</p>
                        <p>As a supplier, you are usually entitled to most of the revenue from your customers' service usage. <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> offers various features that support you in retrieving information on the revenue shares you can claim from or need to pay to others, for example, brokers, resellers, marketplace owners, or the platform operator. The operator is responsible for defining the revenue shares. They may differ for individual marketplaces, brokers or resellers, or even specific services. You are not authorized to change any revenue shares. </p>
                        <p><ph id="costcalc4"
                                        >The revenue shares are calculated every month based on the results of the daily checks for customer billing data. This calculation is called "billing run for revenue share data". The billing period for this billing run cannot be changed; it is always executed for the previous calendar month on the first day of a month plus the offset defined by the operator.</ph></p>
                        <p>The following sections describe which preparatory steps you have to take for the billing and payment services in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, how <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> supports you in creating invoices and collecting payments, and which tasks are involved in handling revenue shares.</p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
