<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="PriceModelTopic" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Defining the price model for a service</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Define for service</uicontrol> page, you define or update the price model for a selected service. </p>
      <p id="concept_price_model"
        >The price model specifies whether and how much customers subscribing to the service are charged for using a subscription.<ph audience="doc"> Click <xref
          href="reference/r_PriceModelDetails.xml">here</xref> for basic information on price models.</ph></p>
      <p id="concept_service"
            >For each marketable service you want to offer, a price model must have been defined before you can activate the service and thus provide it to customers for subscription. You can define exactly one price model for a service. You can, however, also define customer-specific price models or even subscription-specific ones. For service and customer-specific price models, you can specify the license agreement text that is presented to and needs to be accepted by your customers. The underlying technical service comes with licensing information that you can change when defining the price model. <note>If you edit an existing price model on the <uicontrol>Define for service</uicontrol> page, your changes overwrite the previously defined price model. </note></p>
      <p><b>To define the price model for a service</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step id="step_select_service">
        <cmd id="From_the_task_taskbody_steps_step_1"
          >From the <uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol> list, select the service for which you want to define the price model.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step id="step_free_service">
        <cmd id="Added_description_of_new_o_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
          >Select the cost calculation option for the price model: </cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no" id="Select_task_taskbody_steps_step_2">
            <li>Select <uicontrol>Free of charge</uicontrol>, if the service is to be free of charge. </li>
            <li>Select <uicontrol>Pro rata calculation</uicontrol>, if the costs are to be calculated based on the exact usage of the service in milliseconds.</li>
            <li>Select <uicontrol>Per time unit calculation</uicontrol>, if the costs are to be calculated for complete time units, for example, whole days or weeks. The time unit is defined under <uicontrol>Charges based on</uicontrol>.</li>
          </ul>
          <p>If your service is free of charge, proceed with Step 8, else with Step 3. </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_desc">
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> field, enter a detailed description of the price model. It may, for example, provide details of each element the price model consists of.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The description is displayed to customers on a marketplace when they request details of the service from the service catalog.</p>
          <p>You can specify the description in additional languages later by localizing the price model.</p>
          <note><ph
              conref="../help/tasks/service_add.xml#task634/Make_sure_to_use_only_the_con_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/>
          </note>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_trialperiod">
        <cmd>Define a free trial period if you want to offer the service for free for a limited period of time. <ph
            id="After_this_period_the_servic_task_taskbody_steps_step_4"
            >After this period, the service automatically turns into a chargeable service.</ph></cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Select the <uicontrol>Define a free trial period</uicontrol> check box, and enter the length of the free trial period in days. Specify the number of days as an integer.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_charging">
        <cmd>Specify the <b>charging conditions</b>. They include the following information: </cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li id="Currency_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
              ><b>Currency</b> in which a customer is charged for using the service. The supported currencies are defined by the operator. The currency cannot be changed when defining a subscription price model.</li>
            <li id="Charges_based_on_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
              ><b>Charges based on</b>: The time unit for recurring charges. The charges can be on a monthly, weekly, daily, or hourly basis. The option selected here also defines the time unit for per time unit calculation. The time unit cannot be changed when defining a subscription price model.</li>
            <li id="One-time_fee_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
              ><b>One-time fee</b> to be paid when subscribing to the service. This fee is added to the usage charges for the first billing period. </li>
            <li id="Recurring_charge_per_subscrip_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
                ><b>Recurring charge per subscription</b>: The charge to be paid for a subscription on a recurring basis as specified in the <uicontrol>Charges based on</uicontrol> field. </li>
            <li><ph id="Recurring_charge_per_user_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
                  ><b>Recurring charge for users</b>: The charge to be paid per time unit users are assigned to a subscription. The time unit is defined in the <uicontrol>Charges based on</uicontrol> field. For this type of charge, you can specify stepped prices, for example, to grant discounts depending on the amount of time users work with a subscription</ph>: <ul
                compact="no">
                <li>Click the field for entering a price. A plus sign appears to its right. </li>
                <li>Click the plus sign and enter a price per time unit as well as a step limit. The step limit defines the sum of the time units of all user assignments in a billing period up to which the specified price is valid. </li>
                <li>Proceed with the definition of prices and step limits. Use the plus sign to add a price step, the minus sign to remove a step.</li>
                <li>The last <uicontrol>Price per time unit</uicontrol> entry field defines the price to be applied for all time units exceeding the number specified in the last <uicontrol>Step limit</uicontrol> field. </li>
                  </ul><ph audience="doc">Click <xref href="../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml"
              >here</xref> for detailed information.</ph> </li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_events">
        <cmd>Specify the prices for the billable <b>events</b> defined for the service. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p><ph
              conref="reference/r_PriceModelDetails_events.xml#reference832/These_include_for_example_l_reference_refbody_section_1"
            />
          </p>
          <p>The available events are listed in the table. In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> column, you can view their short descriptions.</p>
          <p>For this type of charge, you can specify stepped prices, for example, to grant discounts depending on the number of events that occurred while using the service: <ul
              compact="no">
              <li>Click the field for entering a price. A plus sign appears to its right. </li>
              <li>Click the plus sign and enter a price per event as well as a step limit. The step limit defines the number of events up to which the price per event is valid.</li>
              <li>Proceed with the definition of prices per event and step limits. Use the plus sign to add a price step, the minus sign to remove a step.</li>
              <li>The last <uicontrol>Price</uicontrol> entry field defines the price to be applied for all events of the selected type exceeding the number specified in the last <uicontrol>Step limit</uicontrol> field. </li>
          </ul><ph audience="doc">Click <xref href="../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml"
            >here</xref> for detailed information.</ph> </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_params">
        <cmd>Specify the prices for <b>parameters and options</b>. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p><ph
              conref="reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/It_depends_on_the_implementat_reference_refbody_section_1"
            />
          </p>
          <p>The available parameters and options are listed in the table. In the <uicontrol>Description</uicontrol> column, you can view their short descriptions.</p>
          <p>You can define a price for every parameter and option, <ph
              conref="reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/and_specify_whether_this_pric_reference_refbody_section_1"
            /></p>
          <p>For numeric parameters (parameters with values of type Integer or Long), you can define stepped prices per subscription, for example, to grant volume discounts: <ul
              compact="no">
              <li>Click the field for entering a price. A plus sign appears to its right. </li>
              <li>Click the plus sign and enter a price as well as a step limit. The step limit defines the value up to which the price is valid.</li>
              <li>Proceed with the definition of prices and step limits. Use the plus sign to add a price step, a minus sign to remove a step. </li>
              <li>The last <uicontrol>Price</uicontrol> entry field defines the price to be applied for all parameter values exceeding the number specified in the last <uicontrol>Step limit</uicontrol> field. </li>
          </ul><ph audience="doc">Click <xref href="../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml"
            >here</xref> for detailed information.</ph></p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_license">
        <cmd>Edit the <b>license agreement</b> as desired. The license agreement must be read and accepted by customers when they subscribe to the service.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>By default, the license agreement of the technology provider is used. It is up to you whether you use this license agreement or specify a different one. </p>
          <p>You can specify the license agreement in additional languages later by localizing the price model.</p>
          <p>Resellers who sell the service can provide their own license agreement. It is up to them whether they use the license agreement as you enter it or specify a different one. If you change the license agreement, the reseller's license agreement is not updated.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_license2">
        <cmd>Edit the<b> license agreement</b> as desired. The license agreement must be read and accepted by the customer when he subscribes to the service.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>By default, the license agreement of the technology provider is used. It is up to you whether you use this license agreement or specify a different one. </p>
          <p>You can specify the license agreement in additional languages later by localizing the price model.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="step_save">
        <cmd>To save the price model, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step id="step_localize">
        <cmd>To provide the price model's description and license agreement in another language, click <uicontrol>Localize</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step id="step_roles">
        <cmd>To specify prices for roles that are defined for the underlying application, click <uicontrol>Define for Service Roles</uicontrol>. The price you define for a service role is added to the base price per user in the cost calculation for a billing period. </cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>After activating the corresponding service, the changes are made available to customers.</result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
