<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept
                    id="Configuring_and_Enabling_Acce_278">
  <title>Configuring and Enabling Access to APP and Service Controllers</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
            <p>When integrating applications with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, the instance provisioning can be done in two provisioning modes: synchronous or asynchronous mode. </p>
            <p>Asynchronous provisioning is required if provisioning operations take a long time because long-running processes or manual steps are involved. This is the case, for example, when provisioning virtual machines on a virtual machine server. <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> supports the integration of such applications with its asynchronous provisioning platform (APP). This is a framework which provides a provisioning service as well as functions, data persistence, and notification features which are always required for integrating applications in asynchronous mode.</p>
            <p>Having deployed the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container, the following service controllers are available, registered, and initialized: </p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>AWS service controller: Can be used for integrating the Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud Web service with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. Refer to the <i>AWS Integration</i> guide for details. </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>OpenStack service controller: Can be used for integrating OpenStack services with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. Refer to the <i>OpenStack</i> Integration guide for details.</p>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p>Before technology providers can use the service controllers, they must be entered as responsible organizations in APP as well as in the service controllers.</p>
            <p><b>To register an organization that is to be responsible for a service controller: </b></p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Login to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> administration portal, and choose <b>Create organization</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu.<p>Make sure to set the <b>Technology provider</b> role for the organization. Refer to the online help for details.</p>
                    </li>
                    <li>Access the Web interface (base URL) of APP in the following format:<p>
                            <codeph>https://&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/oscm-app</codeph>
                        </p><p><codeph>&lt;hostname.fqdn&gt;</codeph> is the name and the fully qualified domain name of the machine where APP has been deployed. <codeph>&lt;port&gt;</codeph> is the port to address the machine (default: <codeph>8881</codeph>), <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> is the default context root of APP and cannot be changed.</p></li>
                    <li>Log in with your user ID and password (default: <codeph>administrator</codeph>, <codeph>admin123</codeph>). </li>
                    <li>Specify the ID of the technology provider organization that is to be responsible for the respective service controller (<codeph>ess.openstack</codeph> or <codeph>ess.aws</codeph>).</li>
                    <li>Click <uicontrol>Save Configuration</uicontrol> to save the settings.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p><b>To update the APP configuration settings</b>: </p>
        </section>

  </conbody>
</concept>
