<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Managing Tenants</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <note>This section is relevant only if <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> is installed in OIDC authentication mode. Refer to <xref
                                        href="../Introduction/c_Authentication.xml"
                                /> for details on authentication modes.</note>
                        <p>When you install <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> in OIDC authentication mode, you define the first, default tenant to connect to a specific OIDC provider. The default tenant can be assigned to any number of organizations and marketplaces for authentication.</p>
                        <p>As an operator, you can create additional tenants to use different OIDC provider systems for the users of individual organizations or marketplaces. To do so:</p>
                        <ol>
                                <li>Take the required preparations in the OIDC provider system. For details, refer to <xref
                                                href="../../Shared/reference/c_Preparation_OIDC_Provider.xml"/>.</li>
                                <li>Create a tenant in the <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> administration portal.</li>
                                <li>Download and fill in the template of the configuration file for the new tenant. For details on tenant configuration files, refer to <xref
                                                href="../../Shared/reference/r_ConfigSettings_OIDC_Tenant.xml"/>.</li>
                                <li>Store the configuration file on the Docker host where <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> is deployed:<p><codeph>&lt;docker>/config/oscm-identity/tenants/tenant-&lt;id>.properties</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;docker></codeph> is the <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> data directory specified at installation time. <codeph>&lt;id></codeph> is the ID of the tenant created in <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />.</p></li>
                        </ol>
                        <p>Users are authenticated against the OIDC provider of the tenant associated with the respective marketplace or administration portal. User names do not need to be unique in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, but only within the scope of each tenant. </p>
                        <p>
                                <note>As the platform operator, you are responsible for the correct configuration of tenants.<p>Be aware that although a marketplace is associated with a tenant, it is, by default, still open for publishing and subscribing to services. To avoid this, marketplace owners need to configure the marketplace in a way to restrict the access to it to specific sellers (authorized sellers only) and/or to specific customer organizations (closed marketplace). </p></note>
                        </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <p><b>To create a tenant, choose the following option:</b>
                        </p>
                        <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> administration portal, choose <b>Manage tenants</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu. For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help. </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
