<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Managing User Accounts</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>As an operator, you can lock the account of a specific user, for example when you assume unauthorized access. You can also unlock an account, for example in case it was locked because the user tried to log in using a wrong password for the configured number of times (default: 3). In addition, you can initiate the generation of a new password for a user. In all cases, the user is notified by email.</p>
                        <p>You can, at any time, view the number of users registered with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> as well as the configured maximum number of registered users (default: 10). At regular intervals (default: 12 hours), the system checks the number of registered users. You are informed by email when this check returns that the allowed number of registered users is exceeded. </p>
                        <p>
                                <note>If an organization uses an external LDAP system for user management, only those fields that are not mapped to settings in the LDAP system can be edited. For example, passwords can only be changed in the LDAP system.</note>
                        </p>
                        <p><b>To manage user accounts, choose one of the following options:</b>
                                <ul>
                                        <li><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> administration portal - Choose <b>Manage users</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu and click the appropriate button.<p>For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help. </p></li>
                                        <li>Command line tool - Use the following commands: <ul>
                                                        <li><codeph>lockuser</codeph> for locking a user account:<p>
                                                            <codeblock>&lt;JAVA_HOME>/bin/java -jar lib/oscm-operatorsvc-client.jar 
 &lt;userkey> &lt;password>
 lockuser userid=&lt;userID></codeblock>
                                                            </p></li>
                                                        <li><codeph>unlockuser</codeph> for unlocking a user account: <p>
                                                            <codeblock>&lt;JAVA_HOME>/bin/java -jar lib/oscm-operatorsvc-client.jar 
 &lt;userkey> &lt;password>
 unlockuser userid=&lt;userID></codeblock>
                                                            </p></li>
                                                        <li><codeph>resetpasswordforuser</codeph> for resetting the password of a user: <p>
                                                            <codeblock>&lt;JAVA_HOME>/bin/java -jar lib/oscm-operatorsvc-client.jar 
 &lt;userkey> &lt;password>
 resetpasswordforuser userid=&lt;userID></codeblock>
                                                            </p></li>
                                                </ul></li>
                                </ul></p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
