<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Creating an Organization</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>You can create an organization and specify its roles (technology provider, supplier, reseller, broker, or - implicitly - customer). For every new organization, you must define a user who is to become its first administrator. This user can later register new users and assign roles to them.</p>
                        <p><b>To create an organization, choose one of the following options:</b>
                                <ul>
                                        <li><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> administration portal - Choose <b>Create organization</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu.<p>For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help. </p></li>
                                        <li>Command line tool: <p>You need to define several properties for the new organization in a properties file before executing the respective command. Proceed as follows: </p><ol>
                                                        <li>Edit the <codeph>org.properties</codeph> file located in the directory to which you extracted the <codeph>oscm-operatorclient.zip</codeph> file. Specify the following entries:<ul
                                                            compact="no">
                                                            <li><codeph>user.address</codeph>: Address of the organization's administrator.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.additionalname</codeph>: Any additional name the administrator might have. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.email</codeph>: Email address of the administrator. Notifications about the creation of the account and access information will be sent to this address.<p>The system checks whether the syntax of the given email address is valid, and whether the domain name corresponds to the standards as defined and maintained by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA). </p><p>Examples: <codeph>user.name@domain.arpa</codeph>, <codeph>user.name@domain.org</codeph>, <codeph>user@mycompany.lan.uk</codeph></p>
                                                            </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.firstname</codeph>: The administrator's first name.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.identifier</codeph>: User ID of the administrator. User IDs are restricted to 100 characters and must not contain any of the following characters: <p><codeph>! " # $ % &amp; ' * + , / : ; &lt; = > ? \ ^ `</codeph>
                                        </p><note>If you create an organization with LDAP-based user management, the user ID must match the ID in the external LDAP system. The organization's LDAP configuration determines which additional settings are required. All settings defined in the configuration must be mapped to corresponding values, for example, first name, last name, email address, and language.</note></li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.lastname</codeph>: The administrator's last name.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.locale</codeph>: Language in which the administrator will work by default. <p>The user interface, available documentation, and emails will be presented to the administrator in the language specified here. </p><p>The language is specified as ISO language code. The ISO language code of any active language available in the system can be given.</p></li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.phone</codeph>: Contact telephone or mobile number of the administrator.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>user.salutation</codeph>: The administrator's title, such as MR or MS.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.description</codeph>: Description of the organization, for example, information from the company's profile. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.email</codeph>: Email address for general communication with the organization. The organization can later specify a separate email address to which invoices are sent. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.locale</codeph>: Default language used in the organization.<p>The language is specified as ISO language code. The ISO language code of any active language available in the system can be given.</p>
                                                            </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.phone</codeph>: Telephone or mobile number of a contact person in the organization.</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.url</codeph>: URL of the organization's website. This website can be accessed by customers when displaying details on the organization that offers a service they want to subscribe to. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.name</codeph>: Name of the organization, for example, the company name. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.address</codeph>: Address of the organization. The organization's administrator can later specify a different address to be printed on invoices. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.domicile</codeph>: Country where the organization is located. Specify an ISO country code, for example <codeph>DE</codeph> or <codeph>US</codeph>. </li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.roles</codeph>: Roles the new organization is to have. Valid values are <codeph>TECHNOLOGY_PROVIDER</codeph>, <codeph>SUPPLIER</codeph>, <codeph>RESELLER</codeph>, <codeph>BROKER</codeph>. If the organization wants to act, for example, both as a supplier and a technology provider, separate the values by a comma without any blanks. The <codeph>RESELLER</codeph> and <codeph>BROKER</codeph> roles cannot be combined with each other or with the <codeph>TECHNOLOGY_PROVIDER</codeph> or <codeph>SUPPLIER</codeph> role. If you do not specify a role, an organization with the <codeph>CUSTOMER</codeph> role will be created. In this case, you must specify the marketplace to which the customer organization will be directed (<codeph>marketplaceid</codeph> parameter). For a <codeph>SUPPLIER</codeph> organization, you must specify the default operator revenue share (<codeph>organization.operatorrevshare</codeph> parameter).</li>
                                                            <li><codeph>marketplaceid</codeph>: ID of the marketplace to which the customer is to be directed. </li>
                                                                <li><codeph>organization.operatorrevshare</codeph>: Revenue share agreed between the operator and the supplier organization, which the operator is to receive from the supplier for selling services on the marketplaces managed on the operator's platform. The default operator revenue share applies to all services offered by the supplier as long as you do not define a service-specific revenue share. It also applies irrespective of whether the supplier sells his services himself, or uses brokers or resellers for selling them. Discounts granted by a supplier to his customers are deducted from the revenue share.<ph audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref
                                                            href="../Billing/c_DefineRevenueShares.xml"/>.</ph></li>
                                                            <li><codeph>organization.settings</codeph>: Fully qualified path and name of an LDAP configuration file containing the parameters required for connecting to the organization's LDAP system. If the organization does not use LDAP-based user management, comment this setting out (<codeph>#organization.settings=</codeph>) in the <codeph>org.properties</codeph> file. <p>Here is a sample configuration file: </p><p
                                            id="LDAPSample">
                                            <codeblock>LDAP_BASE_DN=ou\=people,dc\=est,dc\=mycompany,dc\=de
LDAP_CONTEXT_FACTORY=com.sun.jndi.ldap.LdapCtxFactory
LDAP_URL=ldap://myldapserver.lan.est.company.de:389
LDAP_ATTR_UID=uid
LDAP_ATTR_LAST_NAME=sn
LDAP_ATTR_FIRST_NAME=givenName
LDAP_ATTR_EMAIL=scalixEmailAddress
LDAP_ATTR_REFERRAL=ignore</codeblock>
                                        </p><p audience="doc">For a list of LDAP keys, refer to <xref
                                                href="../../Shared/reference/r_LDAP_SettingTypes.xml"/></p></li>
                                                            </ul></li>
                                                        <li>Save the <codeph>org.properties</codeph> file in UTF-8 encoding. </li>
                                                        <li>Execute the <codeph>createorganization</codeph> command with the following syntax: <p>
                                                            <codeblock>&lt;JAVA_HOME>/bin/java -jar lib/oscm-operatorsvc-client.jar 
 &lt;userkey> &lt;password>
 createorganization -f org.properties</codeblock>
                                                            </p></li>
                                                </ol></li>
                                </ul></p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
