<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_20140219"
            xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Integrating an External Billing System</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Welcome to the sample for integrating an external billing system with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
            <p>The sample consists of a file-based mock billing system and a billing adapter for its integration with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. The billing system and adapter are ready to use, their source code is provided in addition.  You can use the sample to evaluate the retrieval of price models for services, customers, and subscriptions from an external billing system.</p>
            <p>The following sections provide an overview of the resources that make up the sample and a step-by-step description of how to deploy, configure, register, and use the billing system and adapter. For a general description of the steps and issues involved in integrating an external billing system with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, refer to the <i>Developer's Guide</i>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Sample Resources</title>
            <p>The following resources are provided in the <codeph>samples/billingPlugin</codeph> folder:</p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li><codeph>oscm-billing-external-interfaces.jar</codeph> - the billing plug-in API that needs to be implemented by each billing adapter.</li>
                <li><codeph>oscm-file-adapter.ear</codeph> - the deployable billing adapter, including the EJB implementation and remote interface.</li>
                <li><codeph>oscm-file-adapter.jar</codeph> - the EJB implementation of the billing adapter.</li>
                <li><codeph>oscm-file-adapter-src.jar</codeph> - the source code of the billing adapter implementation.</li>
                <li><codeph>oscm-file-billing.war</codeph> - the deployable mock billing system, implemented as a REST Web application,  including the required price model tables and price models in PDF format.</li>
                <li><codeph>oscm-file-billing-src.jar</codeph> - the source code of the mock billing system. </li>
                <li><codeph>TechnicalService_ExternalBilling.xml</codeph> - the definition of a technical service for use with the mock billing system.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Deploying and Configuring the Billing System and Adapter</title>
            <p>You can deploy the billing system and adapter on an application server of your choice. They have been developed and tested with Glassfish 3.1.2.2, which is thus recommended.</p>
            <p>Proceed as follows:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Deploy the billing system, <codeph>oscm-file-billing.war</codeph>, to a domain of your choice on the application server.</li>
                <li>Deploy the billing adapter, <codeph>oscm-file-adapter.ear</codeph>, to the same domain.</li>
                <li>Configure the billing adapter in the following file in the application server domain to which you deployed it: <p><codeph>&lt;domain>/applications/oscm-file-adapter/oscm-file-adapter_jar/billingApplication.properties</codeph></p><p>The file contains the URLs of the billing system. In each of these URLs, change the host name and port to the ones of your installation, for example: </p><p><codeph>priceModelURL=http://<b>myhost:8680</b>/oscm-file-billing/rest/priceModel</codeph></p><p>Save the changed configuration file.</p></li>
                <li>Reload the billing adapter application using the means of your application server.</li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Registering the Billing Adapter</title>
            <p>The billing adapter must be registered in the <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> installation with which you want to use it. This is the task of the installation's operator. </p>
            <p>As the provider of the billing adapter, you are responsible for ensuring the communication with <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. This may, for example, involve the appropriate configuration of firewalls and access paths.</p>
            <p>To register the billing adapter:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal as a platform operator.</li>
                <li>Using the <uicontrol>Manage billing systems</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Operation</uicontrol> menu, add a new billing system. Specify the following information: <table
                        frame="none">
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                            <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><uicontrol>Billing system ID</uicontrol></entry>
                                    <entry><codeph>FILE_BILLING</codeph> or another ID of your choice. This ID must be specified in the definition of the technical services that use the billing system.</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><uicontrol>Name</uicontrol></entry>
                                    <entry>A name of your choice</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><uicontrol>JNDI_NAME</uicontrol></entry>
                                    <entry><codeph>java:global/oscm-file-adapter/oscm-file-adapter</codeph></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><codeph><uicontrol>org.omg.CORBA.ORBInitialPort</uicontrol></codeph></entry>
                                    <entry>The IIOP port of the application server domain where the billing adapter has been deployed.<p>Example: <codeph>8637</codeph> if the portbase of the domain is <codeph>8600</codeph>.</p></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><codeph><uicontrol>java.naming.factory.initial</uicontrol></codeph></entry>
                                    <entry><codeph>com.sun.enterprise.naming.SerialInitContextFactory</codeph></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><codeph><uicontrol>java.naming.provider.url</uicontrol></codeph></entry>
                                    <entry>The URL of the application server domain where the billing adapter has been deployed in the following format: <p><codeph>http://&lt;host>:&lt;port></codeph></p><p>Example: <codeph>http://myhost:8680</codeph></p></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry><codeph><uicontrol>org.omg.CORBA.ORBInitialHost</uicontrol></codeph></entry>
                                    <entry>The name of the host where the billing adapter has been deployed.<p>Example: <codeph>myhost</codeph></p></entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table></li>
                <li>Test the connection to the billing adapter by clicking the corresponding button on the page.</li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Using the Billing System and Adapter</title>
            <p>With a successful configuration and connection between <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and the billing adapter, you can specify the billing system for technical services and obtain price models from it for marketable services, customers, and subscriptions based on these technical services.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Technical Services</title>
            <p>In order to use the sample billing system and adapter for a technical service, you need to specify the billing system ID with which it was registered in the technical service definition XML in the <codeph>billingIdentifier</codeph> attribute of the top <codeph>TechnicalService</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>The billing sample comes with a technical service definition, <codeph>TechnicalService_ExternalBilling.xml</codeph>, which you can use for practicing with external price models. The predefined <codeph>billingIdentifier</codeph> in the sample is <codeph>FILE_BILLING</codeph>, but you can change it as required. Several parameters are defined for the technical service, based on which different price models can be retrieved.</p>
            <p>For practicing, register the technical service in <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal as a technology manager of a technology provider organization.</li>
                <li>Using the <uicontrol>Import service definition</uicontrol> option in the <uicontrol>Technical service</uicontrol> menu, import the XML file containing the service definition.</li>
                <li>Using the <uicontrol>Manage suppliers</uicontrol> option in the <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> menu, appoint a supplier for the new technical service.</li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Price Models</title>
            <p>As a service manager of an authorized supplier organization, you can define price models for marketable services, specific customers, and subscriptions based on the technical service with the billing system configured. You do this using the corresponding options at the <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal. Upon each import request for a price model from the billing system, the billing adapter returns a PDF file with the appropriate contents matching the context in <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
            <p>The predefined price model PDF files of the sample are available in language-specific subfolders of the following folder in the application server domain to which you deployed the billing system and adapter: </p>
            <p><codeph>&lt;domain>/applications/oscm-file-billing/WEB-INF/classes/pm</codeph></p>
            <p>The decision which price model to return to <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> is made based on the entries in the following files in the same folder: </p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li><codeph>ServicePriceModel.csv</codeph> - for service price models and customer-specific price models</li>
                <li><codeph>SubscriptionPriceModel.csv</codeph> - for subscription price models</li>
            </ul>
            <p>In both files, the <codeph>UUID</codeph>, <codeph>FileType</codeph>, and <codeph>FileName</codeph> columns specify the price model to be returned. <codeph>UUID</codeph> is a unique ID, <codeph>FileType</codeph> the type of the price model file, <codeph>FileName</codeph> the path and name of the file. The <codeph>Tag</codeph> column in the <codeph>ServicePriceModel.csv</codeph> file specifies a string to be returned to <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> together with the price model for display in the service details.</p>
            <p>The remaining columns of the <codeph>.csv</codeph> files specify the locale and the <ph
                    conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> context for which a price model is to be returned. For subscriptions, this the subscription ID. For services, it is the combination of service parameters (<codeph>INSTANCE</codeph>, <codeph>REGION</codeph>, <codeph>OS</codeph>). The customer ID is evaluated for customer-specific price models.</p>
            <p><b>Examples: </b></p>
            <p>For a service with the parameter values<codeph> t2.micro</codeph> for <codeph>INSTANCE</codeph>, <codeph>eu-west-1</codeph> for <codeph>REGION</codeph>, and <codeph>linux</codeph> for <codeph>OS</codeph>, the language-specific price model <codeph>t2_micro_eu_frankfurt_linux.pdf</codeph> and the tag <codeph>Starting at 4.97 $/Month</codeph> are returned. </p>
            <p>For a subscription named <codeph>Trial Subscription</codeph>, the language-specific price model <codeph>trial_subscription.pdf</codeph> is returned.</p>
            <p><b>Be aware of the following:</b></p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>The service parameter values in the <codeph>ServicePriceModel.csv</codeph> file must match the ones defined in the technical service definition. </li>
                <li>The predefined parameter value combinations in the <codeph>ServicePriceModel.csv</codeph> file are not complete. You may want to add further combinations. </li>
                <li>The same applies to the predefined price models. You can at any time add PDF files in the language-specific folders.</li>
                <li>In order to obtain customer-specific price models in <ph
                        conref="../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you need to insert the correct customer ID in the <codeph>ServicePriceModel.csv</codeph> file.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
