<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept
                    id="id_276_5d6080f4">
  <title>Configuration Steps Required for IdP Communication</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p>When using <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in SAML_SP mode, several configuration steps in <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and in the IdP system are required. </p>
      <p><b>Steps to be performed by the IdP operator: </b></p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
                    <li>A contractual relationship with the IdP operator must exist so that the IdP can allow for Web browser SSO and secure Web service calls using a Security Token Service (STS).</li>
                    <li>
                        <p>The IdP operator must provide the following information:</p>
                        <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li>Entity ID of the IdP system. He can find out the ID by retrieving the federation metadata in the IdP system. </li>
                                <li>Length of the encryption key used by the IdP system.</li>
                                <li>Whether the IdP system can process <codeph>GET</codeph> or <codeph>POST</codeph> authentication requests.</li>
                                <li>The public key certificate of the IdP system. </li>
                            </ul>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>The IdP operator must provide information on the following service endpoints:<p>
                            <ul>
                                <li>For Web browser SSO: the SAML Redirect URL of the IdP as well as the URL of the single logout service endpoint.</li>
                                <li>For STS communication: STS service endpoint URL as well as the URL pointing to the MEX address (Issuer Metadata Exchange) of the STS. </li>
                            </ul>
                        </p><p>The IdP operator must ensure that the correct service endpoints for the Web UI SSO and STS connections are activated. </p><p>In a multi-tenancy environment and when several tenants are associated with one and the same IdP, one service endpoint per tenant must be defined and communicated.</p></li>
                    <li>For Web browser SSO, an SSO federation with the IdP must be established in a way that <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> acts as the relying party. The IdP operator must create this relying party for <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> in the IdP, and all <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> users must be allowed to access this relying party. In this way, <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> is registered with the IdP. <p>One way to achieve this is to use <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> metadata. The minimum data required are a name or ID of <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> as a service provider (as specified in the <codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph> configuration key) and the URL to which the IdP is to send its responses (as specified in the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> or <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> configuration key). Thus the URL of the relying party is usually the URL for accessing the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> administration portal.</p><p>The IdP operator requires a URL in the following format: </p><p><codeph>http://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/&lt;context-root&gt;/saml2/metadata.jsp</codeph>
                        </p><p>where <codeph>&lt;host&gt;, &lt;port&gt;</codeph>, and <codeph>&lt;context-root&gt;</codeph> point to the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> installation.</p></li>
                    <li>For using the STS for authenticating Web service calls and for handling logout requests, the IdP operator requires the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> signature verification certificate. He has to import this certificate into the truststore of the application server where the STS is deployed. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </li>
                    <li>For Web browser SSO and for STS, the assertions returned to <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> must contain user IDs and the corresponding tenant ID for each user. This is required for <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> to map the users to the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> user roles (such as administrator, service manager, marketplace manager), and to ensure the uniqueness of user IDs. <p>To achieve this, the IdP must be configured such that its assertions contain two <codeph>&lt;AttributeStatement&gt;</codeph> elements. The first <codeph>&lt;Attribute&gt;</codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="userid"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue&gt;</codeph> subelement must specify the user ID that matches the ID of the calling user in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> . The second <codeph>&lt;Attribute&gt;</codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="tenantID"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue&gt;</codeph> subelement must specify the ID of the tenant associated with the organization the corresponding user belongs to.</p><p>Example: </p><p>
                            <codeblock>&lt;saml:Assertion ...&gt;
    ...
    &lt;saml:AttributeStatement&gt;
      &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="userid"</b>&gt;
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue&gt;administrator&lt;/saml:AttributeValue&gt;</b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute&gt;
    &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="tenantID"</b>&gt;
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue&gt;34ffd098&lt;/saml:AttributeValue&gt;</b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute&gt;
    &lt;/saml:AttributeStatement&gt;
  &lt;/saml:Assertion&gt;
</codeblock>
                        </p><note>
                            <p>Be aware that the SAML assertions returned from the IdP always need at least contain the default tenant ID in case you do not want to make use of the multi-tenancy functionality. </p>
                        </note></li>
                </ol>
      </p>
      <p><b>Steps to be performed by the <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator: </b></p>
      <p>
        <ol>
          <li
                                audience="BSS">
            <p>The following settings in the <codeph>configsettings.properties</codeph> file are mandatory when installing <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in <b>SAML_SP</b> authentication mode: </p>
            <p>
              <ul>
                <li><codeph>AUTH_MODE</codeph>:<p>Must be set to <codeph>SAML_SP</codeph> (default is <codeph>INTERNAL</codeph>).</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_DEFAULT_TENANT_ID</codeph>: <p>A unique identifier associated with the IdP that all users registered with <ph
                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph
                                            platform="help"
                                        >the platform</ph> are authenticated against when they access a marketplace or the administration portal. You must provide the IdP operator with the value specified here.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph><p>A unique identifier for <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. The IdP system uses this ID for identifying incoming authentication requests from <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. You must provide the IdP operator with the value specified here.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_URL</codeph><p>The SAML Redirect URL of the IdP system.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_AUTHENTICATION_REQUEST_HTTP_METHOD</codeph><p>Information on whether the IdP can process <codeph>GET</codeph> or <codeph>POST</codeph> authentication requests. </p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_SAML_ASSERTION_ISSUER_ID</codeph><p>The entity ID of the IdP system. The IdP administrator can find out the ID by retrieving the federation metadata on his IdP system. </p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_STS_URL</codeph><p>STS service endpoint URL.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_STS_METADATA_URL</codeph><p>URL pointing to the MEX address (Issuer Metadata Exchange) of the STS.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_STS_ENCKEY_LEN</codeph><p>Length of the encryption key used by the IdP.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_LOGOUT_URL</codeph><p>URL of the single logout service endpoint.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE</codeph><p>The path and file name of the application server truststore file holding the public key certificate of the IdP.</p></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD</codeph><p>The password of the application server truststore holding the public key certificate of the IdP.</p></li>
              </ul>
            </p>
          </li>
          <li>For Web browser SSO: Import the IdP certificate into the application server truststore where <ph
                            audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> is deployed, and set the <codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE</codeph> and <codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD</codeph> configuration keys accordingly. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling.</li>
                    <li>Provide the <ph audience="BSS"
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> signature verification certificate to the IdP operator. </li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>

  </conbody>
</concept>
