<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept
                    id="id_276_5d6080f4">
  <title>Configuration Steps Required for IdP Communication</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p>After having successfully deployed <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> in SAML_SP mode, several steps must be performed in <ph
          conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and in the IdP system.</p>
      <p><b>Steps to be performed by the <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator: </b></p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>For Web browser SSO: Import the IdP certificate into the application server truststore where <ph
              audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
              /> is deployed, and set the <codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE</codeph> and <codeph>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD</codeph> configuration settings accordingly. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling.</li>
          <li>Provide the <ph audience="BSS" conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
            /> signature verification certificate to the IdP operator.</li>
          <li>Provide the IdP operator with the values of the following configuration settings: <p>
              <ul>
                <li><codeph>SSO_DEFAULT_TENANT_ID</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph></li>
              </ul>
            </p>
          </li>
          <li>Provide the IdP operator with an URL in the following format: <p><codeph>http://&lt;host&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/&lt;context-root&gt;/saml2/metadata.jsp</codeph>
            </p><p>where <codeph>&lt;host&gt;, &lt;port&gt;</codeph>, and <codeph>&lt;context-root&gt;</codeph> point to the <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> installation.</p>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><b>Steps to be performed by the IdP operator: </b></p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>The IdP operator must ensure that the correct service endpoints for the Web browser SSO and STS connections are activated. <p>In a multi-tenancy environment and when several tenants are associated with one and the same IdP, both service endpoints must be defined per tenant and communicated to the <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator.</p></li>
          <li>For Web browser SSO, an SSO federation with the IdP must be established in a way that <ph
              conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> acts as the relying party:<p>The IdP operator must create this relying party for <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in the IdP system, and all <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> users must be allowed to access this relying party. In this way, <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> is registered with the IdP.</p><p>One way to achieve this is to use <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> metadata. The minimum data required are a name or ID of <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> as a service provider (as specified in the <codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph> configuration setting) and the URL to which the IdP is to send its responses (as specified in the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> or <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> configuration setting). </p></li>
          <li>For using the STS for authenticating Web service calls and for handling logout requests, the IdP operator requires the <ph
              conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
              /> signature verification certificate. He has to import this certificate into the truststore of the application server where the STS is deployed. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </li>
          <li>For Web browser SSO and for STS connections, the assertions returned to <ph
              conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
              /> must contain the user ID and the corresponding tenant ID for each user. This is required for <ph
              conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> to map the users to the <ph
              conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user roles (such as administrator, service manager, marketplace manager), and to ensure the uniqueness of user IDs. <p>To achieve this, the IdP must be configured such that its assertions contain two <codeph>&lt;AttributeStatement&gt;</codeph> elements. The first <codeph>&lt;Attribute&gt;</codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="userid"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue&gt;</codeph> subelement must specify the user ID of the calling user in <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> . The second <codeph>&lt;Attribute&gt;</codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="tenantID"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue&gt;</codeph> subelement must specify the ID of the tenant associated with the organization the user belongs to.</p><p>Example: </p><p>
              <codeblock>&lt;saml:Assertion ...&gt;
    ...
    &lt;saml:AttributeStatement&gt;
      &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="userid"</b>&gt;
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue&gt;administrator&lt;/saml:AttributeValue&gt;</b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute&gt;
    &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="tenantID"</b>&gt;
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue&gt;34ffd098&lt;/saml:AttributeValue&gt;</b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute&gt;
    &lt;/saml:AttributeStatement&gt;
  &lt;/saml:Assertion&gt;
</codeblock>
            </p><note>
              <p>Be aware that the SAML assertions returned from the IdP always need to contain at least the default tenant ID in case you do not want to make use of the multi-tenancy functionality. </p>
            </note></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </section>

  </conbody>
</concept>
