<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Next_Steps_72" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Deploying the BIRT Report Engine</title>
        <conbody>
                <section product="oscm_ce">
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> uses BIRT to generate reports. BIRT is not included in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> packages. To be able to generate reports, you need to obtain and manually deploy BIRT on your own.</p>
                        <p>BIRT needs to be deployed on an application server other than that of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
                        <p>Proceed as follows:</p>
                        <ol>
                                <li>Download the latest version of Eclipse BIRT runtime, for example, from http://www.eclipse.org.</li>
                                <li>Deploy the <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive to a domain on the application server. </li>
                                <li>Add the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> report designs and localized labels to the folder of the <codeph>birt</codeph> application on the application server. <p>The <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> report designs and labels are available in the following archive provided for each release: <codeph>oscm-reports.zip</codeph>. Extract the contents of this archive to the root folder of the <codeph>birt</codeph> application:</p><p><codeph>&lt;GLASSFISH3_HOME>/glassfish/domains/&lt;domain>/applications/birt</codeph> or</p><p><codeph>&lt;TOMCAT_HOME>/webapps/birt</codeph>.</p><p><codeph>&lt;GLASSFISH3_HOME></codeph> is the installation directory of GlassFish, version 3. <codeph>&lt;TOMCAT_HOME></codeph> is the installation directory of Apache Tomcat. </p><p>Be aware of the following: </p><p>The <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive contains the properties files for the labels and texts used in reports. With a new release or fix, new keys may have been added to the system, others may have been changed or deleted. </p><p>Existing texts in English, German, and Japanese are overwritten by an upgrade. If you have customized these texts, merge your customizations into the properties files before deploying the <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive. Otherwise they will no longer be available after the upgrade. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details. </p></li>
                                <li>Restart <codeph>birt</codeph>.</li>
                        </ol>
                        <p>Each time you install a new release of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, you should also check for new releases of BIRT and changes in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> report designs and labels and update them as required. </p>
                </section>
                <section product="oscm_ee">
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> uses BIRT to generate reports. BIRT is included in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> packages. BIRT needs to be deployed on an application server other than <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
                        <p>Be aware of the following: </p>
                        <p>The <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive contains the properties files for the labels and texts used in reports. With a new release or fix, new keys may have been added to the system, others may have been changed or deleted. </p>
                        <p>Existing texts in English, German, and Japanese are overwritten by an upgrade. If you have customized these texts, merge your customizations into the properties files before deploying the <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive. Otherwise they will no longer be available after the upgrade. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details. </p>
                        <p>Proceed as follows: </p>
                        <ol>
                                <li>Deploy the <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive located in <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/domains/bes_domain/applications</codeph> to a domain on the application server.</li>
                                <li>Restart <codeph>birt</codeph>.</li>
                        </ol>
                </section>
                <section><title>Exchanging Certificates</title><p>For secure communication of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> with the BIRT report engine, you need to exchange the corresponding certificates:</p><p>Export the certificate of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> and import it into the truststore of the domain to which you have deployed BIRT. </p>Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
