<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Next_Steps_72" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Next Steps</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>After you have successfully completed the installation of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, you can <ph product="oscm_ce">deploy BIRT in order to enable reports and </ph>optionally change the URL to be used for accessing the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> administration portal and the marketplaces. You can then start to set up the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> organizations using the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal. </p>
                </section>
                <section product="oscm_ce">
                        <title>Deploying BIRT</title>
                        <p>### is the deployment of birt also required for CT-MG Enterprise edition? ### </p>
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> uses BIRT to generate reports. BIRT is not included in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> packages. To be able to generate reports, you need to obtain and manually deploy BIRT on your own. </p>
                        <p>Proceed as follows:</p>
                        <ol>
                                <li>Download the latest version of Eclipse BIRT runtime, for example, from http://www.eclipse.org.</li>
                                <li>Deploy the <codeph>birt.war</codeph> archive to a domain on the application server which you use for <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. You can deploy the archive to the <codeph>bes-domain</codeph> domain of OSCM or a separate domain.</li>
                                <li>Add the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> report designs and localized labels to the folder of the <codeph>birt</codeph> application on the application server. <p>The <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> report designs and labels are available in the following archive provided for each release: <codeph>oscm-reports.zip</codeph>. Extract the contents of this archive to the root folder of the <codeph>birt</codeph> application, <codeph>&lt;GLASSFISH_HOME>/glassfish/domains/&lt;domain>/applications/birt</codeph>.</p></li>
                                <li>Restart <codeph>birt</codeph>.</li>
                        </ol>
                        <p>Each time you install a new release of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, you should also check for new releases of BIRT and changes in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> report designs and labels and update them as required. </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Setting the Context Root</title>
                        <p>By default, i.e. if you used the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> installation scripts, the context root of the URL used for accessing the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> administration portal and the marketplaces is <codeph>oscm-portal</codeph>. You can change this setting in the application server administration console. In addition, you need to adapt the <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> configuration setting, and, if specified, the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> configuration setting, in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
                        <p>
Proceed as follows:</p>
                        <p>
                                <ol>
                                        <li>In the application server administration console:<p>
                                                        <ol>
                                                            <li>Go to <b>Applications -> oscm-portal -> Edit</b> and set the <b>Context Root</b> as required.</li>
                                                            <li>Go to <b>Applications -> oscm-portal-help -> Edit</b> and set the <b>Context Root</b> analogously to the one for <codeph>oscm-portal</codeph>. <p>Example: If you set the context root for <codeph>oscm-portal</codeph> to <codeph>MyPortal</codeph>, set it to <codeph>MyPortal-help</codeph> for <codeph>oscm-portal-help</codeph>.</p>
                                                            </li>
                                                        </ol>
                                                </p></li>
                                        <li> In the <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> administration portal, go to <b>Operation -> Update Configuration Settings</b> and change the <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> configuration key, and, if specified, the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> configuration key, accordingly. See below for details on accessing <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. </li>
                                </ol>
                        </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Accessing <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>
                        </title>
                        <p>You can access the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> administration portal in a Web browser using an URL in the following format: </p>
                        <p><codeph>https://&lt;server&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/&lt;context-root>/&lt;tenant-id></codeph> or </p>
                        <p><codeph>http://&lt;server&gt;:&lt;port&gt;/&lt;context-root>/&lt;tenant-id></codeph>
                        </p>
                        <p><codeph>&lt;server&gt;</codeph> is the host of the application server where <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> has been deployed. <codeph>&lt;port&gt;</codeph> is the port to address the application server (default: <codeph>8080</codeph> for HTTP, <codeph>8081</codeph> for HTTPS). <codeph>&lt;context-root></codeph> is the context root of <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> (default: <codeph>oscm-portal</codeph>). <codeph>&lt;tenant-id></codeph> is the ID of the tenant specified when installing <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> in SAML_SP mode. If installed in INTERNAL mode, the tenant ID is not appended to the URL.   </p>
                        <p>You are prompted for a user ID and password. </p>
                        <p>Depending on the authentication mode, the initial credentials are the following: </p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>INTERNAL: <p>User ID: <codeph>administrator</codeph></p><p>Password: <codeph>admin123</codeph></p><p>It is recommended that you change the initial password in the <ph
                                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                        /> administration portal (<b>Change Password</b> page in the <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> menu). </p></li>
                                <li>SAML_SP: <p>User ID: The ID you specified in the <codeph>ADMIN_USER_ID</codeph> configuration key in the <codeph>sso.properties</codeph> configuration file. </p><p>Password: Password as known in the IdP for the above user. </p></li>
                        </ul>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Creating an Additional Operator Account</title>
                        <p>The creation of an additional operator account for your organization is useful, for example, to be able to delegate operational tasks or to unlock other operator accounts in case the password has been forgotten. Proceed as follows: </p>
                        <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> administration portal, choose <uicontrol>Register new users</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> menu. Enter the relevant user data and assign at least the <uicontrol>Operator</uicontrol> role. </p>
                </section>
                <section>
                        <title>Changing the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> Configuration</title>
                        <p>Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide </i>in case you need to change the configuration of your <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> installation. </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
