<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="Adapting_Configuration_Files_68" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuration Steps Required for IdP Communication</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context id="The_task_taskbody_context">
            <p>After having successfully deployed <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> in SAML_SP authentication mode, the following steps must be performed in the IdP and in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>:</p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>The IdP operator must ensure that the correct endpoints for the Web UI SSO and STS connections are activated. </li>
                    <li>For STS, the IdP operator must create the relying party for <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> in the IdP, and all <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> users must be allowed to access this relying party. The URL of the relying party is usually the URL for accessing the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> administration portal.</li>
                    <li>For Web browser SSO, an SSO federation with the IdP must be established in a way that <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> acts as the relying party.</li>
                    <li><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> must be registered with the IdP. One way to achieve this is to use <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> metadata. The minimum data required are a name or ID of <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> as a service provider (as specified in the <codeph>SSO_ISSUER_ID</codeph> configuration key) and the URL to which the IdP is to send its responses (as specified in the <codeph>BASE_URL</codeph> or <codeph>BASE_URL_HTTPS</codeph> configuration key). <p>The IdP operator requires a URL in the following format: </p><p><codeph>http://&lt;host>:&lt;port>/&lt;context-root>/saml2/metadata.jsp</codeph>
                        </p><p>where <codeph>&lt;host>, &lt;port></codeph>, and <codeph>&lt;context-root></codeph> point to the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> installation.</p></li>
                    <li>For Web browser SSO: Import the IdP certificate into the application server truststore where <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr" audience="BSS"
                                /> is deployed, and set the <codeph><b>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE</b></codeph> and <codeph><b>SSO_IDP_TRUSTSTORE_PASSWORD</b></codeph> configuration keys accordingly. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </li>
                    <li>For using the STS for authenticating Web service calls, the IdP operator requires the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> domain certificate. He has to import this certificate into the truststore of the application server where the STS is deployed. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on certificate handling. </li>
                    <li>For Web browser SSO and for STS, the assertions returned to <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> must contain user IDs and the corresponding tenant ID for each user. This is required for <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> to map the users to the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> user roles (such as administrator, service manager, marketplace manager), and to ensure the uniqueness of user IDs. <p>To achieve this, the IdP must be configured such that its assertions contain two <codeph>&lt;AttributeStatement></codeph> elements. The first <codeph>&lt;Attribute></codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="userid"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue></codeph> subelement must specify the user ID that matches the ID of the calling user in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> . The second <codeph>&lt;Attribute></codeph> subelement must contain a <codeph>Name="tenantID"</codeph> property, and the <codeph>&lt;AttributeValue></codeph> subelement must specify the ID of the tenant associated with the organization the corresponding user belongs to.</p><p>Example: </p><p>
                            <codeblock>&lt;saml:Assertion ...>
    ...
    &lt;saml:AttributeStatement>
      &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="userid"</b>>
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue>administrator&lt;/saml:AttributeValue></b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute>
    &lt;saml:Attribute <b>Name="tenantID"</b>>
        <b>&lt;saml:AttributeValue>34ffd098&lt;/saml:AttributeValue></b>
      &lt;/saml:Attribute>
    &lt;/saml:AttributeStatement>
  &lt;/saml:Assertion>
</codeblock>
                        </p><note>
                            <p>Be aware that the SAML assertions returned from the IdP always need at least contain the default tenant ID in case you do not want to make use of the multi-tenancy functionality. </p>
                        </note></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
