<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="id_112">
  <title>Usage Scenarios</title>
  <conbody>
    <section>
      <p>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /> Azure integration supports the following usage scenarios: </p>
      <ul compact="no">
        <li><b>Provisioning of virtual machines in existing resource groups</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service on an <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> marketplace, the service controller triggers the ARM to deploy one or more virtual machines to a given resource group with a complete network configuration. Depending on the service parameters, a new storage account is created or an existing one is used. </li>
        <li><b>Provisioning of resource groups with virtual machines</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service on an <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> marketplace, the service controller triggers the ARM to deploy a new resource group with the network configuration, storage account, and virtual machines specified by the service parameters.</li>
        <li><b>Starting and stopping virtual machines</b>: By executing the respective service operation at a corresponding subscription, the customer can start and stop the virtual machines created for the subscription. </li>
        <li><b>Deletion of resources</b>: When a customer terminates a subscription, the service controller triggers the ARM to delete all the resources (virtual machines, storage account, resource group) created for the subscription. The subscription is terminated in <ph
            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /> independent of whether the deletion in Azure is successful.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>In Azure, the virtual machines and resource groups created for <ph
          conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /> subscriptions are managed in the same way as other resources. They can be viewed and monitored with the available Azure tools.</p>
      <p>Modifying a subscription and thereby triggering modifications of the resources in Azure is not supported.<ph
          audience="doc"> For more details on the supported usage scenarios, refer to <xref
            href="../Using/c_UsingIntro.xml"/>.</ph></p>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
