<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Providing Templates for the Provisioning of Resources</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
            <p>There are the following ways to provide templates for the provisioning of virtual resources. These templates can be referenced in technical service definitions.</p>
            <p><b>To provide templates:</b></p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>Copy the template files to a location of your choice that can be reached from <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> by HTTP or HTTPS. For example, you could copy them to the <codeph>docroot/templates</codeph> directory of the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain in your application server.<p>Specify this location in the <codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</codeph> controller configuration setting. </p></li>
                    <li>Import the template files into the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database:<ol>
                            <li>In a Web browser, access the URL of the OpenStack service controller, for example: <p><codeph>http://127.0.0.1:8880/oscm-app-openstack</codeph></p></li>
                            <li>Log in with the ID and password of the user specified in the configuration settings for the OpenStack service controller (<codeph>BSS_USER_ID</codeph> and <codeph>BSS_USER_PWD</codeph>) or as another technology manager registered for the same organization.</li>
                            <li audience="os">
                                <p>Click in the <uicontrol>File name</uicontrol> field or click <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol>, and select the file containing the desired template. </p>
                            </li>
                            <li audience="os">
                                <p>Click <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>.</p>
                            </li>
                        </ol><p>If a template with the same name is imported twice, the original (first) one is replaced by the second one. </p><p>The OpenStack integration software looks for the template with the name specified in the technical service definition (<codeph>TEMPLATE_NAME</codeph> service parameter) as follows: </p><p>
                            <ol>
                                <li>The template is searched for in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. </li>
                                <li>If it is not found, the template is searched for in the location specified in the <codeph>TEMPLATE_BASE_URL</codeph> controller configuration setting.</li>
                            </ol>
                        </p></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
