<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
        <title>Service Management</title>
        <conbody>
                <section>
                        <p>Your main task as a reseller is to sell services defined by suppliers. To this end, you prepare the services and offer them on a marketplace to which you have been granted access by the marketplace owner.</p>
                        <p>The supplier of a service is responsible for: </p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>Defining the service and specifying its parameters, conditions, and restrictions. </li>
                                <li>Defining a price model for the service which specifies whether and how much customers subscribing to the service will be charged for using it.</li>
                                <li>Granting you the permission to publish the service on a marketplace of your choice.</li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>As a reseller, you cannot change the service definition and the price model. The contract between you and the customer subscribing to a service is based on the prices defined by the supplier. It is up to the supplier to change the prices, if required. </p>
                        <p>As a reseller who has been granted the permission for a service, you can:</p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>View the service definition and price model.</li>
                                <li>Define your own license agreement for using the service.</li>
                                <li>Publish the service.</li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>These tasks are described in more detail in the sections below. </p>
                </section>
        </conbody>
</concept>
