<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Creating Marketable Services</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Creating a marketable service means specifying its parameters, conditions, and restrictions. </p>
            <p>To create a marketable service, use the <uicontrol>Define a service</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketable service</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> administration portal. </p>
            <p id="Creating_a_marketable_service_concept_conbody_section_p_2"
                >When you create a marketable service, you first have to select the technical service the marketable service is to be based on. You can then specify the following elements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>A <b>service identifier</b>. This is offered for selection when you update or delete the service, or when you specify upgrade and downgrade options or a price model for it. <p>The service identifier is mandatory. It must be unique within the marketable services of your organization.</p></li>
                <li>An <b>image</b> representing the service. This may be useful, for example, for customers to identify the service.<p>The image is shown in the service catalog on the marketplace to which you publish the service.</p></li>
                <li>A <b>service name for customers</b>. The name should be meaningful and should have a high recognition value.<p>The service name for customers is shown in the service catalog on the marketplace to which you publish the service. If you do not specify it, a string is displayed saying that it is not defined. </p></li>
                <li>A <b>short description</b> that briefly introduces the service. It may, for example, provide a short overview of the features the service provides.<p>The short description is shown in the service catalog on the marketplace to which you publish the service.</p></li>
                <li>A <b>service description</b> that provides, for example, details of the features offered by the service. <p>The underlying technical service comes with a description that is displayed by default for the marketable service. It is up to you whether you use the description as defined by the technical service, or whether you enter a different one.</p><p><ph
                            id="On_a_marketplace_with_custom_concept_conbody_section_ul_l"
                            >The service description is shown to customers on a marketplace when they request details of a service.</ph></p></li>
                <li><b>Service parameters</b> related to subscription and usage. <p><ph
                            conref="../../help/tasks/service_add.xml#task634/Subscription_parameters_inclu_task_taskbody_steps_step_3"
                        /></p><p><ph
                            conref="../../help/tasks/service_add.xml#task634/Usage_parameters_include_for_task_taskbody_steps_step_3"
                        /></p></li>
                <li>An external <b>parameter configuration tool</b> that your customers can use for configuring the service parameters and for viewing their prices per subscription when they subscribe to the service on a marketplace.<p>You can integrate a third-party or proprietary parameter configuration tool of your choice with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. During the subscription process, the tool replaces the default user interface for configuring service parameters. To link the tool with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you have to specify the URL of the tool in the service definition.</p><p><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> provides a generic interface by which you can integrate the tool. <!--ph>For details on the integration, refer to the <i>Developer's Guide</i>.</ph--></p></li>
                <li>A <b>custom tab</b> for integrating a Web page or Web application for providing detailed information on a service and its operation to your customers. Customers may open the custom tab when they display details on a subscription on a marketplace. Particularly users of IaaS services are interested in additional details on the service and the operation of the service they subscribed to. Using a custom tab, you can provide the information needed for accessing provisioned instances, such as IP addresses, network information, or user credentials.<p>To link the Web page or Web application with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you have to specify its URL in the service definition.</p></li>
            </ul>
            <p>Additionally, you can specify whether a user subscribing to the service is automatically assigned to the corresponding subscription.</p>
            <p>The service name for customers, the short description, the description, and the name of the custom tab can be specified in one or several languages.<ph audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref
                    href="../MarketableServices/c_MSMaintain.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
