<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Configuring the Status Information Page</title>
            <conbody>
        <section>For checking the status of a script execution, you can add a custom tab to the <b>Details</b> view for subscriptions on a marketplace when defining a marketable service: <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>Make sure that a script for checking the status of provisioned instances is available. Refer to the sample script <xref
                            href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app-shell/tree/master/src/main/resources/sample_scripts/advanced_scripts"
                            scope="external"><u><codeph>status.sh</codeph></u></xref> for details. </li>
                    <li>When creating or editing a marketable service for Shell script execution, specify the <b>URL of a custom tab</b>. This URL points to a Web page or Web application the content of which will be retrieved and shown on the custom tab. Using a custom tab, you can provide the information needed for accessing, for example, provisioned instances, such as IP addresses, network information, or user credentials.<p>A predefined custom tab, <codeph>serverInformation.xhtml</codeph>, is available for viewing the output of a status script, e.g. <codeph>status.sh</codeph>.</p><p>Set the URL for the custom tab in the following format:</p><p><codeph>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8881/&lt;service controller name>/serverInformation.jsf</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> is the fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                />, <codeph>8881</codeph> is the port of APP. <codeph>&lt;service controller name></codeph> is the default context root of the relevant service controller and cannot be changed. </p><p>For example: </p><p><codeph>https://myhost:8881/oscm-app-shell/serverInformation.jsf</codeph></p>
                    </li>
                    <li>Enter a <b>Name of the custom tab</b>, for example, <codeph>Status</codeph>. Do not enter <codeph>Details</codeph> because the first tab is named that way. </li>
                    <li>Enter the name of the status script in the <b>Retrieve status of provisioned instance. Absolute filesystem path or URL to script file</b> field of the service parameters. It is assumed that the script is located in the <codeph>/opt/scripts/</codeph> folder of your Docker host where the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container has been deployed. </li>
                    <li>Save the marketable service definition. </li>
                    <li>Activate the marketable service, log in to the marketplace, and create a subscription to the service. </li>
                    <li>Under <b>My Subscriptions</b>, you can now see the <b>Status</b> tab next to the <b>Details</b> tab. </li>
                </ol>
            </p><p>For details on defining marketable services, refer to the <i>Supplier's Guide</i> and to the online help of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
