<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Prerequisites_and_Preparation_59" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Prerequisites and Preparation</title>
    <conbody>
        <p>The following prerequisites must be fulfilled before you can create and publish services in <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        <section>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>To create technical services for the Shell integration in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you must have access to <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> as a technology manager. You must be a member of the technology provider organization responsible for the Shell service controller as specified in the configuration settings for the installation. </li>
                <li>To create marketable services for the Shell integration in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, you must have access to <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> as a service manager of an organization with the supplier role. This may be the same organization as the technology provider organization or a different one.</li>
                <li>To publish your marketable services, you must have access to an appropriate marketplace in in your service manager role.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Preparing and Providing Shell Scripts</title>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>Shell scripts must exist. They form the basis for the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </li>
                <li>Sample scripts are available <xref
                        href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app-shell/tree/master/src/test/resources/sample_scripts/advanced_scripts"
                        scope="external"><u>here</u></xref>.</li>
                <li>The technology provider organization responsible for the Shell service controller prepares the scripts to be called by the Shell service controller. These scripts can be defined in marketable service parameters and then be referenced as scripts located either inside or outside (external URL) the Docker host. <p>To reference a script located inside the Docker host, you need to provide it in the following directory on your Docker host: </p><p><codeph>/opt/scripts</codeph></p><p>As soon as you provide new scripts or change existing ones, you must restart the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container. </p></li>
                <li>After deployment, the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container has the above shared file system mounted. </li>
                <li>The Shell service controller will run scripts stored on the shared file system as the same UNIX user who runs the <codeph>oscm-app</codeph> container:<p>
                        <fig>
                            <image href="../_images/RunningEnv.png" alt="RunningEnv.png" width="400" height="171"/>
                        </fig>
                    </p></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Shell Script Syntax and Rules</title>
            <p>Shell scripts to be executed properly are subject to the following rules: </p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>Each script must return a valid JSON object followed by an <codeph>"END_OF_SCRIPT"</codeph> string value. In this way, the Shell service controller can determine that a script has finished successfully. Otherwise the script execution will run into a timeout.</li>
                    <li>Each script must return exactly one JSON object. </li>
                    <li>The JSON result may contain the following JSON keywords:<ul compact="no">
                            <li><codeph>status</codeph> (mandatory) - allowed values: <codeph>"ok"</codeph> or <codeph>"error"</codeph></li>
                            <li><codeph>message</codeph> (mandatory) - may contain information related to the script execution addressed to the user.</li>
                            <li><codeph>data</codeph> (optional) - may contain any data which can be output in the <b>Status</b> tab after the script has been executed. You can include the following JSON keywords in the <codeph>data</codeph> field: <ul
                                    compact="no">
                                    <li><codeph>output</codeph> (optional) - may contain any data to be presented, for example, HTML data for the status script. </li>
                                    <li><codeph>accessInfo</codeph> (optional) - may contain access information to be passed to the subscription details for display. </li>
                                    <li><codeph>name</codeph> (optional) - may contain any temporary data.</li>
                                    <li><codeph>id</codeph> (optional) - may contain any ID. </li>
                                </ul></li>
                        </ul></li>
                    <li>Special characters used in scripts must be properly escaped.</li>
                    <li>You find valid and invalid script samples <xref
                            href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app-shell/tree/master/src/test/resources/sample_scripts"
                            scope="external"><u>here</u></xref>.</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
