<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Preparing_Shell_Scripts_60" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Preparing for Azure Automation</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>The Shell controller allows customers to connect to Microsoft Azure from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and manage their resources by scheduling and executing Azure Automation runbooks. For this to be possible, preparations need to be taken in Microsoft Azure and <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Preparations in Microsoft Azure</title>
            <p>In order to connect to Microsoft Azure, a valid service principal (application) is required in the context of a customer's Microsoft Azure subscription whose resources are to be managed from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
            <p>The customer needs to take the following steps: </p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Log in to Microsoft Azure as a user with administrative permissions for the subscription.</li>
                <li>In the <b>Azure Active Directory</b> under <b>App registrations</b>, create a new registration with a name of your choice. <p>Example: <codeph><ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />ServicePrincipal</codeph></p><p>Select supported account types as desired. A redirect URI is not required.</p>
                </li>
                <li>Select the new application and copy its <b>(client) ID</b> and the <b>directory (tenant) ID</b> for later use in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. <p>Example: </p><ul>
                        <li>Application (client) ID: <codeph>ef29bb22-369c-424d-9e72-6800ad24239e</codeph></li>
                        <li>Directory (tenant) ID: <codeph>02d72930-3874-4119-80d4-54a4d7f31dfc</codeph></li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li>Under <b>Certificates and secrets</b>, add a <b>new client secret</b> for the application. Copy the new secret for later use in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. Be aware that the client secret is no longer accessible in Microsoft Azure once you close the page.</li>
                <li>Select the Microsoft Azure subscription for which you created the application. From its properties, copy the <b>subscription ID</b> for later use in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />.<p>Example: </p><p>Subscription ID: <codeph>98e0f7ef-bb83-408d-9675-0e45f65a54f7</codeph></p></li>
                <li>Under <b>Access control (IAM)</b> for the subscription, choose <b>Add role assignment</b> and add the <b>Contributor</b> role to the application (service principal) you created. </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Preparations in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
            <p>In <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, custom attributes need to be created for specifying the authentication information required to connect to Microsoft Azure. The customer administrators later need to provide their values for these custom attributes in their organization's profile on the marketplace. </p>
            <p>Proceed as follows:</p>
            <ol compact="no">
                <li>Log in to the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal with your service manager account.</li>
                <li>Use <b>Manage custom attributes</b> in the <b>Account</b> menu to create custom attributes for customers with the following <b>attribute IDs</b>:<ul>
                        <li><codeph>AzureSubscriptionId</codeph> - the ID of the customer's Microsoft Azure subscription</li>
                        <li><codeph>AzureTenantId</codeph> - the customer's directory (tenant) ID in Microsoft Azure</li>
                        <li><codeph>AzureApplicationId</codeph> - the ID of the application (service principal) created for <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> in Microsoft Azure</li>
                        <li><codeph>AzureSecret</codeph> - the client secret created for the application in Microsoft Azure</li>
                    </ul><p>For each of the attributes, specify a name of your choice as well as <codeph>ess.shell</codeph> as the <b>controller ID</b>.</p></li>
                <li>Make sure that your customers specify the appropriate values for the custom attributes in their organization's profile on the marketplace.</li>
            </ol>
            <p>The custom attributes are referenced by their ID in the PowerShell scripts to be executed in Microsoft Azure through the Shell controller. Examples are available on GitHub under <xref
                    href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app-shell/tree/master/src/main/resources/sample_scripts/powershell"
                    scope="external"
                    >https://github.com/servicecatalog/oscm-app-shell/tree/master/src/main/resources/sample_scripts/powershell</xref>.</p>
            <p>In addition to the custom attributes, the following parameters should be defined in the technical services created for the Shell integration to work with Microsoft Azure:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>AzureAutomationAccountName</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>AzureResourceGroupName</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>AzureRunbookName</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p>These parameters can be used in the scripts for working with Azure Automation resources. For details, refer to <xref
                    href="../../Shared/tasks/t_CreateTechService.xml"/> and <xref
                    href="../Appendix/r_ServiceParameters.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
