<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">

<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7">
    <title>Managing Customers</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> offers various features for managing the interaction of seller organizations with their customers. Customer management involves:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Registering customers with <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />.</li>
                <li>Defining custom attributes.</li>
                <li>Viewing the details of subscriptions. </li>
                <li>Terminating subscriptions.</li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Registering Customers</title>
            <p>Sellers <ph id="can_register_customers_with_concept_conbody_section_2_p">can register customers with <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> so that they do not need to do this themselves. Registering a customer creates a new customer organization as well as an initial administrator account. This administrator is automatically sent an email with all the information required to access the given marketplace and subscribe to services.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Custom Attributes</title>
            <p>Suppliers can define custom attributes. They are a means to store specific data on customers or subscriptions, such as data needed for controlling the cost and activity accounting. For example, a supplier may want to define a unique identifier for each customer or specify the profit center to which a particular customer's revenue is to be accounted. Since there is no standard for such data, the supplier can define his own custom attributes for storing it. </p>
            <p id="custom_attr"
                >Custom attributes can be defined for customers and for subscriptions. For subscription attributes, suppliers can decide whether they themselves want to specify the value, or whether the customer must enter a value when he subscribes to a corresponding service. For customer attributes, suppliers can decide whether they themselves want to specify the value, or whether the customer administrator must enter a value by editing the customer organization's profile on a marketplace. </p>
            <p>The custom attributes are included in the billing data that is generated by <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> every month. The information can then be used, for example, as a reference for an external accounting, billing, or CRM system. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Handling Subscriptions</title>
            <p>Sellers can view the details of each subscription to the services they offer. The entire subscription information is accessible, for example, the activation date and the number of users assigned to the subscription. Suppliers can also view the details of subscriptions to services offered by their authorized brokers.</p>
            <p>Suppliers and resellers can explicitly terminate subscriptions. This may be required, for example, if a customer does not comply with the license agreement or does not pay for the subscription. A subscription to a service offered by a broker can be terminated by the respective supplier.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Providing Customer Support</title>
            <p>As customers work with services, they may encounter problems or have questions or enhancement requests. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> provides the means by which customers can report issues directly to the relevant supplier or reseller by email. Suppliers and resellers can define a dedicated support email address to which the issues are sent. Issues related to services offered by brokers can directly be reported to the suppliers of the services.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
