<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Managing Billing and Payment</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>As users of customers work with services, <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> automatically calculates the fees based on the related price models. It aggregates all the events, users, and configuration data associated with a subscription and rates them according to the applicable price model. At regular intervals <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> generates billing data that can be used for creating invoices. </p>
            <p>Suppliers and resellers are responsible for preparing the billing and payment for their customers, creating invoices, and collecting payments. This includes the following tasks: </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Specify the types of payment to be offered to customers.</li>
                <li>Define the VAT rates to be used for calculating the customer charges.</li>
                <li>Define the period for which billing data is generated.</li>
                <li>Export the generated billing data to make it available to external accounting systems.</li>
                <!--li>Integrate and use the facilities of a commercial payment service provider (PSP).</li-->
            </ul>
            <p>Brokers are not involved in these tasks, because subscriptions to services they offer are contracts between the customers and the suppliers of the services. The suppliers are responsible for preparing the billing and payment as well as collecting the payments from the brokers' customers. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Managing Payment Types</title>
            <p>Suppliers and resellers are responsible for defining how customers may pay for their subscriptions, for example, on receipt of invoice, with credit card, or by direct debit.</p>
            <p>The payment types available to suppliers and resellers must be set up by the operator. Each supplier and reseller can then choose the payment types he wants to offer to his customers. A supplier can also select the payment types he wants to offer to the customers of his authorized brokers. Different payment types can be chosen for individual customers and individual services the customers have subscribed to.</p>
            <p>In specific scenarios, the operator may deactivate any possibilities for customers to select payment types and specify billing addresses. If this is the case, the definition of payment types by suppliers and resellers is not possible.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Managing VAT Rates</title>
            <p>In case suppliers want to invoice usage charges for subscriptions to their services as gross prices, they can enable VAT rate support for their organization. </p>
            <p>Suppliers can specify a basic VAT rate, that applies by default to all prices for their own customers and the customers of their authorized brokers. In addition, country-specific or even customer-specific VAT rates can be defined.</p>
            <p>Customers of resellers are not affected by the VAT rates defined by suppliers. Any cost calculation for resellers' customers results in net prices.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Billing Periods</title>
            <p
                conref="../../help/tasks/user_manageBilling.xml#task634/A_billing_period_is_the_time_task_taskbody_context_p_2"/>
            <p>By default, the start day of a billing period is the 1st day of a month. However, this is not always suitable in real business. For this reason, each supplier and reseller can define his desired start day for billing periods. This setting applies to new customer subscriptions to services provided by the supplier or reseller. Existing subscriptions keep their billing period as defined when the customer subscribed to the service.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Exporting Billing Data</title>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> allows suppliers and resellers to export the billing data for one or several customers for a specific time frame. The exported data can, for example, be forwarded to an accounting system which processes the data and generates the corresponding invoices. In this way, suppliers and resellers can use billing and payment processes that have been established in their organization.</p>
        </section>
        <!--section>
            <title>Integrating PSP Support</title>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> supports suppliers and resellers in using the facilities of a commercial payment service provider (PSP) for the creation of invoices and payment collection. The billing data generated in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> can be transferred to the PSP. The PSP can then create and deliver customer invoices, thus initiating the payment request.</p>
            <p>For using the services of a PSP, the supplier or reseller organization needs to have a valid contractual relationship with the PSP. Using the public Web services and APIs of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, the services of any PSP can be integrated with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section-->
    </conbody>
</concept>
