<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Defining Price Models</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails.xml#reference832/A_price_model_specifies_wheth_reference_refbody_section_p"
                /></p>
            <ul>
                <li>Using the subscription as such.</li>
                <li>Each user assigned to the subscription.</li>
                <li>Individual events. These include, for example, login and logout by users to the underlying application, the completion of specific transactions, or the creation or deletion of specific data.</li>
                <li>Parameters and their options.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../SupplierGuide/PriceModels/c_PMIntro.xml#concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7/It_depends_on_the_implementat_concept_conbody_section_p_2"
                />
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Price Model Scope</title>
            <p>Price models can have different scopes: </p>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../SupplierGuide/PriceModels/c_PMTypes.xml#concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7/Service_price_models_concept_conbody_section_p_1"
                />
            </p>
            <p>In addition to service price models, <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> allows for the definition of <b>customer price models</b>. A customer price model can be used, for example, to offer special discounts to a long-time customer, or to make a new service available to a pilot customer at no charge. <ph
                    conref="../../SupplierGuide/PriceModels/c_PMTypes.xml#concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7/A_customer_price_model_is_spe_concept_conbody_section_p_3"
                />
            </p>
            <p>To support even greater flexibility, suppliers can define <b>subscription price models</b> in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. A subscription price model is specific to one subscription of an individual customer. It is not available for any other subscriptions of the same or a different customer. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Price Model Elements</title>
            <p>Each price model defined in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> - independent of its scope - consists of different elements that determine how the charges for a service are calculated. The following elements can be defined:</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>One-time fee</li>
                    <li>Recurring charge per subscription</li>
                    <li>Recurring charge for users</li>
                    <li>Prices for parameters and options</li>
                    <li>Prices for events</li>
                    <li>Role-based prices</li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p>Stepped prices are supported which allow the definition of ranges for which different price model elements apply. In addition, a free trial period can be defined and discounts can be granted to individual customers.</p>
            <p id="The_actual_charges_for_a_serv_reference_refbody_section_3"
                >The actual charges for a service depend on the combination of the price model elements. The charges are either calculated pro rata (based on milliseconds) or per time unit (month, week, day, or hour). With pro rata calculation, customers are charged exactly for the time a service was used. With per time unit calculation, customers are charged for complete time units, for example, one week, even if the service was not used for the whole week.</p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
