<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Access Types</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> offers various ways of integrating and accessing your application. The interaction takes place between the following components:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>The client which in fact is the user who accesses a service using a Web browser or a Web service.</li>
                <li><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</li>
                <li>The application which is accessed by the user.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>There are some criteria to be considered before you decide to use a specific access type. The following decision diagram helps you in deciding which access type to use according to your environment and requirements:</p>
            <p product="oscm_ee">
                <fig>
                    <image href="../_images/AccessDecision_EE.png" height="254" width="261"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p product="oscm_ce">
                <fig>
                    <image href="../_images/AccessDecision_CE.png" height="254" width="261"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p>The decision you make is reversible. If the basic requirements of your system are changing, you can, of course, also change the access type.</p>
            <p>The access type determines </p>
            <ul>
                <li>whether your application uses <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> for user authentication and <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> forwards login information to your application (<b>application login</b>).</li>
                <li>whether your application needs to implement a <b>provisioning service</b>.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>The following table provides an overview of the different access types and the available combinations:</p>
            <fig>
                <image align="center" href="../../Shared/_images/MatrixAccessTypes.png" height="159" width="277"
                    placement="break"/>
            </fig>
            <p>* <i>With user access, the application login can be controlled completely by the application.</i></p>
            <!-- note>
                <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> offers the following additional access types: platform access and proxy access. The usage of these access types is discouraged since time or data-sensitive applications put a considerable load on <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and cause a significant resource consumption. If you want to use platform or proxy access nevertheless, contact your platform operator.</p>
            </note-->
            <p>You define the desired access type when preparing a technical service definition for your application. If you opt for access through <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> (login access), you need to adapt the login/logout implementation in your application. Depending on the access type you choose, you must implement the methods defined by the provisioning service. </p>
            <p>The following sections provide detailed information on the different access types. The sequence diagrams illustrate the interaction between the involved components. Arrows with solid lines represent messages requiring a response, arrows with dotted lines represent the response messages. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
