<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_7867C3B8F2DB44B9A0965F23E1AAC43C" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Implementing Technical Service Operations</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p
                conref="../../TechProvGuide/Implement/t_ImplementOperations.xml#task_7867C3B8F2DB44B9A0965F23E1AAC43C/You_may_wish_that_your_techni_task_taskbody_context_p_1"/>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../TechProvGuide/Implement/t_ImplementOperations.xml#task_7867C3B8F2DB44B9A0965F23E1AAC43C/The_information_about_the_ope_task_taskbody_context_p_2_ph"
                    />For details, refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i>.</p>
            <p>To integrate a technical service operation: </p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Implement the <codeph>executeServiceOperation()</codeph> and the <codeph>getParameterValues()</codeph> methods in a Web service definition using the <codeph>OperationService</codeph> interface of the operation API, which is part of the <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> integration package.</cmd>
                <info>The following information is provided as parameter settings for the <codeph>executeServiceOperation()</codeph> method: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>The user identifier. This ID is unique in the instance context and allows the technical service to perform built-in security checks. </li>
                            <li>The instance identifier. This ID uniquely identifies the application instance that is to be affected by the operation. </li>
                            <li>For asynchronous operations: The transaction identifier. This ID uniquely identifies the transaction to be executed. </li>
                            <li>The operation identifier. This ID uniquely identifies the operation to be executed as defined in the technical service definition. For details, refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i>. </li>
                            <li>Parameters. This is the list of parameters and their values as retrieved with the <codeph>getParameterValues()</codeph> method or - depending on the type of parameter - their specified values. The parameters must also be defined in the technical service definition. For details, refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i>.</li>
                        </ul>
                    </p><p>You need to provide the operation in a WSDL file that is accessible by a URL. </p></info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Edit the technical service definition XML file and include the operation and its parameters. </cmd>
                <info>For details, refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i>. </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <example>When implementing service operations, be aware of the following:<p>
                <ul>
                    <li>The return type is not configurable; currently it can only be of type <codeph>OperationResult</codeph>.</li>
                    <li><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> does not provide access control. Every user who can use the subscription can also execute the operations. </li>
                    <li>The operations can be executed in synchronous or asynchronous mode. The transaction mode is defined in the <codeph>OperationResult</codeph> class of the <codeph>OperationService</codeph> interface.</li>
                    <li>For allowing users to view the status of asynchronous service operations, implement the <codeph>updateAsyncOperationProgress()</codeph> method using the <codeph>SubscriptionService</codeph> interface of the <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> public Web service API. </li>
                </ul>
            </p></example>
    </taskbody>
</task>
