<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Managing Subscriptions</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> offers various means for customers to manage their existing subscriptions. Administrators of customer organizations can: </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Browse the subscriptions and search for specific ones using a full-text search feature.</li>
                <li>Change the user assignments for a subscription. If a subscription assignment is changed, the affected user is sent an email with the appropriate information.</li>
                <li>Upgrade or downgrade a subscription to a different usage or price model as offered by the supplier. </li>
                <li>Modify a subscription. This includes renaming the subscription, assigning and deassigning subscriptions to/from organizational units, or choosing different options that are available for the underlying service.</li>
                <li>Report issues. Questions, requests, or problems arising from the usage of a service can be reported directly to the supplier or reseller who offers the service. If the service is offered by a broker, the issues can be reported directly to the supplier of the service.</li>
                <li>Terminate a subscription. If a subscription is terminated, <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> deactivates the related data but keeps it. The application underlying to the subscription is triggered to deprovision all the items related to the subscription. The assigned users are sent an email informing them about the termination.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>OU administrators can carry out these tasks for the subscriptions assigned to their organizational units. Subscription managers and OU administrators can also execute these tasks for their own subscriptions. A subscription manager or OU administrator is assigned the ownership for a subscription either implicitly by creating it or explicitly by an administrator or OU administrator.  </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
