<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Using Services</title>
            <conbody>
                        <p>After a customer has subscribed to a service, his registered users who are assigned to the subscription can work with the underlying application. </p>
                        <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> supports two basic ways for a user to access an application:</p>
                        <ul>
                                    <li>The user logs in to <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> and works with the application.</li>
                                    <li>The user logs in directly to the application without involving <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. </li>
                        </ul>
                        <p>The type of access available for each application depends on the application itself and on how it has been integrated with <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    />. </p>
                        <section>
                                    <title>Accessing Applications Through <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /></title>
                                    <p>If a user accesses an application through <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            />, he logs in to <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> on a Web page whose URL he has received from <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. Depending on this URL: </p>
                                    <ul>
                                                <li>The user is forwarded immediately to the remote interface of the application and can start his work, or </li>
                                                <li>The user is directed to a marketplace that presents the services the user is entitled to use. The user just selects the desired service. This forwards him to the remote interface of the underlying application where he can start his work.</li>
                                    </ul>
                                    <p>An additional login to the application is not required. In the application, the user works in the context and on the data which are maintained for the applicable service subscription. </p>
                                    <p>When the user has completed his work, the application usually offers a way to log out, including a route back to the marketplace if he has started his work from there. </p>
                        </section>
                        <section>
                                    <title>Accessing Applications Outside of <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /></title>
                                    <p>Users can work directly with applications underlying to <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> services, without a previous login to <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                />. </p>
                                    <p>In this case, the application itself provides the user with the appropriate information and a URL for logging in and starting his work. </p>
                                    <p>In the application, the user works in the context and on the data which are maintained for the applicable service subscription. </p>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
