<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>The Reseller's Tasks in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>As a reseller, you offer the services defined by one or more suppliers on marketplaces to which you have been granted access. In order to offer a service, you need an explicit permission by the supplier. While you cannot change the definition and price model of a service, you can apply your own terms and conditions, for example, as to licenses. </p>
            <p>
                <fig>
                    <image href="../../Shared/_images/ScenarioReseller.png" alt="ScenarioReseller.png" width="400"
                        height="74" align="center"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p>A subscription to a service establishes a contract between the customer and your reseller organization. This contract is based on the price model defined by the supplier and on the terms and conditions defined by you.</p>
            <p>For subscribing to services you offer, customers need to register with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, or you can register them. The customers can register or import any number of users who work with the services. </p>
            <p>Apart from offering services to customers, your role as a reseller involves the following tasks:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Managing your customers. This includes, for example, explicitly terminating a customer's subscription.</li>
                <li>Preparing billing and payment for the customers. As users work with a service, the usage charges are calculated based on the fees defined in the related price model. This billing data can be used for generating invoices. You are responsible for the processing of the billing data and for the payment collection. <!--p><ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> enables you to integrate and use the facilities of a commercial payment service provider (PSP) for this purpose.</p--></li>
                <li>Handling revenue shares. As a reseller, you are usually not entitled to keep the entire revenue collected from your customers, but only a certain share thereof. This revenue share is defined by the operator. It may be different for each marketplace where you offer services or even for individual services. Depending on your contracts with the operator, marketplace owner, and suppliers, you have to pay them their respective shares or they will collect their shares from you. You can at any time retrieve billing data and information on the actual revenues depending on the usage of the services. </li>
            </ul>
            <p>If required, you can also act as a customer in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. As a reseller, you are automatically privileged to subscribe to services and work with the services you have subscribed to. </p>
            <p>If you need to perform marketplace owner tasks, your organization must be assigned the corresponding role by the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> operator. Note that a reseller organization cannot additionally be assigned the technology provider, supplier, or broker role.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
