<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="billing_adapter"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Billing Adapters</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>A billing adapter is needed to:</p>
                        <ul>
                                <li>Establish a connection between <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> and an external billing system. Each billing system requires a separate adapter.</li>
                                <li>Retrieve price models from the external billing system and return them to <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> when <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> sends a corresponding import request triggered by a supplier. In addition, a billing adapter can be extended to upload external price models for subscriptions to <ph
                                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> without a previous request.</li>
                        </ul>
            <p>A billing adapter must be implemented as an EJB (Enterprise Java Bean) with a remote interface. <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> usually acts as a remote client. It obtains a reference to the remote interface by means of JNDI (Java Naming and Directory Interface) lookup. For this to be possible, the billing adapter needs to be registered and configured in <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> by the operator. </p>
                        <p>The providers of the billing adapter are responsible for its deployment on an application server and for ensuring the communication with <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> on the one side and the billing system on the other. This may, for example, involve the appropriate configuration of firewalls and access paths.</p>
                        <p>A billing adapter must implement the interfaces and methods of the billing plug-in API (<codeph>org.oscm.billing.external</codeph> package). This API and its documentation are included in the <ph
                                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        /> integration package, <codeph>oscm-integration-pack.zip</codeph>. </p>
                        <p>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> integration package also contains a sample billing adapter. This adapter works with a simple file-based billing system which is included in the sample. For details of how to deploy and use the sample billing system and adapter, refer to the documentation that comes with them.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
