<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="push_subsription_pm"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Uploading Subscription Price Models</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>A billing adapter can be extended to upload external price models for subscriptions to <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> without a previous request from <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. This is accomplished by making the billing adapter work as a JMS client and pushing JMS messages with subscription price models into the remote queue of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </p>
            <p>This upload mechanism may be useful, for example, if the price model in the external billing system changes during the life time of a subscription. The billing adapter could check for such changes at regular intervals or the billing system could notify the adapter accordingly. The environment involving <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, the billing adapter, and the external billing system must be set up and configured in a way to allow for the passing of the required notifications and JMS messages.</p>
            <p>To make a billing adapter work as a JMS client and push JMS messages with price models to the remote queue of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, perform the following steps:</p>
            <ol>
                <li>Create the initial context for the remote JMS server.<codeblock>Properties jndiProperties = new Properties();
InitialContext context = new InitialContext(jndiProperties);</codeblock><p>The <codeph>jndiProperties</codeph> must contain the provider URL of <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />: </p><p><codeph>mq://&lt;host>:8176</codeph>
                    </p><p><codeph>mq</codeph> is the Message Queue protocol of the application server Message Queue software (JMS provider for the application server).</p><p><codeph>&lt;host></codeph> is the host where <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> is deployed.</p></li>
                <li>Retrieve the queue connection factory through JNDI lookup and create a connection.<codeblock>Object lookup = context.lookup("jms/bss/taskQueueFactory"); 
ConnectionFactory conFactory =  ConnectionFactory.class.cast(lookup);
Connection connection = conFactory.createConnection();</codeblock></li>
                <li>Retrieve the queue in the remote JMS provider through JNDI lookup.<codeblock>Queue queue = (Queue)cntxt.lookup("jms/bss/taskQueue");</codeblock></li>
                <li>Initialize the communication session.<codeblock>Session session = connection.createSession(false, Session.AUTO_ACKNOWLEDGE);</codeblock></li>
                <li>Create and send the message with the subscription price model.<codeblock>MessageProducer producer = session.createProducer(queue);
            ObjectMessage msg = session.createObjectMessage();
            msg.setObject(priceModel);
            producer.send(msg);</codeblock><p>The price model is a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> object of the billing plug-in API. The context sent in the price model must contain values for:  <ul>
                            <li><codeph>SUBSCRIPTION_ID</codeph></li>
                            <li><codeph>TENANT_ID</codeph></li>
                        </ul></p></li>
            </ol>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
