<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Handling Problems in the Provisioning Process</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                            <p>If there are problems in the communication between the participating systems, the corresponding subscription in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> remains pending. The Shell service controller informs the technology managers of its responsible technology provider organization by email of any incomplete operation in the Shell script execution. </p>
                                    <p>You can then take the appropriate actions to solve the problem. For example, you could remove an incomplete virtual machine, or you could restore a missing connection.</p>
                                    <p>After solving the problem, the Shell integration components and <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> need to be synchronized accordingly. You do this by triggering a corresponding action in the APP component. Proceed as follows:</p>
                                    <ol>
                                                <li>Work as a technology manager of the technology provider organization responsible for the Shell service controller. </li>
                <li>Invoke the instance status interface of APP for the service controller by opening its URL in a Web browser. <p>The access URL has the following format: </p><p><codeph>https://&lt;host_fqdn>:8881/oscm-app/controller/?controllerid=ess.shell</codeph></p><p><codeph>&lt;host_fqdn></codeph> is the fully qualified name or IP address of the host used to access <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, <codeph>8881</codeph> is the port of APP. <codeph>oscm-app/controller/?controllerid=ess.shell</codeph> is the default context root of the service controller and cannot be changed. </p><p>The Web page shows all subscriptions for the application, including detailed information such as the customer organization, the ID of the related application instance, and the provisioning status. </p></li>
                                        <li>Find the subscription for which you solved the problem in the most recent operation. </li>
                                                <li>In the <b>Action</b> column, select the action for the Shell integration components to execute next. Possible actions are the following:<ul>
                        <li><codeph>RESUME</codeph> - to resume the processing of a provisioning operation in APP which was suspended.</li>
                        <li><codeph>SUSPEND</codeph> - to suspend the processing of a provisioning operation in APP, for example, when a Shell script does not respond. </li>
                        <li><codeph>UNLOCK</codeph> - to remove the lock for an instance in APP.</li>
                        <li><codeph>DELETE</codeph> - to terminate the subscription in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> and remove the instance in APP, but keep a virtual system for later use. The service manager role is required for this action.</li>
                        <li><codeph>DEPROVISION</codeph> - to terminate the subscription in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, remove the instance in APP, and delete any virtual system. The service manager role is required for this action.</li>
                        <li><codeph>ABORT_PENDING</codeph> - to abort a pending operation in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> is notified to roll back the changes made for the subscription and return it to its previous state. </li>
                        <li><codeph>COMPLETE_PENDING</codeph> - to complete a pending operation in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> is notified to complete the changes for the subscription and set the subscription status to <b>ready</b> (or <b>suspended</b> if it was suspended before). This is possible only if the operations of the service controller are already completed.</li>
                    </ul></li>
                                                <li>Click <b>Execute</b> to invoke the selected action. </li>
                                    </ol>
            <p>The instance status interface provides the following additional functionality that is useful for problem-solving purposes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You can display service instance details for each subscription by clicking the corresponding entry in the table. This displays all subscription-related information that is stored in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database.</li>
                <!--li>The <b>Run with timer</b> column indicates whether the timer for the interval at which APP polls the status of instances is running. You can reset the timer, if required.<ph audience="doc"> For details on the timer setting, refer to <xref
                            href="../../Shared/Installation/r_ConfigSettings.xml"/></ph>.</li-->
            </ul>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
