<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Registering Customers</title>
    <conbody>
        <section id="You_can_register_your_custome_concept_conbody_section_1">
            <p>You can register customers with <ph conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> so that they do not need to do this themselves. The new customer automatically receives the login information that enables him to access the given marketplace and subscribe to services.</p>
            <p>Registering a customer includes entering the following user data for the first administrator of the new customer organization:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Title</b>, <b>first name</b>, and <b>last name</b> of the administrator.</li>
                <li><b>Email address</b> that is used for notifying the customer about the registration.</li>
                <li><b>User ID</b> to be used for the administrator.</li>
                <li><b>Language</b> in which the user interface, available documentation, and emails are presented to the administrator.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Registering a customer includes entering the data for the new organization:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Name</b>, <b>address</b>, and <b>phone number</b>.</li>
                <li><b>Email address</b>.</li>
                <li><b>Website</b>.</li>
                <li><b>Country</b> where the customer organization is located. </li>
                <li><b>Description</b> that provides, for example, information from the company's profile.</li>
                <li><b>Marketplace</b> to which the customer is directed.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>To register a customer, use the <uicontrol>Register customer</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> administration portal. </p>
            <p>Once you have registered a customer, the organization data can only be edited by the customer's administrators. If you want to update the organization data, you must be registered as an administrator of your customer. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="As_a_broker_you_can_only_vie_concept_conbody_section_2">
            <p>As a broker, you can view the organization data that is defined for your customers. To view the data, use the <uicontrol>View customer</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> administration portal. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="As_a_reseller_you_can_only_v_concept_conbody_section_3">
            <p>As a reseller, you can view the organization data that is defined for your customers. To view the data, use the <uicontrol>View customer</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> administration portal. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="As_a_supplier_you_can_only_v_concept_conbody_section_4">
            <p>As a supplier, you can view the organization data that is defined for your customers. If you have granted brokers the permission to offer your services, you can also view the organization data that is defined for your brokers' customers. To view the data, use the <uicontrol>View customer</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                    conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> administration portal. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
