<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Updating Service Controller Settings in the Database</title>
            <conbody>
        <section>
                        <p id="During_deployment_several_co_concept_conbody_section_p_1">During the deployment of <ph
                                        conref="../Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                        />, several configuration settings are written to the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. This configuration is used for the initial setup of the <ph
                                        audience="aws">AWS</ph><ph audience="azure">Azure</ph><ph audience="os"
                                        >OpenStack</ph><ph audience="shell"
                                        >Shell</ph> service controller and its registration with APP. The platform operator is responsible for taking care that the initial settings are correct. Refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i> for details on the initial configuration in the <codeph>var.env</codeph> configuration file.</p>
                        <p id="cfg"
                                        >A technology provider can define service parameters in the technical service definition. If such a parameter has the same ID as a controller configuration setting stored in the APP database, it overrules the configuration setting in the database when the marketable service based on such a technical service is subscribed to. By default the values in the controller configuration settings are used. Refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i> for details on defining technical services. </p>
                        <p id="cfg2"
                                >In addition, a supplier can define custom attributes for subscriptions and for customers. If such an attribute has the same ID as a controller configuration setting stored in the APP database as well as a corresponding technical service parameter, it overrules the technical service parameter as well as the configuration setting in the database when the marketable service based on such a technical service is subscribed to.</p>
                        <p id="cfg3">The controller configuration settings are evaluated as follows: </p>
                        <p id="cfg4">
                                <ol>
                                        <li>Configuration setting as stored in the APP database. </li>
                                        <li>Technical service parameter. If defined, it overrules 1. </li>
                                        <li>Custom attribute for customer. If defined, it overrules 1. and 2.</li>
                                        <li>Custom attribute for subscription. If defined, it overrules 1. and 2. and 3. </li>
                                </ol>
                        </p>
                        <p id="To_update_the_controller_sett_concept_conbody_section_p_6"
                                        ><b>To update the controller configuration settings in the APP database:</b></p>
                </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
