<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Adding a Node to a Cluster</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>### DRAFT version ### - to be completed - take into account Bug 9591:</p>
            <p>Build: BES-MAIN-DAILY-3056 (2012/08/28) Version: BES 15.2 sprint_D Test category: installation (cluster model) OS:Winodws server 2008 We have already finished installation of node 1 in BES cluster environment followed the installation manual. But we encountered some problems when we tried to add the node 2 to BES cluster. It spend a lot of time to solve these problems due to there was no any information concerning setting up node 2 in installation manual. Finally, through cooperating with EST, these problems were solved and node 2 worked successfully. So, in order to users can smoothly set up the node 2 according to the installation manual, base on our practice, we suggest the following three key points should be added to installation manual: 1. The directory "masterSourceBase" on node 1 must be shared so that it could be accessed by all nodes. For example, we shared the directory as "\\BESPTSV1WIN\masterSourceBase" on windows environment, so we can set the jvm option "-Dhibernate.search.default.sourceBase" in config file "bescluster-config" as follows: -Dhibernate.search.default.sourceBase=\\\\BESPTSV1WIN\\masterSourceBase Therefore, every node (include node 1) of BES cluster could access "masterSourceBase" through visiting sharing "\\BESPTSV1WIN\masterSourceBase" 2. Add the following line to file "glassfish\nodeagents\na(x)\gf(x)\imq\instances\besclustergf(x)\etc\passwd.txt" after the node x is deployed: jmsuser:-84a8500672a117536a62cfe428e1d6d:user:1 3. Copy file "cluster.properties" form node 1 to node x and Add the following two lines to file "glassfish\nodeagents\na(x)\gf(x)\imq\instances\besclustergf(x)\props\config.properties" after the node x is deployed: imq.brokerid=brokerid_gf(x) imq.cluster.url=file\:/C\:/bes_install_sv/glassfish/domains/domain1/config/cluster.properties ------- Additional Comment #1 From mike jaeger 2012-10-08 14:50 ------- i think the proceeding heavily depends on whether cluster environments will be supported with version 15.2 or not. Bruno, can you please add a comment on that? ------- Additional Comment #2 From Christoph Held 2012-10-19 17:30 ------- Cluster support is not planned for 15.2 ------- Additional Comment #3 From Bogdan Barzu 2012-10-19 18:05 ------- As agreed with Bruno: the cluster support is out of the 15.2 documentation. If the cluster support will be available in the next release, then the documentations team should merge the information described in this bug into the cluster documentation, if suitable. But there is no point to keep this bug open any longer. Gerti: please attach the information in this bug to the cluster documentation (as review comments or any form you find suitable), so it does not get lost. And then close this bug by setting the resolution to LATER.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Preconditions and Preparations</title>
            <ol>
                <li>
                    <p>A cluster with one node/server instance is already installed. </p>
                    <p>All components are installed on one host (host1): host1: DAS, MasterIndexer, DB, node-agent1 (na1), node1/instance1 (gf1)</p>
                </li>
                <li>Check <codeph>/etc/hosts</codeph> on host1 and host2 and make sure that the host name is not mapped to a <codeph>localhost</codeph> address! <p>Use the real IP address: </p><p><b>##wrong##</b>
                        <codeph>127.0.0.2 hostname.dyn.lan.company.de hostname </codeph></p><p><b>##correct##</b><codeph>10.140.16.44 hostname.dyn.lan.company.de hostname</codeph></p></li>
                <li> Edit <codeph>pg_hba.conf</codeph> to enable the access to the database from all hosts with cluster nodes: <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li>Add IP address of host1.</li>
                            <li>Add IP address of host2.</li>
                            <li>Restart the PostgreSQL server. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p></li>
                <li>Edit <codeph>postgres.conf</codeph> to increase the number of maximum connections for 30 connections per additional node. <p>
                        <ul>
                            <li><codeblock>max_connections=240</codeblock> #210+30.</li>
                            <li>Restart the PostgreSQL server. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p></li>
                <li>If not available, create a directory on a file share (accessible by all cluster nodes) as source base of the master indexer. For example: <p><codeph> /mnt/user/test/cluster/masterSourceBase </codeph></p><p>On Windows create and share a folder. Map it as network drive on node machines. </p></li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Configuration and Setup for node2 on host2</title>
            <p>The target is to have a second cluster element on a separate host (host2) including a second node agent (na2) and a second server instance (gf2).</p>
            <p>Proceed as follows: </p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Install and setup Glassfish on host2 as described in the <i>Installation Guide</i>. </li>
                    <li>Create a node agent and a server instance on host2. For example:<p>
                            <codeblock>asadmin create-node-agent --host host1 --port 8148 na2
asadmin create-instance --host host1 --port 8148 --nodeagent na2 --cluster bescluster gf2 
</codeblock>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>Configure node2 on host2: <p>
                            <ol>
                                <li>Copy the <codeph>jmsuser</codeph> entry for the IMQ broker from node1 to node2</li>
                                <li> Copy the<codeph> jdbc jar &lt;glassfish_home>/imq/lib/ext/postgresql-8.4-701.jdbc3.jar</codeph> from host1 to the same location on host2</li>
                                <li>Start the node agent to create the necessary directories and files. The node agent will implicitly start the server instance.<p>
                                        <codeblock>asadmin start-node-agent na2</codeblock>
                                    </p></li>
                                <li> Stop the server instance and the node agent: <p>
                                        <codeblock>asadmin stop-instance --host host1 --port 8148 gf2 
asadmin stop-node-agent na2</codeblock>
                                    </p></li>
                                <li>Copy the <codeph>jmsuser</codeph> entry (e.g. <codeph>jmsuser:-84a8500672a117536a62cfe428e1d6d:user:1</codeph>) from node1 file:<p><codeph>&lt;glassfish_home>/nodeagents/na1/gf1/imq/instances/besclustergf1/etc/passwd</codeph></p><p>and paste the <codeph>jmsuser</codeph> entry to the same file on node2: file: </p><p><codeph>&lt;glassfish_home>/nodeagents/na2/gf2/imq/instances/besclustergf2/etc/passwd</codeph></p></li>
                                <li>Add broker ID and cluster URL to the broker configuration properties:<p>Edit <codeph>&lt;glassfish_home>/nodeagents/na2/gf2/imq/instances/besclustergf2/props/config.properties</codeph>.</p><p>Add the following properties: </p><p>
                                        <codeblock>imq.brokerid=brokerid_gf2 
imq.instanceconfig.version=300 
imq.cluster.url=file\:&lt;glassfish_home>/nodeagents/na2/gf2/config/cluster.properties </codeblock>
                                    </p><p>On Windows the last property will be:</p><p><codeph>imq.cluster.url=file\:/&lt;glassfish_home>/nodeagents/na2/gf2/config/cluster.properties </codeph></p><p>
                                        <note>The cluster URL points to the <codeph>cluster.properties</codeph> file. Any change of the <codeph>cluster.properties</codeph> file requires a restart of all node agents with synchronization of the instances.</note>
                                    </p></li>
                                <li>Execute the following command: <p>
                                        <codeblock>asadmin start-node-agent --syncinstances=true na2 </codeblock>
                                    </p><p>All Glassfish properties (cluster- or instance-specific, e.g. ports) can be configured via the Glassfish administration console on host1). </p></li>
                            </ol>
                        </p></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
