<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_1BCF5C425D7D4627AB1C66A085CF6E11" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Managing LDAP Settings</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <note>This section is relevant only if OSCM is installed in INTERNAL authentication mode. Refer to <xref
                    href="../Introduction/c_Authentication.xml"/> for details on authentication modes.</note>
            <p>User IDs and passwords of an organization can be created and maintained in the platform or in an existing LDAP system of an organization.</p>
            <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/UserMgmt2"> </p>
            <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/UserMgmt3"> </p>
            <p>Whether an organization uses an LDAP system for user management is determined when the organization is created in the platform. An organization can be created in several ways: </p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>A customer registers himself. In this way, an organization with the customer role is created. Users are always managed in the platform, and an LDAP system cannot be used.</li>
                    <li>A seller (supplier, reseller, or broker) registers a customer. In this way, an organization with the customer role is created. The seller can specify whether user management in an external LDAP system is to be used. </li>
                    <li>You as the platform operator create an organization of any role. For any organization, you can specify whether user management in an external LDAP system is to be used.<ph
                            audience="doc"> For details, refer to <xref href="../Organizations/c_OrgCreateOrg.xml"
                            />.</ph></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/UserMgmt4"> </p>
            <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/UserMgmt5"> </p>
            <p>As an operator, you can define default LDAP configuration settings for the entire platform. These settings apply as long as no organization-specific LDAP settings are specified. You can also check an organization's connection to its LDAP system. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Defining Default LDAP Settings</title>
            <p>Defining default LDAP settings for the entire platform is useful if settings are to be reused for several organizations. If organization-specific LDAP settings exist, they overrule the default LDAP settings. </p>
            <p><b>To define default LDAP settings:</b>
            </p>
            <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal, choose <b>Manage LDAP settings</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu. For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help.<ph
                    audience="doc"> For a list of LDAP keys, refer to <xref
                        href="../../Shared/reference/r_LDAP_SettingTypes.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Checking the Connection to an LDAP System</title>
            <p>If for some reason an organization's LDAP system cannot be reached, you can check and restore the connection so that user authentication is possible again. </p>
            <p><b>To check an LDAP connection:</b>
            </p>
            <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal, choose <b>Manage LDAP settings</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu. For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help.<ph
                    audience="doc"> For a list of LDAP keys, refer to <xref
                        href="../../Shared/reference/r_LDAP_SettingTypes.xml"/>.</ph></p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
