<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="Timers" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Configuring Timers</title>
    <conbody>
        <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_manageTimers.xml#concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95/concept_Timers"> </p>
        <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_manageTimers.xml#concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95/concept_Timers1"> </p>
        <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_manageTimers.xml#concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95/concept_Timers2"> </p>
        <p conref="../../help/tasks/operator_manageTimers.xml#concept_B32294CC9FA643A2A14A74B1DAA49C95/concept_Timers3"> </p>
        <section>
            <title>Example</title>
            <p>For the timer used to remove customer accounts that have not been confirmed, the following configuration settings are defined: </p>
            <p><codeph>PERMITTED_PERIOD_UNCONFIRMED_ORGANIZATIONS=604800000</codeph>
            </p>
            <p><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_ORGANIZATION=86400000</codeph>
            </p>
            <p><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_ORGANIZATION_OFFSET=300000</codeph></p>
            <p>The first setting indicates how long an organization account is allowed to remain unconfirmed: 7 days. The second setting indicates the time interval at which the check for unconfirmed accounts is executed: every 24 hours. The third setting, the offset, is set to 5 minutes. The timer will expire at 0:05 a.m. every day. The offset is not accumulated, but stays the same every day. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Available Timers</title>
            <p>There are the following timers: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><b><codeph>ORGANIZATION_UNCONFIRMED</codeph></b>: Timer to check for organization accounts that have not been confirmed by a login of the initial administrator within a certain period of time. When this timer expires, the respective organization accounts are removed. <p>This timer requires the following configuration settings: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_ORGANIZATION</codeph>
                        </li>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_ORGANIZATION_OFFSET</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>PERMITTED_PERIOD_UNCONFIRMED_ORGANIZATIONS</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><codeph><b>SYNCHRONIZE_USERS</b></codeph>: Relevant of OIDC authentication mode only. Timer to synchronize users in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> organizations with users in the corresponding groups in the OIDC provider system. The interval for this timer is one day and cannot be changed. <p>This timer requires the following configuration setting: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_SYNCHRONIZE_USERS_OFFSET</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><codeph><b>USER_NUM_CHECK</b></codeph>: Timer to check for the current amount of users registered with the platform. <p>This timer requires the following configuration setting: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_USER_COUNT</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><b><codeph>RESTRICTED_SUBSCRIPTION_USAGE_PERIOD</codeph></b>: Timer used to ensure that subscriptions can only be used for the time specified in the underlying service's parameters. If this period is exceeded, the timer-related operations must be executed to make sure that the subscription cannot be used anymore unless the supplier upgrades or downgrades the underlying service. <p>This timer requires the following configuration settings: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_SUBSCRIPTION_EXPIRATION</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_SUBSCRIPTION_EXPIRATION_OFFSET</codeph></li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><codeph><b>TENANT_PROVISIONING_TIMEOUT</b></codeph>: Timer used to check pending subscriptions. When the timeout time is reached, an email is sent to the administrators and the relevant OU administrators and subscription managers of the organizations who created the subscriptions, informing them about the timeout. <p>This timer requires the following configuration settings: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_TENANT_PROVISIONING_TIMEOUT</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_TENANT_PROVISIONING_TIMEOUT_OFFSET</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><b><codeph>BILLING_INVOCATION</codeph></b>: Timer for billing runs calculating subscription usage costs (customer billing data) or revenue share data. The interval for this timer is one day and cannot be changed. <p>This timer requires the following configuration setting: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li><codeph><b>DISCOUNT_END_CHECK</b></codeph>: Timer used to check whether the end date for discounts granted to customers has been reached. The timer interval is one day and cannot be changed.<p>This timer requires the following configuration settings: </p><ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_DISCOUNT_END_NOTIFICATION_OFFSET</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul></li>
                <li>
                    <p><b><codeph>INACTIVE_ON_BEHALF_USERS_REMOVAL</codeph></b>: Timer used to remove non-existing users from the database that were created because an organization acted on behalf of another organization. </p>
                    <p>The timer for database cleanup requires the following configuration settings:</p>
                    <ul>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_INACTIVE_ON_BEHALF_USERS</codeph></li>
                        <li><codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_INACTIVE_ON_BEHALF_USERS_OFFSET</codeph>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
            </ul>
            <p audience="doc">For a detailed description of the timers, refer to <xref
                    href="../../Shared/reference/r_ConfigSettings_UI.xml"/>. </p>
            <p><b>To configure a timer:</b>
            </p>
            <p>To view the current settings for the available timers, choose <b>Update configuration settings</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal. To persistently update the setting of a timer, proceed as described in <xref
                    href="c_UpdateConfiguration.xml"/>. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Retrieving Expiration Times</title>
            <p>You can check when the currently registered timers expire. </p>
            <p><b>To retrieve the expiration times:</b>
            </p>
            <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal, choose <b>Manage timers</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu. For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Re-Initializing Timers</title>
            <p>When you set a timer or update the settings for a timer, you need to re-initialize the timers in order to start them. </p>
            <p><b>To re-initialize the timers:</b>
            </p>
            <p>In the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> administration portal, choose <b>Manage timers</b> in the <b>Operation</b> menu. For detailed step-by-step instructions, refer to the online help. </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
