<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<concept id="concept2311"
                    xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Usage Scenarios</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> supports a variety of usage scenarios. The following sections describe typical scenarios and provide an overview of the participating users and organizations.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Basic Usage Scenario</title>
            <p><ph
                        id="The_basic_scenario_of_deployi_concept_conbody_section_p_1">The basic scenario of deploying and using applications as services in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> framework involves the following users and organizations:</ph>
            </p>
            <fig>
                <image
                    align="center" alt="Scenario.png"
                    href="../_images/Scenario.png"
                        placement="break"/>
            </fig>
            <ol>
                <li><ph
                            id="Technology_providers_concept_conbody_section_ol_l"><b>Technology providers</b> (e.g. independent software vendors) technically prepare their applications for usage in the Cloud and integrate them with <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. They register the applications as technical services in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</ph>
                </li>
                <li><ph
                            id="Suppliers_concept_conbody_section_ol_l"><b>Suppliers</b> (e.g. independent software vendors or sales organizations) define service offerings, so-called marketable services, for the technical services in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. They publish the services to a marketplace.</ph>
                </li>
                <li><ph
                            id="Customers_concept_conbody_section_ol_l"><b>Customers</b> register themselves or are registered by an authorized organization in <ph
                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and subscribe to one or more services. Users appointed by the customers work with the underlying applications under the conditions of the corresponding subscriptions.</ph>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Extended Usage Scenarios</title>
            <p
                    id="The_concept_conbody_section_3_p">The <ph
                        id="suppliers_who_define_marketab_concept_conbody_section_3_p">suppliers who define marketable services may involve additional users and organizations in offering and selling these services</ph>:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><ph
                        id="Brokers_concept_conbody_section_3_u"><b>Brokers</b> support suppliers in establishing relationships to customers by offering the suppliers' services on a marketplace. A service subscription is a contract between the customer and the supplier.</ph></li>
                <li><ph
                    id="Resellers_concept_conbody_section_3_u"><b>Resellers</b> offer services defined by suppliers to customers applying their own terms and conditions. A service subscription establishes a contract between the customer and the reseller.</ph></li>
            </ul>
            <p>Brokers and resellers usually receive their share of a supplier's revenue. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> provides the means to define these revenue shares and calculate and retrieve the actual amounts from the service usage fees.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> Across Usage Scenarios</title>
            <p>In addition to technology providers, suppliers, resellers, brokers, and customers, the following users are involved in the preparation and operation of <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> and the applications integrated with it:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><ph
                        id="Marketplace_owners_concept_conbody_section_ul_l"><b>Marketplace owners</b> are responsible for administrating and customizing the marketplaces to which services are published.</ph></li>
                <li><ph
                            id="Operators_concept_conbody_section_ul_l"><b>Operators</b> are responsible for deploying and maintaining <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</ph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> offers features and functions which are of relevance for all these participating parties. These include a state-of-the-art user interface, account and identity management, and external process control. Public Web services and application programming interfaces (APIs) are available by which developers can integrate applications and external systems with <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
