<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd">

<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7">
    <title><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> for Operators</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Operators are the people who install, operate, and maintain <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> in their environment.</p>
            <p>The tasks of an operator comprise the following: </p>
            <ul>
                <li>Set up and maintain the <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> runtime environment. This includes the installation and deployment of <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and the interfacing with an application server, mail server, and databases.</li>
                <li>Monitor <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> to track system usage and problems that occur at runtime. This includes configuring log levels and maintaining log files. </li>
                <li>Create regular backups of the <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> databases, configuration settings, and log files.</li>
                <li>Create and manage organizations and users. This includes creating customer, technology provider, supplier, broker, and reseller organizations, importing users from data files provided by their organizations, locking and unlocking user accounts, and resetting the password of users.</li>
                <li>Define revenue shares for marketplace owners, brokers, resellers, and the operator. </li>
                <li>Create and manage marketplaces. This includes configuring marketplaces and assigning organizations as marketplace owners. </li>
                <li>Add additional language support so that users can work in other languages than the default ones available after installation (English, German, Japanese). The operator can customize or translate the default user interface and email texts, platform objects such as event and parameter names, labels and texts used in reports, as well as the online help topics for the administration portal and the FAQs for the marketplaces.</li>
                <li>Execute billing tasks. This includes the explicit start of billing runs or the manual retry of payment processing when, for example, communication problems caused the automatic payment processing for an organization to fail.</li>
                <li>Register, update, and remove external  billing systems. This includes choosing the default billing system.</li>
                <li>Set up a commercial payment service provider (PSP) for a supplier or reseller. This includes setting up the payment types and specifying the communication settings.</li>
                <li>Create certificates for trusted communication, import and sign them. Certificates are required for <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> to authenticate a calling client and to allow for trusted communication between <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> and an application underlying a technical service, a PSP, or an external process control system.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> provides the following facilities to support the operators in performing their tasks:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>After an operator has successfully installed and configured <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        />, he can access and use the <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> user interface.</li>
                <li>The <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                        /> reporting facilities provide operators with an overview of the revenue generated by the services which are published on their <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> installation, and of the revenue shares for the operator, suppliers, brokers, resellers and marketplace owners. In addition, operators can retrieve an overview of the marketable services of a supplier with their subscriptions, a list of all customers of a supplier and his brokers and the services they have subscribed to, as well as a summary of all billing data for each customer of a supplier and his brokers, and the billing data of the current billing period for a selected subscription of a supplier's customer.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>For a detailed description of all tasks involved in the operation and maintenance of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, refer to the <i>Operator's Guide</i>.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
