<?xml version="1.0"?> 
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN" "concept.dtd"

[
<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC "-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc" "entities.dtd">
]>

<concept xml:lang="en-us" id="concept_61077BCD8FA14EEAACBC7E421B654671">
    <title>Integrating External Process Control</title>
    <conbody>
        <section
            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_ProcessMgmtIntegration.xml#concept_61077BCD8FA14EEAACBC7E421B654671/Organizations_often_have_spec_concept_conbody_section_1"/>
        <section>
            <p>Users can see all pending actions at the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> user interface, cancel them, or delete aborted ones. </p>
        </section>
        <section
            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_ProcessMgmtIntegration.xml#concept_61077BCD8FA14EEAACBC7E421B654671/The_following_actions_may_be_concept_conbody_section_2"/>
        <section>
            <title>Connecting to an External Process Control System</title>
            <p>If you want <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> to connect to an external system to handle notifications and thus make use of the trigger processing feature of <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, the following steps are required: </p>
            <p>
                <ol>
                    <li>Implement a notification service:<p>An external system that is to be notified about certain actions must implement a Web service that connects <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> with it. The Web service must implement the notification API, which is available in the following variants:</p><ul>
                            <li>SOAP-based API, <codeph>org.oscm.notification.intf.NotificationService</codeph>.</li>
                            <li>REST API, described in <codeph>notification-rest-api.yaml</codeph>. Be aware that this API only supports <codeph>Subscribe to service</codeph>, <codeph>Modify subscription</codeph>, and <codeph>Terminate subscription</codeph> triggers.</li>
                        </ul><p>Both APIs and their documentation are provided with the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> integration package. </p></li>
                    <li>Deploy the notification service in your environment. You can do this on the system hosting the process control system you want to use, or on any other system.</li>
                    <li>Configure the relevant triggers in <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. To do this, you must be an administrator of your organization in <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />. <p>When defining a trigger, you need to provide the URL of the notification service: </p><ul>
                            <li>When using the SOAP-based API, this is the URL of the service's WSDL file, for example: <codeph>https://myServer:8280/NotificationService?wsdl</codeph>. </li>
                            <li>When using the REST API, this is the URL to which <ph
                                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                    /> can send a <codeph>POST</codeph> request for notification purposes.</li>
                        </ul><p>For details on how to define and manage triggers in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>, refer to the <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                /> online help.</p><p>As soon as the notification service is deployed and the process triggers have been configured in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            />, every action for which a process trigger has been configured results in a notification to your notification service. A trigger process key is sent for all actions that require a callback from the external system. This key is necessary to approve or reject an action. </p><p>The process triggers are queued and executed asynchronously. They are not called inside the transaction initiated by the user.</p></li>
                    <li>For approval or rejection, the process control system needs to send its response to the trigger service of <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                            href="../Interfaces/c_PlatformServices.xml"/>)</ph>. The API of the trigger service is available in the following variants: <ul>
                            <li>SOAP-based API, <codeph>org.oscm.intf.TriggerService</codeph>.</li>
                            <li>REST API, described in <codeph>trigger-service-rest-api.yaml</codeph>. </li>
                        </ul><p>As a result of the response, the interrupted action in <ph
                                conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                            /> is continued or canceled. When rejecting an action, the reason for the rejection can be passed. </p></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
