<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>The Supplier's Tasks in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section><fig>
                <image href="../_images/Intro.png" alt="Intro.png" width="350" height="173" placement="break"
                    align="center"/>
            </fig><p>As a supplier, you define marketable services for applications that have been prepared and registered as technical services in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> by technology providers.</p><p>For each technical service, you can create any number of marketable services, applying different price models, configurations, and restrictions. A price model defines how much a customer will be charged for using a service. </p><p>Once you have defined a marketable service and its associated price model, you can make the service available to customers by publishing it to a marketplace. Instead of or in addition to offering services yourself, you can appoint brokers or resellers to do so on the same or different marketplaces.</p><p>For subscribing to services you offer and using the underlying applications in the Cloud, customers need to register themselves with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, or you can register them. The customers can subscribe to any number of your services on the basis of the terms and conditions and the price models you have defined. They can register or import any number of users who work with the services.</p><p>Apart from providing marketable services with their price models, your role as a supplier involves:</p><ul>
                <li>Managing your customers. This includes, for example, explicitly terminating a customer's subscription.</li>
                <li>Preparing billing and payment. As users work with a service, the usage charges are calculated based on the fees defined in the related price model. This billing data can be used for generating invoices. You are responsible for the processing of the billing data and payment collection. <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> enables you to integrate and use the facilities of a commercial payment service provider (PSP) for this purpose.</li>
                <li>Handling revenue shares. The platform operator, the owners of the marketplaces where you publish your services as well as the brokers and resellers who support you are usually entitled to certain shares of your revenues. The revenue shares are defined by the operator. They may differ for individual marketplaces, brokers or resellers, or even specific services. For services applying the native billing system of <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />, you can at any time retrieve billing data and information on the actual revenues depending on the usage of the services. This data can be used as the basis for collecting or paying the shares, depending on your contracts with the participating parties.</li>
            </ul><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> offers comprehensive reports for different purposes and at different levels of detail. Supplier reports focus on retrieving business data that enable you, for example, to recognize specific patterns of customer behavior.<p>As a supplier, you can carry out specific actions under the control of an external process control system. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> provides a way to interact with such an external process control system by means of triggers and dedicated Web services. </p><p>If required, you can also act as a customer in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. As a supplier, you are automatically privileged to subscribe to services and work with the services you have subscribed to. </p><p>If you need to perform technology provider or marketplace owner tasks, your organization must be assigned the corresponding roles by the operator. Note that a supplier organization cannot be assigned the reseller or broker role in addition. </p></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
