<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Public Web Services and APIs</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> exposes its basic functionality as public Web services and provides APIs that enable developers to make applications ready for SaaS and use the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> features. </p>
            <p>The so-called <b>platform services</b> can be invoked by any application that implements Web services. In addition, the following utilities for developers are available: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Provisioning API</b>: Resources for implementing a provisioning service which is necessary for integrating an application with the subscription management of <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>. </li>
                <li><b>Notification API and Trigger API</b>: Resources for implementing and using a notification service which must be provided to enable <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> to interact with an external process control system.</li>
                <li><b>Operation API</b>: Resources for implementing the interface for calling operations for a technical service, such as backup and restore. </li>
                <!--li><b>Payment Service API</b>: Resources for integrating a payment service provider (PSP) with <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</li-->
                <li><b>Integration Helpers</b>: A Web application package that supports application developers in adapting the login/logout implementation of a Java-based Web application.</li>
                <li><b>Asynchronous Provisioning Platform (APP)</b>: A framework for integrating applications with <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> using provisioning services that work in asynchronous mode.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>While the platform services and most of the APIs are based on SOAP (Simple Object Access Protocol) and WSDL (Web Services Description Language), several components provide a REST (Representational State Transfer) API in addition or a pure Java API. The REST API and its documentation are accessible and useable by means of the Swagger toolkit.</p>
            <!--p>For a description of the basic concepts and usage of the public Web services, APIs, and additional resources and samples that are provided for developers, refer to the <i>Developer's Guide</i>. For a description of the resources for integrating a PSP, refer to the documentation shipped with the <codeph><xref format="html" href="https://github.com/servicecatalog/development/releases" scope="external"
                ><u><i>oscm-integration-psp-pack.zip</i></u></xref></codeph> file. </p-->
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
