<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN" "reference.dtd" >
<reference id="Service_Parameters_114">
  <title>Service Parameters and Operations</title>
  <refbody>
    <section>
      <p>The following sections describe the technical service parameters and service operations which are supported by the VMware service controller. </p>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>General Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters are required for provisioning a VM:</p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TEMPLATENAME</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The name of the VM template to be used for the provisioning of a new VM instance. The template is a master copy of a VM that can be used to create many clones. When you provision a VM, you create a copy of the template, including its settings, configured virtual devices, installed software, and other contents of its disks. </p>
                <p>Once specified, the template name can no longer be changed. Be aware that template names are case-sensitive. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>centos52-template</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>ACCESS_INFO</b></p>
                <p>Optional. A pattern for the access information for a VM after it has been provisioned. The access information is sent by email to the subscribing user as well as all users assigned to the subscription. It is displayed in the details of the subscription. </p>
                <p>The instance-specific values of this parameter contain the actual access information for the VM as soon as the subscription has been created. </p>
                <p>The pattern may contain any textual expression. In addition, the following placeholders are supported: </p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><codeph>${IP}</codeph>: IP address of the VM.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${HOST}</codeph>: Host name of the VM.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${CPU}</codeph>: CPU count.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${MEM}</codeph>: Main memory.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${DISK}</codeph>: System and data disk size(s).</li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>${HOST}(IP:${IP})&lt;br>${CPU} CPUs, ${MEM} RAM, ${DISK} HDD</codeph></p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>${HOST}, ${IP}</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>MAIL_FOR_COMPLETION</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The address to which emails are to be sent in case manual steps are required to complete an operation. If you specify this parameter, the service controller interrupts the provisioning of the VM and waits for a notification about the execution of a manual action. Omit this parameter if you do not want to interrupt the provisioning process. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>info@company.com</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VM Naming Rule Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters define the naming rules for the VMs to be provisioned: </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>INSTANCENAME</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The name of the VM instance to be provisioned. This name is either generated automatically, or must be specified by customers when they subscribe to a corresponding service. The instance name is used as the host name of the VM in the network configuration. The permitted length of host names depends on the operating system. </p>
                <p>The string given in <codeph>INSTANCENAME_PREFIX</codeph> is prepended to the name. The name including the prefix must match the pattern given in <codeph>INSTANCENAME_PATTERN</codeph>.</p>
                <p>For the automatic generation of instance names, the following placeholders are supported. They are filled with the corresponding data from the VMware service controller database when the VM is provisioned. Refer to <xref
                    href="r_CSVFormat.xml"/> for details. </p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><codeph>${VC}</codeph>: Unique ID of the vCenter derived from the <codeph>vcenter</codeph> database table. Specifies the vSphere server on which the VM is provisioned. </li>
                    <li><codeph>${DC}</codeph>: Unique ID of the data center derived from the <codeph>vcenter</codeph> database table. </li>
                    <li><codeph>${ID3}</codeph>: Unique sequential number of 3 digits.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${ID6}</codeph>: Unique sequential number of 6 digits.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${ID8}</codeph>: Unique sequential number of 8 digits. </li>
                    <li><codeph>${ID10}</codeph>: Unique sequential number of 10 digits.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${ID12}</codeph>: Unique sequential number of 12 digits.</li>
                    <li><codeph>${IP3}</codeph>: The last octet (eight bit) of the VM's IP address, for example, <codeph>152</codeph> of the <codeph>192.16.20.152</codeph> IP address. </li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>It is helpful to add some hint about the naming rules as default value. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>Hostname ([a-z0-9]){6,8}</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>INSTANCENAME_PATTERN</b></p>
                <p>Optional. A regular expression specifying a pattern for the VM instance names entered by the users when they subscribe to a corresponding service. This parameter is useful if the <codeph>INSTANCENAME</codeph> parameter is configurable by the user subscribing to the service, i.e. the instance names are not generated automatically. If the names do not match the pattern, the subscription is rejected. Special characters must not be used.</p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>^[a-zA-Z0-9][a-zA-Z0-9-]{0,61}[a-zA-Z0-9]$</codeph></p>
                <p>The pattern may contain any textual expression. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>IT([a-z0-9]){6,8}</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>INSTANCENAME_PREFIX</b></p>
                <p>Optional. A string to be prepended to the VM instance names when they are generated or entered by the users when they subscribe to a corresponding service. The combination of prefix and instance name must match the <codeph>INSTANCENAME_PATTERN</codeph> parameter. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>IT</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VM Location Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters can be specified for defining where on the vSphere server the VMs are to be provisioned. The parameters can be used by suppliers for offering a list of options to the customers subscribing to a corresponding service. </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_VCENTER_SERVER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The site where vSphere is installed. vCenter is the centralized management tool for the vSphere suite. Together with the <codeph>TARGET_DATACENTER</codeph> and <codeph>TARGET_CLUSTER</codeph> parameters, this parameter is used to specify the location of the provisioned VM instances. The vCenter must be contained in the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database after the import of the <codeph>vcenter.csv</codeph> configuration file.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_DATACENTER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The data center where the VM instances will be provisioned. Together with the <codeph>TARGET_VCENTER_SERVER</codeph> and <codeph>TARGET_CLUSTER</codeph> parameters, this parameter is used to determine the location of the provisioned VM instances. The data center must be contained in the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database after the import of the <codeph>datacenter.csv</codeph> configuration file.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_CLUSTER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The cluster where the VM instances will be provisioned. A cluster is a group of hosts. Together with the <codeph>TARGET_VCENTER_SERVER</codeph> and <codeph>TARGET_DATACENTER</codeph> parameters, this parameter is used to determine the location of the provisoned VM instances. The cluster must be contained in the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database after the import of the <codeph>cluster.csv</codeph> configuration file. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_HOST</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The name of the host on which the VM instances will be provisioned. If not specified, the default vSphere load balancing mechanism will determine the host machine to be used. In this case, the target host will be the one with the least VMs running on it. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_STORAGE</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The name of the disk where the files of the VM instances are to be stored. If not specified, the vSphere load balancing mechanism will determine the target storage. In this case, the target storage will be the one with the highest amount of available disk space.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>vmwdev1</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>TARGET_FOLDER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The name of the virtual folder where the VM instances will be provisioned. If not specified, the VMs are placed into the folder where the VM template from which they were cloned is located. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>folder_${ORGID}</codeph></p>
                <p><codeph>${ORGID}</codeph> is a placeholder for the organization of the subscribing user.</p>
                <p>The actual value will be, for example, <codeph>folder_83d79a</codeph>.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VM Sizing Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters define the size of the VMs to be provisioned. Make sure that users can only specify numbers that are supported by the VM template and the configuration in vSphere. This can be done, for example, by presenting the supported numbers as different parameter options for selection. </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NUMBER_OF_CPU</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The number of virtual CPUs the VM instance to be provisioned will use. The number of licensed CPUs on the host, the number of CPUs that the guest operating system supports, and the VM hardware version determine the number of virtual CPUs that you can use. </p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>1</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>AMOUNT_OF_RAM</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The amout of memory in MB allocated to each VM. </p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>1024</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DISK_SIZE</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The operating system disk size in GB. This parameter can be used to adjust the system disk size. If the parameter is not specified, the same disk size as specified in the VM template is used. </p>
                <p>Currently, only one virtual device is supported. If multiple disks are defined in the VM template, the first one only will be configured. </p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>40</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DATA_DISK_SIZE_#</b></p>
                <p>Optional. Up to 4 additional data disks can be defined: Replace the hash sign (<codeph>#</codeph>) with a digit between 1 and 4. For each disk, this parameter is used for specifying the disk size in GB. Make sure that when a user modifies subscription parameters, the value for the disk size can only be increased.</p>
                <p>When adding data disks, additional actions are required on the operating system where the VMs are provisioned: To enable disk usage, you need to format and mount them. To do so, you could use a script and provide the script's URL in the <codeph>SCRIPT_URL</codeph> service parameter.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>DATA_DISK_SIZE_1="40"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DATA_DISK_TARGET_#</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The mount point of the data disk with the given number (Linux), or the disk drive (Microsoft Windows).</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>DATA_DISK_TARGET_1="D"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DATA_DISK_TARGET_VALIDATION_#</b></p>
                <p>Optional. A regular expression specifying a fixed part of the mount point or disk drive where the additional data disk is to be mounted. This parameter must not be configurable by the user subscribing to the service.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>~/home/datadisk/</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VM Network Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters define the network for the VM instances to be provisioned: </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NUMBER_OF_NICS</b></p>
                <p>Mandatory. The number of network interface cards (NICs) which are to be used for new VMs. The number must match the number defined in the VM template. You can configure up to 4 networks for a VM. </p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>1</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_NETWORK_ADAPTER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The network adapter with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>)  which is to be used when a VM is provisioned. If specified, it replaces the network adapter defined in the VM template. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_NETWORK_ADAPTER="VLAN1"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_NETWORK_SETTINGS</b></p>
                <p>Optional. Determines how the IP address for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>) is set. The following options can be specified: </p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><codeph>DHCP</codeph>: The DHCP protocol defines the IP address. </li>
                    <li><codeph>MANUAL</codeph>: The IP address is specified manually using the <codeph>NIC#_*</codeph> service parameters described below.</li>
                    <li><codeph>DATABASE</codeph>: The IP address is retrieved from the <codeph>vmware</codeph> database. The first free address is taken. The available IP addresses must have been defined in and imported from the <codeph>ippool.csv</codeph> configuration file.</li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_NETWORK_SETTINGS="DHCP"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_IP_ADDRESS</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The IP address for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>). Only useful when the <codeph>NIC#_NETWORK_SETTINGS</codeph> parameter is set to <codeph>MANUAL</codeph>.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_IP_ADDRESS="172.16.254.1"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_SUBNET_MASK</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The subnet mask for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>). Only useful when the <codeph>NIC#_NETWORK_SETTINGS</codeph> parameter is set to <codeph>MANUAL</codeph>.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_SUBNET_MASK="255.255.252.0"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_GATEWAY</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The gateway for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>). Only useful when the <codeph>NIC#_NETWORK_SETTINGS</codeph> parameter is set to <codeph>MANUAL</codeph>.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_GATEWAY="192.0.2.254"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_DNS_SERVER</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The DNS server for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>). Only useful when the <codeph>NIC#_NETWORK_SETTINGS</codeph> parameter is set to <codeph>MANUAL</codeph>.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_DNS_SERVER="208.67.222.222"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>NIC#_DNS_SUFFIX</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The DNS suffix for the NIC with the given number (<codeph>#</codeph>). The suffix is used in DNS name registration and resolution. This policy lets you specify a suffix for a group of VMs, and prevents users from changing it. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>NIC1_DNS_SUFFIX="example.com"</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>VM Configuration Parameters</title>
      <p>The following parameters define the configuration of the VMs to be provisioned: </p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SCRIPT_URL</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The URL points to a shell script (Linux) or batch file (Microsoft Windows) that is downloaded from the given location, and uploaded and executed on a VM after the VM has been created and configured. You can use such a script or batch file, for example, for formatting and mounting additional data disks, or changing the root password. For security reasons, the <codeph>SCRIPT_URL</codeph> parameter must not be configurable by the user subscribing to the service.</p>
                <p>Apart from the <codeph>SCRIPT_URL</codeph> parameter, the following service parameters must be specified: </p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li>
                      <p><codeph>SCRIPT_USERID</codeph>
                      </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                      <p><codeph>SCRIPT_PWD</codeph>
                      </p>
                    </li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>Scripts or batch files can be provided, for example, in the <codeph>docroot</codeph> directory of the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain.</p>
                <p>A script or batch file can contain commands or placeholders for the following service parameters:</p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><codeph>LINUX_ROOT_PWD</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>NIC#_DNS_SERVER</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>NIC#_DNS_SUFFIX</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>NIC#_GATEWAY</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>NIC#_IP_ADDRESS</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>NIC#_SUBNET_MASK</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>INSTANCENAME</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>SCRIPT_URL</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>SCRIPT_USERID</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>SCRIPT_PWD</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>DOMAIN_NAME</codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>DATA_DISK_TARGET_#</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>DATA_DISK_SIZE_#</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                    <li><codeph>DATA_DISK_TARGET_VALIDATION_#</codeph> (<codeph>#</codeph> being a digit between 1 and 4)</li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>If the script or batch file contains a placeholder for a service parameter, you must insert the user credentials of a service manager of a supplier organization as VMware service controller settings:</p>
                <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li><codeph>USERID_&lt;organizationID></codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>USERKEY_&lt;organizationID></codeph></li>
                    <li><codeph>USERPWD_&lt;organizationID></codeph></li>
                  </ul>
                </p>
                <p>For details, refer to <xref href="r_ConfigSettingsController.xml"/>.</p>
                <p>A sample script for changing the Linux root password is available in the <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/samples</codeph> directory: <codeph>changeRootPassword.sh</codeph>.</p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>http://localhost:8080/changeNetworkSettings.sh</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SCRIPT_USERID</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The user ID for executing the shell script (Linux) or batch file (Microsoft Windows) in the VM. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SCRIPT_PWD</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The password for executing the shell script (Linux) or batch file (Microsoft Windows) in the VM. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>DOMAIN_NAME</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The domain part of the fully qualified domain name (FQDN) for Linux environments, or the Microsoft Windows domain that the VM will join if it is a Microsoft Windows system.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>LINUX_ROOT_PWD</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The root account password for Linux environments. Initially, a VM is provisioned with the user credentials derived from the VM template. </p>
                <p>The root password can be changed only by executing a script using the <codeph>SCRIPT_URL</codeph> parameter. A sample of such a script is provided in the <codeph>&lt;install_pack_dir>/samples</codeph> directory:  <codeph>changeRootPassword.sh</codeph>. </p>
                <p>In the sample script, the <codeph>LINUX_ROOT_PWD</codeph> parameter contains the new Linux root password which is set when the script is executed. The sample script can be provided, for example, in the <codeph>docroot</codeph> directory of the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_DOMAIN_JOIN</b></p>
                <p>Optional. If set to <codeph>true</codeph>, the VM will join a Microsoft Windows domain, if set to <codeph>false</codeph>, the VM will be part of a Microsoft Windows Workgroup. </p>
                <p>Default: <codeph>false</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_DOMAIN_ADMIN</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The name of a Microsoft Windows domain administrator.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_DOMAIN_ADMIN_PWD</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The password of the Microsoft Windows domain administrator.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_WORKGROUP</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The Microsoft Windows Workgroup the VM will join, if specified by the <codeph>WINDOWS_DOMAIN_JOIN</codeph> parameter.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_LOCAL_ADMIN_PWD</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The local administrator password of the VM.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>WINDOWS_LICENSEKEY</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The license key of the Microsoft Windows system.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SYSPREP_RUNONCE_COMMAND</b></p>
                <p>Optional. The Microsoft Windows batch file that is executed by the Microsoft Windows system preparation script (<codeph>sysprep</codeph>) after the first boot. </p>
                <p>Example: <codeph>cmd /c CALL \\server\share\file.bat</codeph></p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>Service Operations for VMs</title>
      <p>The VMware service controller supports the service operations below for VMs. </p>
      <p>The <codeph>actionURL</codeph> for each operation is:</p>
      <p><codeph>https://&lt;host>:&lt;port>/OperationService/AsynchronousOperationProxy?wsdl</codeph></p>
      <p><codeph>&lt;host></codeph> and <codeph>&lt;port></codeph> are the server and port of the <codeph>app-domain</codeph> domain where the vSphere integration software is deployed.</p>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>START_VM</b></p>
                <p>Starts a VM in vSphere if it was stopped.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>STOP_VM</b></p>
                <p>Stops a VM in vSphere if it was started.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>RESTART_VM</b></p>
                <p>Shuts down a VM in vSphere and starts it again. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>SNAPSHOT_VM</b></p>
                <p>Creates a snapshot of the VM. Be aware that no snapshot versions are stored. When a new snapshot is created, the previous one is overwritten. </p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
      <table frame="top">
        <tgroup cols="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>
                <p><b>RESTORE_VM</b></p>
                <p>Restores a previously created snapshot of the VM.</p>
              </entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </section>
  </refbody>
</reference>
