<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>The Broker's Tasks in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Your main task as a broker is the promotion of marketable services defined by one or more suppliers. To this end, you publish the services to marketplaces to which you have been granted access. A subscription to a service establishes a contract between the customer and the supplier of the service. </p>
            <p>
                <fig>
                    <image href="../../Shared/_images/ScenarioBroker.png" alt="ScenarioBroker.png" width="400"
                        height="77" align="center"/>
                </fig>
            </p>
            <p>In order to offer a service on a marketplace, you need an explicit permission by the supplier. The supplier defines the price model for the service as well as the terms and conditions. As a broker, you cannot change any of these. </p>
            <p>For subscribing to services you offer, customers need to register with <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, or you can register them. The customers can register or import any number of users who work with the services. As a broker, you can view the customer subscriptions, but you cannot change or terminate them.</p>
            <p>Brokers usually receive a share of the revenue for the services they offer. This revenue share is defined by the operator. It may be different for each marketplace where you offer services or even for individual services. You can at any time retrieve billing data and information on your actual revenue depending on the usage of the services. The data can be used as the basis for collecting the shares from the suppliers or marketplace owners, depending on who is responsible for paying you according to your contracts.</p>
            <p>If required, you can also act as a customer in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. As a broker, you are automatically privileged to subscribe to services and work with the services you have subscribed to. </p>
            <p>If you need to perform marketplace owner tasks, your organization must be assigned the corresponding role by the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> operator. Note that a broker organization cannot additionally be assigned the technology provider, supplier, or reseller role.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
