<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>The Technology Provider's Tasks in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
        /></title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <fig>
                <image href="../_images/TechProvRole.png" alt="TechProvRole.png" placement="break"
                    align="center"/>
            </fig>
            <p>As a technology provider, you own or develop applications which you intend to provide as services in the Cloud using <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> to cover the business-related functionality. </p>
            <p>To achieve this goal, you perform the following basic tasks:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Prepare your applications for usage in a SaaS model, taking into consideration aspects such as a remote interface, multi-tenancy, high scalability and availability, and security.</li>
                <li>Implement the technical interfaces for integrating the applications with <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</li>
                <li>Provision the applications as technical services in <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>As soon as a technical service is available in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, one or more suppliers appointed by you can define actual service offerings, so-called marketable services, for it. The suppliers (or brokers or resellers appointed by them) publish these services to a marketplace, where customers can subscribe to them.</p>
            <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> provides specific reports for technology providers. For example, you can retrieve information on the number of subscriptions for your services and on the usage and load of the underlying applications. </p>
            <p>As a technology provider, you can also act as a customer in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />. This means that you are automatically privileged to subscribe to services and work with the services you have subscribed to. </p>
            <p>If you also need to perform supplier or marketplace owner tasks, your organization must be assigned the corresponding roles by the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> operator.</p>
        </section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
