<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Controller Configuration Settings</title>
    <refbody>
        <section id="The_reference_refbody_section_1">
            <p>This appendix describes the controller configuration settings as stored in the <codeph>bssapp</codeph> database. For details on how to update them, refer to <xref
                    href="../Administrating/c_UpdateConfiguration.xml"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>CONTROLLER_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>CONTROLLER_ID=ess.aws</codeph></p>
            <p>The identifier of the service controller. This setting cannot be changed.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_ORGANIZATION_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_ORGANIZATION_ID=&lt;organizationID></codeph></p>
            <p>The ID of the organization in <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> which is responsible for the service controller. The organization must have the technology provider role. It is created and initially assigned to the AWS service controller by the platform operator.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_ID</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_ID=&lt;userId></codeph>
            </p>
            <p>The identifier of the user specified in <codeph>BSS_USER_KEY</codeph> for accessing <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_KEY</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_KEY=&lt;userKey></codeph>
            </p>
            <p>The user key for accessing <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />.</p>
            <p>The user key for accessing <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    />. You receive this key with the confirmation email for your user account. The user must have the technology manager role in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> and belong to the technology provider organization responsible for the service controller. </p>
            <p>It is recommended that the user account is used only for carrying out actions on behalf of the service controller in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BSS_USER_PWD</title>
            <p><codeph>BSS_USER_PWD=_crypt:&lt;password></codeph></p>
            <p>The password of the user for accessing <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/>.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>ACCESS_KEY_ID_PWD</title>
            <p><codeph>ACCESS_KEY_ID_PWD=_crypt:&lt;accessKeyID></codeph></p>
            <p>The identifier of the access key for the AWS account.</p>
            <p>A technology provider who is responsible for creating technical services for appropriate AMIs needs to have an AWS account to create Amazon EC2 instances. For details about creating an AWS account, refer to the user documentation of Amazon Web Services.</p>
            <p>Together with the secret access key, the access key ID is used to authenticate API calls to Amazon EC2.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>SECRET_KEY_PWD</title>
            <p><codeph>SECRET_KEY_PWD=_crypt:&lt;secretAccessKey></codeph></p>
            <p>The secret access key for the AWS account.</p>
            <p>Together with the access key ID, the secret access key is used to authenticate API calls to Amazon EC2.</p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
