<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_E68E2024B1F6403AAA1130A39B1D4DCD" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Modifying Subscription Parameters</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>By modifying the corresponding service parameters at their subscriptions, customers can change the virtual platforms and servers provisioned in ROR. </p>
            <p>The following scenarios are supported by the ROR integration software:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Horizontal scale-up and scale-down</b>: By changing the corresponding service parameters, customers can trigger ROR to add a virtual server to their virtual platform. In the same way, they can request ROR to remove a virtual server from the platform.<p> In both cases, the ROR service controller informs the master virtual server of the new number and IP addresses of the slave servers. </p><p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the virtual platform and servers are ready to be used with the changed parameters. The IP addresses of the virtual servers and the initial passwords for accessing them are output in the subscription details. The initial user ID for accessing the virtual servers is <codeph>Administrator</codeph> for Microsoft Windows systems, <codeph>root</codeph> for Linux systems. It is strongly recommended that the initial password is changed after the first login.</p></li>
                <li><b>Vertical scale-up and scale-down</b>: By changing the corresponding service parameters, customers can trigger ROR to add CPUs to each virtual server in their virtual platform. In the same way, they can request ROR to remove CPUs from the virtual servers. <p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the virtual platform and servers are ready to be used with the changed parameters. </p></li>
            </ul>
            <p>The modifications are carried out in asynchronous mode. As long as the update is not complete, the status of the corresponding subscription is <b>pending update</b>.  The status changes to <b>ready</b> as soon as the modificaton has been finished successfully. </p>
            <note>If the subscription was <b>suspended</b> before starting the modification, its status changes to <b>suspended update</b> as long as the operation is not complete.</note>
            <p>In the technical service definition, you can specify an address to which emails are to be sent that notify service users or administrators of customer organizations about a successful modification of a virtual platform or server.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
