<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<task id="task_E68E2024B1F6403AAA1130A39B1D4DCD" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Subscribing to Services</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>Users of customer organizations can subscribe to the services you have created for ROR on the marketplace where you have published them. This results in the provisioning of a virtual platform or server in ROR, as defined in the underlying technical service.</p>
            <p>The following scenarios are supported by the ROR integration software:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Provisioning of a virtual platform (L-Platform)</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service, ROR is triggered to create a virtual platform with one or more virtual servers based on a specific template. <p>The customer can enter a name for the virtual platform. The technical service may specify a prefix which is prepended to this name, as well as a pattern against which the name is checked before the provisioning operation is started. </p><p>Depending on the parameters defined for the technical service, the customer can select or enter the number of virtual servers and/or the number of CPUs for each server. </p><p>As soon as the virtual platform is available, the ROR service controller informs the master virtual server of the number and IP addresses of the slave servers. </p><p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the virtual platform and servers are ready to use. The IP addresses of the virtual servers and the initial passwords for accessing them are output in the subscription details on the marketplace. </p></li>
                <li><b>Assignment of a single server to an existing virtual platform</b>: When a customer subscribes to a corresponding service, ROR is triggered to instantiate a virtual server. This virtual server is added to an existing virtual platform for which the same customer already has a subscription. <p>The customer can enter a name for the virtual server. The technical service may specify a prefix which is prepended to this name, as well as a pattern against which the name is checked before the provisioning operation is started. </p><p>Depending on the parameters defined for the technical service, the customer can select or enter the number of CPUs for the new server. Technical parameters, such as the IDs of the virtual platform or the network within the virtual platform, to which the new server is to be added, are usually specified in the technical service, not by the customer.</p><p>If all steps are completed successfully, the subscription and the new virtual server are ready to use. The IP address of the new virtual server and the initial password for accessing it are output in the subscription details on the marketplace. </p></li>
            </ul>
            <p>The provisioning operations are carried out in asynchronous mode. As long as the provisioning is not complete, the status of the subscription is <b>pending</b>. The status changes to <b>ready</b> as soon as the provisioning has been finished successfully. </p>
            <p>The users assigned to a subscription can access the virtual servers provided by ROR using the IP addresses and initial passwords indicated in the subscription details. The initial user ID for accessing the virtual servers is <codeph>Administrator</codeph> for Microsoft Windows systems, <codeph>root</codeph> for Linux systems. It is strongly recommended that the initial password is changed after the first login.</p>
            <p>In ROR, the virtual platforms and servers created for <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> subscriptions are managed in the same way as other virtual platforms and servers. They can be viewed and monitored with the standard ROR tools.</p>
        </context>
    </taskbody>
</task>
