<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634"
        xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing the access to a marketplace</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p><ph
                id="On_the_task_taskbody_context_p_1_ph">On the <uicontrol>Manage access</uicontrol> page, you can decide who is allowed to access a marketplace. </ph>
      </p>
      <p><ph id="When_a_marketplace_is_created_task_taskbody_context_p_2_ph"><ph id="When_a_marketplace_small_ph"
              >When a marketplace is created, it is public and accessible by any anonymous or registered users. <ph
              platform="help">You</ph><ph platform="print"
            >The marketplace owner</ph> can restrict the access to it to the users of specific registered organizations.</ph>
        <ph id="When_a_marketplace_small2_ph">In this case, the users need to log in to be able to see, subscribe to, and use the services published on the marketplace. New customers cannot register themselves on the marketplace but need to be registered by a supplier, broker, reseller, or the platform operator.</ph>
        </ph></p>
      <p><ph id="If_task_taskbody_context_p_3_ph"
          >If you turn a marketplace from a public into a non-public one, organizations with existing subscriptions or services published on the marketplace are automatically granted access to it. You can at any time revoke the access permission for each of these organizations in the same way as for organizations which were granted access explicitly. As a prerequisite, the organization's existing subscriptions must have been terminated and its services published on the marketplace must have been deactivated. </ph></p>
      <p><ph id="A_marketplace_with_restricted_task_taskbody_context_p_4_ph">A marketplace with restricted access can at any time be made public again and thus accessible by any users and organizations.</ph></p>
      <p><b>To manage the access to a marketplace</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace for which you want to manage the access permissions. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The list contains all marketplaces to which you have access as a marketplace manager.</p>
          <p>The <uicontrol>Authorized customers only</uicontrol> option shows whether the marketplace is public or accessible by users of specific organizations only. In the latter case, the available organizations are listed below with check marks indicating the authorized ones.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Change the access policy for the marketplace as required by selecting or deselecting the <uicontrol>Authorized customers only</uicontrol> option.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>For a marketplace for authorized customers, select the organizations that are to be granted access. </cmd>
        <info>Remove the check mark to revoke the access permission for an organization. As a prerequisite, the organization must not have any active subscriptions or services published on the marketplace. </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
  </taskbody>
</task>
