<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Updating a marketplace</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>On the <uicontrol>Update marketplace</uicontrol> page, the following tasks can be performed: </p>
            <p>
                <ul compact="no">
                    <li>Assign another owner to the marketplace. This can be done by the platform operator.</li>
                    <li>Define revenue shares for the marketplace and the default revenue shares for broker and reseller organizations. Revenue shares can be defined by the platform operator. </li>
                    <li>Provide a different name for the marketplace. This can be done by a marketplace manager of the organization owning the marketplace. </li>
                    <li>Change the marketplace features and settings. This can be done by a marketplace manager of the organization owning the marketplace. </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p><b>To change the owner of a marketplace</b> (operators only):</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace whose owner you want to change. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The list contains all marketplaces that exist on your platform.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Assign another organization as the owner of the selected marketplace.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p><b>Caution</b>: Assigning a new owner to a marketplace may remove the marketplace owner role from the previous owner organization and the marketplace manager role from its users. This is the case if the marketplace for which you change the owner is the last one owned by the organization.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The administrators of the new owner organization are assigned the marketplace manager role. They are notified by email. The email contains two URLs. One can be used by the marketplace managers for administrating and customizing the marketplace. The other can be used for public access to the marketplace.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p><b>To define revenue shares</b> (operators only):</p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace for which revenue shares are to be defined. <p>The list contains all marketplaces that exist on your platform.</p></li>
                    <li>Specify percent values in the following entry fields: <p>
                            <ul>
                                <li><uicontrol>Marketplace owner revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: Revenue share the marketplace owner is to receive from organizations who offer and sell services on the selected marketplace. The marketplace owner revenue share applies to all services published to the marketplace. </li>
                                <li><uicontrol>Broker revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: Default revenue share all broker organizations will receive for selling services of suppliers who have authorized the brokers to do so. The default revenue share applies if no service-specific or organization-specific revenue share is defined using the <uicontrol>Manage broker revenue share</uicontrol> menu option. </li>
                                <li><uicontrol>Reseller revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: Default revenue share all reseller organizations will receive for selling services of suppliers who have authorized the resellers to do so. The default revenue share applies if no service-specific or organization-specific revenue share is defined using the <uicontrol>Manage reseller revenue share</uicontrol> menu option. </li>
                            </ul>
                        </p><p><b>Example</b>: Enter the following values: </p><p>
                            <ul>
                                <li><uicontrol>Marketplace owner revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: <codeph>10.00</codeph>
                                </li>
                                <li><uicontrol>Broker revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: <codeph>20.00</codeph></li>
                                <li><uicontrol>Reseller revenue share (%)</uicontrol>: <codeph>30.00</codeph></li>
                            </ul>
                        </p><p><b>Situation 1</b>: Only supplier organizations publish services to the marketplace. The operator revenue share is defined to be 10%. The marketplace owner receives 10% of the revenues resulting from selling the suppliers' services; the supplier organization receives the rest minus the operator revenue share (90% - 10% = 80%). </p><p><b>Situation 2</b>: A supplier has authorized a reseller to sell his services on the marketplace. The operator revenue share is defined to be 10%. The marketplace owner receives 10% of the revenues, the reseller receives 30%, the supplier receives the rest minus the operator revenue share (60% - 10% = 50%). </p><p><b>Situation 3</b>: A supplier has authorized a broker to offer his services on the marketplace. The operator revenue share is defined to be 10%. The marketplace owner receives 10% of the revenues, the broker receives 20%, the supplier receives the rest minus the operator revenue share (70% - 10% = 60%).</p><p
                            id="revenueshare"
                            >The values you enter for revenue share percentages are based on agreed conditions between the operator, marketplace owners, suppliers, resellers, and brokers. You as the operator are responsible for setting correct values. It is possible to set the percentages to a total of over 100%. This might be intentional. For example, a supplier who wants to strongly promote a service for a limited period of time may grant a broker or reseller a revenue share of 80%. In addition, the supplier may need to pay 30% of the revenue to the marketplace owner and 10% to the operator. This results in a total revenue share percentage of 120 and thus in a negative revenue for the supplier. </p></li>
                    <li>To save the revenue shares, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.<p>The shares are applied when the next billing run is started. The individual shares are calculated and output in the billing data.</p></li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p><b>To rename a marketplace</b> (marketplace managers only):</p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace to be renamed. <p>The list contains all marketplaces owned by your organization.</p></li>
                    <li>Specify the new name for the marketplace.<p>The marketplace name is offered for selection when you administrate or customize the marketplace, or manage the sellers who are allowed to publish services to it.</p></li>
                    <li>To save the new name, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>The marketplace is instantly displayed with the new name.</p>
            <p><b>To change the marketplace features and settings</b> (marketplace managers only):</p>
            <p>
                <ol compact="no">
                    <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace whose features and settings you want to change. <p>The list contains all marketplaces owned by your organization.</p></li>
                    <li>Change the <uicontrol>Tagging</uicontrol> feature for the marketplace, if required. <ph
                            conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/The_tag_cloud_contains_search_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/>
                        <p><ph conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/With_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/></p></li>
                    <li>Change the <uicontrol>Reviews</uicontrol> feature for the marketplace, if required. <ph><ph
                                conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/When_enabled_customers_who_s_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                            /></ph><p><ph conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/With_task_taskbody_steps_step_3"
                            /> Existing ratings and comments are retained, but they are not visible. They re-appear when you enable the feature again.</p></li>
                    <li>Change the <uicontrol>Social bookmarks</uicontrol> feature for the marketplace, if required. <ph><ph
                                conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/When_enabled_bookmarks_for_d_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                            /></ph><p><ph conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/With_task_taskbody_steps_step_4"
                        /></p></li>
                    <li>Change the <uicontrol>Authorized sellers only</uicontrol> feature for the marketplace, if required. When enabled, only authorized supplier, broker, and reseller organizations are allowed to publish services to the marketplace. As a marketplace manager of the marketplace owner organization, you are responsible for defining these sellers. <p><ph
                                conref="marketplace_create.xml#task634/Select_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"/></p><p><ph
                                id="When_you_switch_from_an_open_task_taskbody_result_p_5_ol"
                                >When you switch from an open marketplace to a marketplace for authorized sellers only, the sellers of all the services published so far are automatically admitted to it. Furthermore, the blacklist of the open marketplace is retained. This means that sellers you excluded from the marketplace will still be excluded, if you later decide to change the marketplace back to an open one.</ph></p><p><ph
                                id="The_same_applies_in_the_oppos_task_taskbody_result_p_5_ol"
                                >The same applies in the opposite direction: The list of authorized sellers is retained when you turn a marketplace into an open one. Additionally, the services of the authorized sellers remain published on the marketplace, unless the sellers are included in the marketplace's blacklist.</ph></p></li>
                    <li>Change the <uicontrol>Categories</uicontrol> feature for the marketplace, if required. When enabled, categories are shown on the marketplace. As a marketplace manager of the marketplace owner organization, you can define categories which suppliers, brokers, and resellers can assign to the services they publish to the marketplace. The categories can be used by visitors of the marketplace for filtering and browsing the services. The categories are also taken into consideration by the full-text search feature on the marketplace.<p>When you disable this feature, categories are no longer available to marketplace visitors for searching, filtering and browsing, but can still be defined and assigned to services. Existing category definitions and assignments are not affected.</p><p>
                            <note>As a marketplace manager, you can use categories for grouping the services displayed on the marketplace home page. Disabling this feature has no effect on the marketplace home page. The services are still grouped by categories, even if this feature is disabled.</note>
                        </p>
                    </li>
                    <li>To save the updated features and settings, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            <p>The updated features and settings are instantly applied. For marketplace visitors, the update takes effect with their next login to the marketplace. </p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
    <related-links>
        <linklist>
            <title>Related topics</title>
            <link href="marketplace_manageBrokerRevenueShare.xml"/>
            <link href="marketplace_manageResellerRevenueShare.xml"/>
            <link href="operator_manageOperatorRevenueShare.xml"/>
            <link href="marketplace_manageSuppliers.xml"/>
            <link href="marketplace_manageCategories.xml"/>
            <link href="marketplace_customizeLandingpage.xml"/>
        </linklist>
    </related-links>
</task>
