<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Executing billing tasks</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p id="Billing_Intro"
        >At daily intervals, the database content is checked for organizations which have produced billing-relevant data, the billing data is calculated, and the data is collected and stored in the database. These checks and calculations are called "billing runs for customer billing data". </p>
      <p id="Billing_Introx"
          >Each supplier and reseller can define his preferred start day of the monthly billing periods. When a billing period ends, the costs for all customer subscriptions that were produced in the course of this period are calculated. This is done in the billing run that is executed on the start day of the next billing period plus the offset defined by the <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> configuration setting. For example: A supplier defines that his billing period is to start on the 8th of a month. The <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> is set to 5 days and 4 hours. The billing run calculating the costs for the supplier's customers is executed on the 13th of each month at 04:00:00.000. </p>
      <p id="Billing_Intro1"
          >Brokers and resellers, as well as the platform operator and the owners of the marketplaces on which services are published, usually receive a share of the revenue for the services. The revenue shares for these organizations and their effects on suppliers' revenues are calculated every month based on the results of the daily checks for customer billing data. This calculation is called "billing run for revenue share data". The billing period for this billing run cannot be changed; it is always executed for the previous month on the first day of a month plus the offset defined by the <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> configuration setting. </p>
      <p id="Billing_Intro2"
        >When a billing run for customer billing data is finished, the billing data that must be handled by a payment service provider (PSP) is processed. This transaction is called "payment processing".</p>
      <note id="Billing_runs_apply_to_the_nat_task_taskbody_context_note"
          >Billing runs and payment processing apply to the <ph platform="help">platform's </ph>native billing system<ph
          platform="print"> of <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          /></ph>. They do not take into account any costs and data in external billing systems integrated with <ph
          platform="help">the platform</ph><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          platform="print"        />. These are controlled and managed solely in the external billing system. </note>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Execute billing tasks</uicontrol> page, you can perform the following tasks by clicking <uicontrol>Execute</uicontrol> in the relevant section of the page: </p>
      <p>
        <ul compact="no">
          <li><uicontrol>Start billing run</uicontrol>
            <p>This action explicitly starts a billing run for calculating the customer billing data for a billing period. </p><p
              id="StartBillingRun"
                >The billing period depends on the day when you start the billing run and on the <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> configuration setting. Explicitly starting a billing run is useful, for example if you want to check the payment processing of billing data by a PSP test system, and you do not want to wait for the automatic calculation of the data.</p><p
              id="StartBillingRun2"
                >If you start a billing run on the first day of a month plus the day(s) defined in the <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> setting, the revenue share data is also calculated and stored. </p><p>Examples:</p><p
              id="StartBillingRun3"
                >A supplier has defined his billing period to start on the 5th and end on the 4th of each month. The <codeph>TIMER_INTERVAL_BILLING_OFFSET</codeph> is set to 3 days. If you want to recalculate the customer billing data for this supplier, for example for the period of January 5th through February 4th, you need to start the billing on February 8th. </p><p
              id="StartBillingRun4"
              >If you want to calculate the revenue share data for the month of January, you need to start the billing run on February 4th. </p></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Start payment processing</uicontrol><p>This action starts the payment processing of customer billing data that must be handled by a payment service provider (PSP). It is checked whether the <codeph>PSP_USAGE_ENABLED</codeph> parameter has been set to <codeph>true</codeph>. If this is not the case, payment processing is aborted. To set the parameter, use the <b>Update configuration settings</b> option in the <b>Operation</b> menu.</p></li>
          <li><uicontrol>Retry failed payment processes</uicontrol><p>This action re-invokes failed payment processes, for example when communication problems caused the automatic payment processing for an organization to fail. </p></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
    </context>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="operator_manageConfiguration.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
