<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing users</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage users</uicontrol> page, you can lock the account of a specific user, for example when you assume unauthorized access. You can also unlock an account, for example in case it was locked because the user tried to log in using a wrong password for the configured number of times (default: 3). </p>
      <p>If the platform is installed in INTERNAL authentication mode you can initiate the generation of a new password for a user (unless you are using an external LDAP system for user management), and register multiple users in one operation by importing a user data file. </p>
      <p>If the platform is operated in OIDC authentication mode, you can synchronize the organizations and users on the platform with the corresponding groups at the OIDC provider systems.</p>
      <p>At the top of the page, you can view the number of users registered with the platform as well as the configured maximum number of registered users (default: 10). At regular intervals (default: 12 hours), the system checks the number of registered users. You are informed by email when this check returns that the allowed number of registered users is exceeded. </p>
      <p><b>To reset a password or lock/unlock a user</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Enter the ID of the user or select it from the list. </cmd>
        <info/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Reset Password</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Unlock</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Lock</uicontrol>, respectively. </cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>In all cases, the selected user is notified by email. </p>
      <p><b>To register multiple users for an organization</b>:</p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>Request the organization's administrator to provide a file containing the user data or create the file yourself.<ph audience="doc"> Refer to <xref
              href="../../Shared/reference/r_FileFormat_ImportUsers.xml"/> for details on the format and content.</ph> </li>
          <li>Import the user data file: <p>
              <ol compact="no">
                <li>Select the organization for which you want to import users. </li>
                <li>Select the marketplace to which the users are to be directed. </li>
                <li>Click the <b>File name</b> field or <b>Browse</b>, and select the file containing the user data.</li>
                <li>Click <b>Import</b>. <p>The system validates the user data file before starting the actual import. It checks whether: </p><p><ul
                      compact="no">
                      <li>All lines containing user data are complete (all fields are specified).</li>
                      <li>The spelling of the values for title and user roles is correct.</li>
                      <li>Multiple user roles are enclosed in double quotes.</li>
                    </ul>If an error is found during the validation of the user data file, a corresponding message is displayed and the import does not start. </p><p>You must correct the information in the file before you can start the import again. </p><p>You cannot start multiple imports at a time. You need to wait until the current import is finished. For long lists of users, this may take some time.</p></li>
              </ol>
            </p></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p>As soon as the import is finished, all users who have been imported and registered successfully are sent an email with the login data and an initial password to be used for the first login. The newly registered users are automatically added to the organization's default organizational unit. The default unit contains all users currently registered for the organization.</p>
      <p>You are sent an email with the following information: </p>
      <p>
        <ul compact="no">
          <li>Number of users who were imported and registered successfully. </li>
          <li>For every user that was not imported: user ID and reason.<p>Possible reasons are: </p><ul compact="no">
              <li>A user with the specified ID already exists.</li>
              <li>The specified user ID is invalid. </li>
              <li>The specified user role is not available for the organization. For example, if the organization is a supplier, the <codeph>BROKER_MANAGER</codeph> user role cannot be specified.</li>
            </ul></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p><b>To synchronize organizations with groups at the OIDC providers</b>:</p>
      <p>Click <uicontrol>Reload</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Users from OIDC Provider</uicontrol> section.</p>
      <p>All organizations of the platform are synchronized with the corresponding groups in the OIDC provider systems represented by the tenants assigned to the organizations. New group members are registered as platform users and can be assigned roles as required. Obsolete members are removed from the organizations, if possible.</p>
      <note>
        <p>For platform operations to work correctly, a specific user can be assigned to exactly one organization and group at a given time. </p>
        <p>On the platform, users can be manually added to or removed from organizations. However, such changes will be undone with the next synchronization with the OIDC provider system.</p>
      </note>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
