<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing operator revenue share</title>
  <taskbody id="On_the_task_taskbody">
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage operator revenue share</uicontrol> page, you can define a revenue share for individual services which a supplier offers on the marketplaces operated on your platform. The service-specific revenue share overrules the default operator revenue share defined for a supplier organization when creating or updating the organization. </p>
      <p>The service-specific revenue share applies irrespective of whether the supplier sells his services himself, or uses brokers or resellers for selling them. Discounts granted by a supplier to his customers are deducted from the operator revenue share. </p>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage operator revenue share</uicontrol> page, you can also update the revenue share for services for which the resale permission has already been revoked and for services which have already been deleted by a supplier. There might still be active subscriptions for these services, therefore it might be necessary for you to update the revenue share.</p>
      <p><b>To define the service-specific operator revenue share</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the service for which the revenue share is to be defined. </cmd>
        <info>The list contains all services that are available on your platform and all services that have already been deleted. The service name is followed by the organization ID of the supplier who provides the service. </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>The table shows the default operator revenue share defined for the supplier organization.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>In the <uicontrol>Revenue share (%)</uicontrol> entry field, you can specify a percent value for the service-specific revenue share: </p>
          <p>This percentage is valid for the selected service and applicable to the supplier publishing this service or authorizing brokers and resellers to do so. The value overrules the default value defined using the <uicontrol>Create organization</uicontrol> or <uicontrol>Manage organization</uicontrol> menu option, as well as any other previously defined service-specific revenue share. </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The value is applied as soon as a customer subscribes to the selected service. The revenue share amounts are calculated when the next billing run is started. </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result/>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="operator_createOrganization.xml"/>
      <link href="operator_manageOrganizations.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
