<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing a trigger</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage trigger</uicontrol> page, you can define a new process trigger for your organization or change or delete an existing one.</p>
      <p>As a prerequisite for controlling actions by processes, a notification service must exist and be deployed. This service forms the interface between the platform and the process control system. For details on implementing such a service, contact the platform operator.</p>
      <p><b>To add a new trigger</b>: </p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Display as</uicontrol> field, enter a name for the trigger as it is to be shown to users on the <uicontrol>Manage processes</uicontrol> page. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Type</uicontrol> list, select the action which is to be subject to process control. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The list contains all actions for which triggers can be configured. </p>
          <p>For any type of organization, the following triggers can be configured: </p>
          <ul>
            <li>A subscription is to be changed, for example, renamed (<codeph>Modify subscription</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A billing run is completed, and the billing data for a billing period is calculated (<codeph>Billing run finished</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A subscription is to be added (<codeph>Subscribe to service</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A user is to be assigned to or removed from a subscription (<codeph>Assign users to subscription</codeph>). <p>For the case that a user is automatically assigned to a new subscription when subscribing to a service, no trigger can be configured. The <codeph>Assign users to subscription</codeph> trigger only applies to users that are manually assigned to a subscription.</p></li>
            <li>A subscription is to be upgraded or downgraded (<codeph>Up/Downgrade subscription</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A subscription is to be terminated (<codeph>Terminate subscription</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A user is to be registered (<codeph>Register user</codeph>).<p>Triggers can only be configured for registering single users. The import of multiple users in one operation from an LDAP system or a user data file cannot be executed under process control.</p></li>
          </ul>
          <p>For <b>suppliers</b>, the following additional triggers can be configured: </p>
          <ul>
            <li>A customer is to be registered (<codeph>Register customer</codeph>). </li>
            <li>The payment types for a customer are to be changed (<codeph>Manage payment types for customer</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A marketable service is to be activated (<codeph>Activate service</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A marketable service is to be deactivated (<codeph>Deactivate service</codeph>). </li>
            <li>A user subscribes to a service of the supplier organization (<codeph>Subscription created (any user)</codeph>)</li>
            <li>A user modifies a subscription to a service of the supplier (<codeph>Subscription modified (any user)</codeph>)</li>
            <li>A user terminates a subscription to a service of the supplier (<codeph>Subscription terminated (any user)</codeph>)</li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Target type</uicontrol> field, choose the appropriate entry depending on the application programming interface (API) used for implementing the notification service for your organization: </cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li>SOAP-based API: <uicontrol>Web Service</uicontrol></li>
            <li>REST API: <uicontrol>REST Web Service</uicontrol></li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Target URL</uicontrol> field, enter the URL of the notification service implemented for your organization. The URL depends on the API used for implementing the notification service: </cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li>SOAP-based API: the URL of the WSDL file of the notification service, for example: <p><codeph>https://myServer:8280/NotificationService?wsdl</codeph>
              </p></li>
            <li>REST API: the URL to which <codeph>POST</codeph> requests are to be sent for notification purposes, for example: <p><codeph>https://myServer:8081/mynotification/v1/processes</codeph></p></li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Specify whether the execution of the action is to be suspended until it is approved or rejected in the external process control system. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>If not, the action is instantly executed. The process control system is informed if the action for the non-suspending trigger is executed successfully.</p>
          <p>Note that for the following triggers for suppliers the execution of the action cannot be suspended: <codeph>Subscription created (any user)</codeph>, <codeph>Subscription modified (any user)</codeph>, and <codeph>Subscription terminated (any user)</codeph>.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To store the trigger definition, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>You are returned to the <b>Process triggers</b> page, where you can click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> to configure another trigger, or select an existing trigger to update or delete it. </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result><b>To update a trigger definition</b>:<p>
        <ol>
          <li>Change the trigger definition as required. See above for details on the individual fields.<p>If the trigger to be updated has already started corresponding processes in the process control system, you can only change the name for the trigger. You have to abort the corresponding processes before you can update the other elements of the trigger definition.</p>
          </li>
          <li>To store the updated trigger definition, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ol>
      </p><p>You are returned to the <b>Process triggers</b> page, where you can click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> to configure another trigger, or select an existing trigger to update or delete it. </p><p><b>To delete a trigger definition</b>:</p><p>
        <ol>
          <li>Click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Confirm the deletion. </li>
        </ol>
      </p><p>You are returned to the <b>Process triggers</b> page, where you can click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> to configure another trigger, or select an existing trigger to update or delete it. </p></result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="../tasks/triggerProcess_list.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
