<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Adding payment types</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>New payment type</uicontrol> page, you can add the payment types to be available for a supplier or reseller organization. The payment types defined here can later be made available for selection by customers. </p>
      <p><b>To add a payment type</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Payment service provider</uicontrol> list, select the PSP that offers the payment type that you want to assign to the selected supplier or reseller organization. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The list contains all PSPs registered and configured on your platform.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <b>PSP identifier</b> field, enter the identifier or account number for the supplier or reseller as provided by the PSP. </cmd>
        <info>Suppliers and resellers need to have a contractual relationship with the PSP. The PSP configures the channel for a supplier or reseller and issues an identifier, usually an account number, so that payments can be immediately linked to the supplier's or reseller's account.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the types of payment that the selected supplier or reseller may offer to his customers.</cmd>
        <info>Next to <b>Payment</b>, you see the payment types offered by the selected PSP. The available payment types depend on the configuration of the PSP.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To save your entries, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            <note>You can no longer remove a payment type which has been assigned to a supplier or reseller organization.</note>
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>You are returned to the page for managing the organization. </p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
