<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing LDAP settings</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>User IDs and passwords of an organization can be created and maintained in the platform or in an existing LDAP system of the organization.</p>
      <p conref="operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/UserMgmt3"/>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>LDAP settings</uicontrol> page, you can define and manage the LDAP settings for your organization. In doing so, you can overwrite, omit, or add parameters to the default settings defined for the platform by the operator.</p>
      <p>In case you need to modify the LDAP settings, for example, when the connection URL has changed, you can export the current settings to a local configuration file, change the values as required, and import the settings again. Be aware that with this action you will overwrite all existing LDAP settings for your organization.</p>
      <p>When accessing the <uicontrol>LDAP settings</uicontrol> page, the current LDAP settings are listed in a read-only table. You can see which values are based on default platform settings (they apply as long as you do not define organization-specific settings), as well as the currently defined key/value pairs. </p>
      <p><b>To manage LDAP settings</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Create an LDAP configuration file on your file system and define the LDAP connection settings in the file. You can also click <uicontrol>Export</uicontrol> to export the current LDAP settings from the platform to a file. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Check the settings in the file and change them as required. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Here is a sample configuration file: </p>
          <p conref="operator_createOrganization.xml#OrgCreate/LDAPSample"/>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To load the configuration file, click the <uicontrol>File name</uicontrol> field or <uicontrol>Browse</uicontrol>, and select the file containing the settings. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>All existing LDAP settings are replaced by the ones defined in the configuration file. </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Test connection</uicontrol> to make sure that the connection to your LDAP system can be established.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>The LDAP settings are immediately applied for your organization. <p>
        <note>When you provide invalid LDAP connection parameters, you and all users of your organization can no longer log in to the platform. In this case, contact the platform operator and request him to reset your organization's LDAP settings.</note>
      </p></result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="../../Shared/reference/r_LDAP_SettingTypes.xml"/>
      <link href="../tasks/user_import.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
