<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Managing custom attributes</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage custom attributes</uicontrol> page, you can add, update, or delete custom attributes for your customers or for your customer's subscriptions. </p>
      <p id="Custom_attributes_are_useful_task_taskbody_context_p_2"
          >Custom attributes are a means to store additional customer information such as data that is needed for controlling the cost and activity accounting. For example, you may want to specify the profit center to which a particular customer's revenue is to be accounted. Since there is no standard for such data, you can define your own custom attribute for storing the profit center. The custom attributes will be included in the billing data that is generated every month for services applying the native billing system of <ph
          platform="help">the platform</ph><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
          platform="print"
        />. The information can then be used, for example, as a reference for an external accounting, billing, or CRM system.</p>
      <p>When defining custom attributes for subscriptions, you can decide whether you yourself want to specify the attribute value, or whether the customer must enter the value when he subscribes to one of your services. </p>
      <p>When defining custom attributes for customers, you can decide whether you yourself want to specify the attribute value, or whether the customer administrator must enter the value by editing the profile of the customer organization on a marketplace. Custom attributes for customers are always applied to all subscriptions of customers of a specific supplier. For example, credentials for accessing an external account such as OpenStack or Amazon Web Services (AWS) can be set as customer-specific attributes. </p>
      <p>For every custom attribute, you can enter a default value. This value is used as long as no specific value for an individual customer or an individual subscription is entered. If the value of a custom subscription attribute is to be specified by the customer, the corresponding field is preset with the default value during the subscription process. If the customer's administrator or subscription manager changes this value during the subscription process, the new value is automatically applied to all subscriptions of the customer. </p>
      <p>To specify the value of a custom attribute for an individual customer, use the <uicontrol>Manage customer</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu. To specify the value of a custom attribute for an individual subscription, use the <uicontrol>Manage subscription attributes</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> menu.</p>
      <p>Custom attributes are available for customers of your brokers when you grant them the permission to offer and sell your services. Custom attributes are not available for customers of your resellers.</p>
      <p><b>To add custom attributes</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>To add a custom attribute for all your customers, click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Define custom attributes for customers</uicontrol> section. To add a custom attribute for all your subscriptions, click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> in the <uicontrol>Define custom attributes for subscriptions</uicontrol> section.</cmd>
        <info/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>On the <uicontrol>Add custom attribute</uicontrol> page, enter the required data.<ph audience="doc"> Click <xref
            href="createCustomUda.xml">here</xref> for more details.</ph></cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To save your entries, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> on the <uicontrol>Add custom attribute</uicontrol> page.</cmd>
        <info>You are returned to the <uicontrol>Manage custom attributes</uicontrol> page. The new attribute is instantly displayed.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Add</uicontrol> if you want to add an additional attribute. Otherwise, you can leave the page.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p><b>To edit custom attributes</b>:</p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>Click the icon in the <uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> column of the attribute to be edited.</li>
          <li>On the <uicontrol>Edit custom attribute</uicontrol> page, change the data by editing the fields.<ph audience="doc"> Click <xref
              href="updateCustomUda.xml">here</xref> for more details.</ph></li>
          <li>To save your entries, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol> on the <uicontrol>Edit custom attribute</uicontrol> page.<p>You are returned to the <uicontrol>Manage custom attributes</uicontrol> page. The updated definition is instantly displayed. </p></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p><b>To delete custom attributes</b>:</p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>Click the icon in the <uicontrol>Edit </uicontrol> column of the attribute to be deleted.</li>
          <li>On the <uicontrol>Edit custom attribute</uicontrol> page, click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Confirm the deletion.<p>The custom attribute is instantly deleted, and you are returned to the <uicontrol>Manage custom attributes</uicontrol> page.</p></li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="../tasks/organization_editCustomer.xml"/>
      <link href="../tasks/subscription_editUdas.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
