<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Defining a customer price model</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Define for customer</uicontrol> page, you can define or update the price model for a selected service and customer. </p>
      <p>The customer price model you define or update takes priority over the original service price model.<ph audience="doc"> Click <xref
          href="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails.xml">here</xref> for basic information on price models.</ph></p>
      <p>Usually, you change a customer price model only in agreement with the relevant customer. For updating a customer price model, the relevant marketable service must be deactivated. Your changes overwrite the previous values. The update does not affect existing subscriptions. The changes only take effect for new subscriptions of the customer after the service has been activated again. </p>
      <p><b>To define a customer price model</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Customer</uicontrol> list, select the customer for whom you want to define the price model.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The list shows all customers that have subscribed to one of your services and all customers you have registered, irrespective of whether they have subscribed to a service. </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/From_the_task_taskbody_steps_step_1"/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Define the price model in the subsequent sections of the page.<ph audience="doc"> Click <xref
              href="priceModel_customer_nat.xml">here</xref> for details.</ph></cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>After activating the service, the price model is available to the selected customer. It takes effect for all new subscriptions of the customer.</result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="priceModel_customer_delete.xml"/>
      <link href="priceModel_service.xml"/>
      <link href="priceModel_subscription.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
