<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
      <title>Registering</title>
      <taskbody>
            <context>
                  <p>On the <uicontrol>Registration</uicontrol> page, you enter data required for creating your account. </p>
                  <p><uicontrol>To register</uicontrol>:</p>
            </context>
            <steps>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Enter your email address. </cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>This information is mandatory. You are notified by email about the registration. </p>
                              <p>The system checks whether the syntax of the given email address is valid, and whether the domain name corresponds to the standards as defined and maintained by the Internet Assigned Numbers Authority (IANA). </p>
                              <p>Examples: <codeph>user.name@domain.arpa</codeph>, <codeph>user.name@domain.org</codeph>, <codeph>user@mycompany.lan.uk</codeph></p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Specify the data for your user and organization account. </cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>Fields marked with an asterisk (*) are mandatory. </p>
                              <p>
                                    <ul compact="no">
                                          <li><uicontrol>Desired user ID</uicontrol>: ID with which you want to log in to the platform. User IDs are restricted to 100 characters and must not contain any of the following characters:<p><codeph>! " # $ % &amp; ' * + , / : ; &lt; = > ? \ ^ `</codeph>
                                                </p></li>
                                          <li><uicontrol>Password</uicontrol>: Password with which you want to log in to the platform. The minimum length is 6 characters, the maximum length is 100 characters. <p><ph
                                                            id="When_you_type_the_password_t_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                                                            >When you type the password, the <uicontrol>Password strength</uicontrol> field indicates how secure your password is. The color green means that your password is strong and secure. A strong and secure password consists of at least 8 characters, and contains numbers, letters, and special characters.</ph>
                                                </p></li>
                                          <li><uicontrol>Title</uicontrol>: Salutation, such as <codeph>MR</codeph> or <codeph>MS</codeph>
                                          </li>
                                          <li><uicontrol>First name</uicontrol>: Your first name. </li>
                                          <li><uicontrol>Last name</uicontrol>: Your last name.</li>
                                          <li><uicontrol>Organization</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Address</uicontrol>: Name and address of your organization. </li>
                                    </ul>
                              </p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Country</uicontrol> where your organization is located. </cmd>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Enter the characters as visible in the <uicontrol>Word verification</uicontrol> area. Be aware that the characters are case-sensitive.</cmd>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Read the terms and conditions as well as the privacy policy and accept them by selecting the corresponding check box.</cmd>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>To confirm your registration, click <uicontrol>Register</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                        <stepresult>
                              <p>You are sent an email with the URL for completing the registration process and confirming the creation of your account.</p>
                        </stepresult>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>To confirm your account, click the URL in the confirmation email.</cmd>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>On the <uicontrol>Registration</uicontrol> page, click <uicontrol>Continue</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                        <stepresult>
                              <p>The <uicontrol>Login</uicontrol> page is displayed and you can log in with the user ID and password you specified. </p>
                              <p>In addition, you are sent an email with the URL for accessing your account. You can use it for future logins.</p>
                        </stepresult>
                  </step>
            </steps>
            <result>
                  <p>After registering, you are automatically assigned the administrator role for your organization. This role provides you with the privileges required to manage your organization and its users and subscriptions. </p>
            </result>
      </taskbody>
      <related-links>
            <linklist>
                  <title>Related topics</title>
                  <link href="../tasks/public_login.xml"/>
            </linklist>
      </related-links>
</task>
