<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
      <title>Logging in</title>
      <taskbody>
            <context>
                  <p audience="int"><i>This help text is only accessible via hyperlinks from other help texts.</i></p>
                  <p>On the <uicontrol>Login</uicontrol> page, you log in in with your personal login data. To reach the <uicontrol>Login</uicontrol> page, you type the access URL in your Web browser's address bar, choose a corresponding bookmark, or click the link provided in the email with your login data you have received.</p>
                  <p><b>To log in</b>:</p>
            </context>
            <steps>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Type your user ID and password.</cmd>
                        <info/>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Login</uicontrol> or press <uicontrol>Return</uicontrol>. </cmd>
                        <stepresult>
                              <p><ph id="You_are_either_logged_in_dire_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                                          >You are either logged in directly, or you are prompted to change your initial password when you log in for the first time. It is highly recommended to change the initial password.</ph></p>
                        </stepresult>
                  </step>
            </steps>
            <result>
                  <p><ph id="If_you_try_to_log_in_with_a_w_task_taskbody_result_p_1_ph"
                              >If you try to log in with a wrong password, your account may be locked after the third attempt. This depends on whether your organization maintains its user data in an external authentication system. In this case, passwords can only be changed or reset in this system. If user data are maintained in the platform, contact your administrator who can reset your password. You will get a new temporary password for your next login.</ph></p>
                  <p><ph id="If_you_have_forgotten_your_pa_task_taskbody_result_p_2_ph"
                                    >If you have forgotten your password, click <uicontrol>Forgot your password?</uicontrol> on the <uicontrol>Login</uicontrol> page. This allows you to define a new password for your user ID. Defining a new password is not possible if your account is locked or if your organization maintains its user data in an external authentication system.</ph></p>
                  <p id="If_you_have_forgotten_your_us_task_taskbody_result_p_3"><ph
                              id="If_you_have_forgotten_the_dat_task_taskbody_result_p_2_ph"
                              >If you have forgotten your user ID, contact your administrator who can look up the IDs of all users registered for your organization.</ph></p>
                  <p><ph id="If_your_session_expires_you_task_taskbody_result_p_3_ph"
                              >If your session expires, you have to log in again.</ph></p>
            </result>
      </taskbody>
      <related-links>
            <linklist>
                  <title>Related topics</title>
                  <link href="../tasks/public_registration.xml"/>
                  <link href="../tasks/user_pwd.xml"/>
            </linklist>
      </related-links>
</task>
