<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd">
<reference id="reference832" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Viewing price model details </title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>On the <uicontrol>View service</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>Manage service</uicontrol> page, you can view the following details of the charging conditions and prices for using the service if it is not free of charge. All prices are without VAT.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Charging conditions</title>
            <p>The charging conditions include the following information:</p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>
                    <p id="For_each_subscription_a_char_reference_refbody_section_1"><b>Calculation option</b>: The cost calculation option for the price model:<ul>
                            <li><uicontrol>Free of charge</uicontrol>: The service is free of charge. </li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Pro rata calculation</uicontrol>: The costs are calculated based on the exact usage of the service in milliseconds.</li>
                            <li><uicontrol>Per time unit calculation</uicontrol>: The costs are calculated for complete time units, for example, whole days or weeks. The time unit is defined under <uicontrol>Charges based on</uicontrol>.</li>
                        </ul></p>
                </li>
                <li><b>Free trial period (in days)</b>: The number of days during which the service can be used for free. <ph
                        conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/After_this_period_the_servic_task_taskbody_steps_step_4"
                    /></li>
                <li conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/Currency_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"/>
                <li conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/Charges_based_on_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"/>
                <li conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/One-time_fee_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"/>
                <li
                    conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/Recurring_charge_per_subscrip_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"/>
                <li><ph
                        conref="../../Shared/priceModel.xml#PriceModelTopic/Recurring_charge_per_user_task_taskbody_steps_step_5"
                    /></li>
            </ul>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Event prices</title>
            <p>Event prices refer to individual, billable events. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_events.xml#reference832/These_include_for_example_l_reference_refbody_section_1"
                />
            </p>
            <p>For this type of charge, stepped prices can be defined granting the customer, for example, discounts depending on the number of events that occurred while using the service.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Parameter prices</title>
            <p>A price model can define prices for service parameters and options. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/It_depends_on_the_implementat_reference_refbody_section_1"
                    /> The supplier can define a price for every parameter and option, and specify whether this price is to be charged per subscription or per user assigned to the subscription. Numeric parameters are a multiplier for the price. For boolean parameters, the multiplier is <codeph>1</codeph> if the value is <codeph>true</codeph>. In all other cases, the multiplier is <codeph>0</codeph>.</p>
            <p>For numeric parameters (parameters with values of type Integer or Long), stepped prices can be defined granting the customer, for example, volume discounts.</p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Role-specific prices</title>
            <p>A price model can define a price for each service role that is defined. This price is added to the base price per user in the cost calculation for a billing period.</p>
            <p>The service roles must have been specified in the technical service definition. Service roles can be mapped to corresponding permissions in the underlying application. </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
