<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Activating or deactivating services</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Activate or deactivate services</uicontrol> page, you can activate or deactivate marketable services. If you are logged in as a supplier, the page lists all services you have defined. If you are logged in as a broker or reseller, the page lists all services you are authorized to offer.</p>
      <p>If a service is activated, it is available for subscription to customers. If a service is deactivated, it is not available to customers and the supplier can change its definition and price model. Existing subscriptions to the service are not affected by a deactivation.</p>
      <p>The following prerequisites must be fulfilled for activating a marketable service: </p>
      <ul>
        <li>The marketplace to which the service is to be published must have been specified.</li>
        <li>A price model must have been defined for the service.</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        <note>If you want to check what your activated service looks like on the marketplace, make sure that you belong to an organizational unit which has access to the service. If you do not see the published service on the marketplace, contact your administrator who is responsible for making services accessible to organizational units.</note>
      </p>
      <p><b>To activate or deactivate a service</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select or clear the check box in the <uicontrol>Active</uicontrol> column next to the service you want to activate or deactivate.</cmd>
        <info/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Decide whether an activated service is to be displayed in the service catalog on the marketplace.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>If you activate multiple marketable services which are based on the same technical service, you can decide to display only a subset of them in the service catalog. At least one service of such a set of services must be displayed in the catalog. A service that is not displayed is offered to customers as soon as they request details of a related service. Requesting details displays all editions of a service, i.e. a complete list of the marketable services that are based on the same technical service. </p>
          <p>To display a service in the service catalog, select the check box in the <uicontrol>In catalog</uicontrol> column. Clear the check box for removing the service from the service catalog. By default, the check box is selected for all services.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <note>The marketplace owner is allowed to deactivate a service you have activated, for example, if you are in arrears with your payments. An email from the marketplace owner informs you about the reason for a deactivation. As soon as the problem is solved, the marketplace owner can reactivate the service.<p>For a service that has been deactivated by the marketplace owner, the check box in the <uicontrol>Active</uicontrol> column is hidden. It is displayed again as soon as the marketplace owner reactivates the service. </p></note>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="service_edit.xml"/>
      <link href="priceModel_service.xml"/>
      <link href="service_publish.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
