<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2019 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Defining publishing options</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Define publishing options</uicontrol> page, the following tasks can be performed: </p>
      <p>
        <ul compact="no">
          <li>Define or change the marketplace to which a service is to be published. Specifying the marketplace is a prerequisite for activating the service.<p>As a prerequisite for changing the marketplace, the service must be deactivated. Existing subscriptions of customers on the original marketplace are not affected. </p></li>
          <li>Grant brokers or resellers the permission to sell a service or revoke such a permission. This can be done by suppliers only.<p>As a prerequisite for granting the permission, the price model and the marketplace must be defined.</p><p>If you grant the permission for a service, the broker or reseller can publish the service to a marketplace of his choice. If you revoke the permission for a service, the service is instantly withdrawn from the marketplace to which it was published by the broker or reseller. Customers can no longer subscribe to it, yet existing subscriptions of the broker's or reseller's customers are not affected.</p></li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p><b>To define or change the marketplace for a service</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol> list, select the service for which you want to define or change the marketplace.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>If you are a supplier, the list contains all services you have defined. You can view the agreed revenue share the platform operator is to receive when you, a broker or reseller sells the selected service. </p>
          <p>If you are a broker or reseller, the list contains all services you are authorized to offer.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Define the marketplace options in the <uicontrol>Define the marketplace options</uicontrol> section:</cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li>Specify whether the service is to be public. By default, the <uicontrol>Public service</uicontrol> check box is selected. <p><ph
                  id="A_public_service_is_visible_i_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                  >A public service is visible in the service catalog for anybody accessing the marketplace. A service that has not been marked as public is available for subscription to registered customers only.</ph></p></li>
            <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace to which the service is to be published. You can publish the service to any marketplace to which you have been granted access and admitted as a seller by the marketplace owner.<p>As a broker or reseller, you can view the revenue share that is applicable to your organization. As a supplier, you can view the revenue shares that are defined for the operator, the marketplace owner and for brokers and resellers.</p><p><ph
                  id="Provided_that_categories_are_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                  >Provided that categories are defined for the marketplace you select, you can assign one or multiple categories to your service. The marketplace owner is responsible for creating the categories you can choose from. Customers can use the categories for browsing the service catalog and filtering the services on the marketplace. The marketplace owner may also decide to display the services on the marketplace home page grouped by categories.</ph></p></li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>The options are instantly applied. You can now activate the service to make it available for subscription to customers on the selected marketplace.</p>
      <p><b>To grant or revoke the resale permission for a service</b> (suppliers only):</p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>From the <uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol> list, select the service for which you want to grant or revoke the resale permission.<p>The list contains all services you have defined.</p></li>
          <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select a marketplace for which the operator has defined the appropriate revenue shares based on your agreed conditions with the operator, marketplace owner, resellers, and brokers. <p>These defaults apply to all brokers and resellers you grant a resale permission, unless a service-specific or organization-specific revenue share is defined. Be aware that this is irrespective of the marketplace to which the brokers or resellers are going to publish the service.</p><p>Below the default revenue shares, all broker and reseller organizations managed on the platform are displayed with their applicable revenue shares. </p></li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Select the reseller and broker organizations</uicontrol> section, select or clear the check box in the first column next to a broker or reseller to grant or revoke the resale permission. </li>
          <li>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
      <p>The resale permission is instantly granted or revoked. </p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="service_activation.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
