<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Updating a service</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Update service</uicontrol> page, you can change all elements of a marketable service definition except for the technical service on which the marketable service is based. Updating a service also allows you to provide the service name for customers, the short description, the description, and the name of the custom tab in different languages.</p>
      <p>You can only update a service that is deactivated. Existing subscriptions of your customers are not affected by the update. Any changes you make are effective for new subscriptions only. To provide the service to customers for subscription, you must activate it.</p>
      <p>If you have granted resale permissions, the brokers and resellers as well as their customers can immediately view any changes you make to the service definition, even if you have not yet activated your service. Existing subscriptions to services are not affected by the update. Any changes you make are effective for new subscriptions only.</p>
      <p><b>To change the elements and properties of a service definition</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol> list, select the marketable service you want to change.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The list contains all services you have defined.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>You can change the following elements and properties: </cmd>
        <info>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li><uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol>: Identifier of the service. It must be unique within the marketable services of your organization.<p><ph
                  conref="service_add.xml#task634/This_field_is_mandatory._The_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/></p><p><ph
                  conref="service_add.xml#task634/3"/></p><p><ph conref="service_add.xml#task634/2"/></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Service image</uicontrol>: File containing the image for identifying the service. <p>Click <ph
                  conref="service_add.xml#task634/either_the_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/></p><p><ph
                  conref="service_add.xml#task634/The_service_image_is_shown_in_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Service name for customers</uicontrol>: Meaningful name for the service. It should have a high recognition value for customers. <p><ph
                  conref="service_add.xml#task634/The_service_name_for_customer_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Short description</uicontrol>: Brief description of the service. <ph
                conref="service_add.xml#task634/The_length_of_the_short_descr_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"/>
              <p><ph conref="service_add.xml#task634/The_short_description_is_show_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
              /></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Description</uicontrol>: Detailed description of the features offered by the service.<p>The service description is displayed on a marketplace when customers request details of the service. </p><p>
                <note><ph conref="service_add.xml#task634/Make_sure_to_use_only_the_con_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                  /></note>
              </p></li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>By selecting or deselecting <uicontrol>Auto-assign the subscribing user</uicontrol>, you can determine whether a user subscribing to this service is automatically assigned to the subscription after having completed the subscription process.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Service parameters</uicontrol> table, you can change the subscription and usage parameters for the service by editing the values in the <uicontrol>Value</uicontrol> column. The value must be within the range defined for the technical service.</cmd>
        <info>By selecting the <uicontrol>User option</uicontrol> check box for a parameter you can specify whether it is offered as an option to customers who subscribe to the service.</info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Optionally, specify or change the <b>URL of a parameter configuration tool</b>. In this way, you can link an external tool of your choice. Your customers can use this tool for configuring the subscription and usage parameters when they subscribe to the service.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>If an external tool is used, the <uicontrol>Service parameters</uicontrol> table for configuring the parameters is replaced by the tool's interface during the subscription process. <note
              conref="service_add.xml#task634/Make_sure_that_the_URL_pointi_task_taskbody_steps_step_6"/></p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Optionally, specify or change the <b>URL of a custom tab</b>. In this way, you can add a tab to the <b>Details</b> view for subscriptions on the marketplace. This URL may point to a Web page or Web application the content of which will be retrieved and shown on the custom tab. Particularly users of IaaS services may be interested in additional details on the service and the operation of the service they subscribed to. Using a custom tab, you can provide the information needed for accessing provisioned instances, such as IP addresses, network information, or user credentials.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            <note>Make sure that the URL pointing to the Web page or Web application for the custom tab is secure. The URL is not validated by the platform, neither for syntax nor for semantic.</note>
          </p>
          <p>Predefined custom tabs are available for viewing details on subscriptions to an IaaS service such as OpenStack or Amazon Web Services (AWS). On the custom tab, the booked Virtual Machines (VMs) are listed with the following information: </p>
          <p>
            <ul>
              <li>Header with the name of the subscription</li>
              <li>Access information</li>
              <li>For each booked VM: <p>
                  <ul>
                    <li>Instance name</li>
                    <li>Instance ID </li>
                    <li>Instance type </li>
                    <li>Instance status </li>
                    <li>Public IP address</li>
                    <li>Private IP addresses</li>
                  </ul>
                </p></li>
            </ul>
          </p>
          <p>You can set the URL for accessing the custom tab in the following format: </p>
          <p><codeph>https://&lt;app-host-name>:8881/&lt;service controller name>/serverInformation.jsf</codeph></p>
          <p>For example: </p>
          <p><codeph>https://MyAPPHost:8881/oscm-app-openstack/serverInformation.jsf</codeph></p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Optionally, specify or change the <b>Name of the custom tab</b> as shown to your customers. The name is restricted to 40 alphanumeric characters and must not contain special characters.</cmd>
        <info/>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To provide the service name for customers, the short description, the description, and the custom tab name in another language, click <uicontrol>Localize</uicontrol>. The <uicontrol>Localize service</uicontrol> page allows you to provide the elements describing the service name in all supported languages.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>After activating the service, the changes are made available to your customers for new subscriptions. Brokers and resellers as well as their customers can immediately view your changes.</p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="service_localize.xml"/>
      <link href="priceModel_service.xml"/>
      <link href="service_publish.xml"/>
      <link href="service_activation.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
