<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Managing a service</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>On the <uicontrol>Manage service</uicontrol> page, you can view and update the details of the services which you are authorized to sell.</p>
            <p>The following information on a service is available:</p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>The service name and short description which are shown in the service catalog on a marketplace when you activate the service.</li>
                <li>The service description which offers details of the features offered by the service. It is displayed on a marketplace when customers request details of the service.</li>
                <li>The license agreement which must be read and accepted by customers when they subscribe to the service.</li>
                <li>The service can be free of charge or with costs. If customers are charged for using the service, the charging conditions and prices are shown.<ph
                        audience="doc"> Click <xref href="service_viewPMDetails.xml"
                    >here</xref> for more details.</ph> All prices are without VAT. </li>
            </ul>
            <p>The information can only be viewed, except for the license agreement. You can update the text for your customers, if required. As a prerequisite, the service must be deactivated. Existing subscriptions of your customers are not affected by the update. Any changes you make are effective for new subscriptions only. To provide the service to customers for subscription, you must activate it.</p>
            <p><b>To view and update the details of a service</b>:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Service ID</uicontrol> list, select the service for which to view or update the details.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The list contains all services you are authorized to sell.</p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>In the <uicontrol>License agreement</uicontrol> field, update the license agreement text for the service, if required. The field is initially preset with the license agreement as defined by the supplier of the service. It is up to you whether you use this license agreement or specify a different one. </cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>
                        <note><ph id="Make_sure_to_use_only_the_con_task_taskbody_steps_step_2"
                                >Make sure to use only the controls provided in the editor for formatting your text. Manually entered HTML tags and references to external style sheets or content may result in errors in the page layout.</ph></note>
                    </p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
                <info>The text is stored in the language defined by your user profile.</info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To provide the license agreement in another language, change the language in which you currently work to the required language in your user profile using the <uicontrol>Edit profile</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> menu. You can then enter the corresponding translations.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>The service is displayed with the updated definition. </p>
            <p>To make the service available for subscription to customers, you must first specify the marketplace to which you want to publish it. You can then activate the service.</p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
    <related-links>
        <linklist>
            <title>Related topics</title>
            <link href="organization_edit.xml"/>
            <link href="service_publish.xml"/>
            <link href="service_activation.xml"/>
        </linklist>
    </related-links>
</task>
