<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
      <title>Customizing the marketplace stage</title>
      <taskbody>
            <context>
                  <p>On the <uicontrol>Customize stage</uicontrol> page, you can customize the area of the marketplace home page where you can place, for example, advertisements, eye catchers, or further information.</p>
                  <p>The marketplace stage can be provided as an image or as HTML code linking, for example, to animations. A separate stage can be used for each of the supported languages. A preview function allows you to view the stage before it is published. As soon as you confirm the preview, the stage is published and visible to all visitors of the marketplace.</p>
                  <p>The branding of a marketplace also comprises its layout (colors, fonts, background images, logos, etc.) and the texts (labels of user interface elements, email message texts, etc.). The layout can be customized using the <uicontrol>Customize layout</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu. The texts can be customized using the <uicontrol>Customize texts</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu.</p>
                  <p><b>To customize the marketplace stage</b>:</p>
            </context>
            <steps>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace for which you want to customize the stage.</cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>The list contains all marketplaces to which you have access as a marketplace manager.</p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Select the <uicontrol>Language</uicontrol> for which you want to provide a customized stage. </cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>You can provide a stage for all supported languages.</p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Enter the HTML code referencing the desired image. If you do not specify an image for a certain language, the stage of the default language is used. If there is no customized stage for the default language either, the default image as available after installation of the platform is used.</cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>The recommended width of the stage is 100%, the recommended height is between 200 and 300 pixels. </p>
                              <p>Example: <codeph>&lt;IFRAME FRAMEBORDER\="0" SRC\="yourstage.htm" NAME\="stage" WIDTH\="100%" HEIGHT\="280px" SCROLLING\="no">&lt;/IFRAME></codeph>
                              </p>
                              <p>You can enter the HTML code directly, or you can use an inline frame for embedding the stage in the HTML code of the marketplace home page.</p>
                              <p><b>Caution</b>: It is recommended that you use an inline frame. If you do not use an inline frame, specify only snippets as HTML code. Do not use a fully featured HTML page that contains elements like <codeph>&lt;html&gt;</codeph>, <codeph>&lt;head&gt;</codeph>, or <codeph>&lt;body&gt;</codeph>. Check the page layout with the preview function (see next step below). A snippet may break the layout of the marketplace home page, the preview dialog, or even the <uicontrol>Customize stage</uicontrol> page, especially if the snippet contains scripts (e.g. JavaScripts). </p>
                              <p>Be aware that you are responsible for a correct page layout.</p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Preview</uicontrol> to view the changed marketplace home page. </cmd>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>If you have reached the desired result, confirm the publishing of the new marketplace home page by clicking <uicontrol>Yes</uicontrol>. The new stage is visible to visitors the next time they access your marketplace.</cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>By clicking <uicontrol>No</uicontrol>, you return to the <uicontrol>Customize stage</uicontrol> page and can make additional changes. The existing stage is not changed. </p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
            </steps>
      </taskbody>
      <related-links>
            <linklist>
                  <title>Related topics</title>
                  <link href="shop_customizeBrand.xml"/>
                  <link href="shop_translations.xml"/>
            </linklist>
      </related-links>
</task>
