<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
      <title>Adding tracking code</title>
      <taskbody>
            <context>
                  <p>On the <uicontrol>Add tracking code</uicontrol> page, you can add or remove tracking code to or from your marketplace Web pages. </p>
                  <p>Tracking code allows you to monitor the marketplace traffic by measuring the frequency in which the marketplace is accessed by visitors. You are free to choose your preferred Web analytics software. The menu option enables you to insert the desired HTML code for tracking the access into each marketplace Web page. When a page is loaded, the tracking script is executed and you can evaluate the analytics data.</p>
                  <p id="To_add_tracking_code_task_taskbody_context_p_2"><b>To add tracking code</b>:</p>
            </context>
            <steps>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace to which you want to add tracking code.</cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p>The list contains all marketplaces to which you have access as a marketplace manager.</p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>Enter the HTML code. You can use snippets of JavaScript code, if required.</cmd>
                        <info>
                              <p><b>Caution</b>: The code may break the layout of your marketplace pages, and the layout changes may invalidate a customized branding of your marketplace.</p>
                              <p>Be aware that you are responsible for a correct page layout.</p>
                        </info>
                  </step>
                  <step>
                        <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>. </cmd>
                  </step>
            </steps>
            <result>
                  <p>The code is added to all pages of your marketplace. The change takes effect the next time you log in to the marketplace or refresh your Web browser.</p>
                  <p><b>To remove tracking code</b>:</p>
                  <p>
                        <ol compact="no">
                              <li>From the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> list, select the marketplace from which to remove the tracking code. <p>The list contains all marketplaces to which you have access as a marketplace manager.</p></li>
                              <li>Remove the HTML code.</li>
                              <li>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</li>
                        </ol>
                  </p>
                  <p>The code is removed from the pages of your marketplace. The change takes effect the next time you log in to the marketplace or refresh your Web browser.</p>
            </result>
      </taskbody>
</task>
