<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2020 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Terminating a subscription</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Terminate subscription</uicontrol> page, you can explicitly terminate a customer's subscription. <ph
          id="This_may_be_required_for_exa_task_taskbody_context_p_1_ph"
          >This may be required, for example, if a customer does not comply with a license agreement or does not pay for a subscription. Terminating a subscription is possible even if users are currently using the underlying service.</ph></p>
      <p><b>To terminate a subscription</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the list in the upper page area, select the subscription to be terminated. You can select any active subscription to your services. The subscriptions of your direct customers and your broker's customers are included.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The details of the selected subscription are shown in the lower page area.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Reason</uicontrol> field, explain why you terminate the subscription. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>As soon as the subscription is terminated, this text is sent to the customer's administrators and, if applicable, the responsible OU administrators or subscription manager.  </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Click <uicontrol>Terminate</uicontrol>. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Confirm the termination.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p>The subscription is instantly terminated. The customer's administrators and, if applicable, the subscription manager or OU administrator owning the subscription are sent an email informing them about the termination and the reason you have entered. Any users assigned to the subscription can no longer use it. </p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
