<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Registering a service definition</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Register service definition</uicontrol> page, you can define the basic features for a technical service that you want to provide. You can select the access type and specify the information required for users to access the service. </p>
      <p>A more flexible but also more complex way is to create an XML file containing the technical service definition and to import this file. If you want to specify or change parameters, options, or events of a technical service, proceed as follows: </p>
      <ol compact="no">
        <li>Export the service definition.</li>
        <li>Edit the XML definition file.</li>
        <li>Import the service definition again. </li>
      </ol>
      <p>For details on service access types and the technical service definition, refer to the <i>Technology Provider's Guide</i>. </p>
      <p audience="none"
        >You can register a service definition if you have the technology manager user role, and your organization is registered as a technology provider.</p>
      <p><b>To register a technical service definition</b>:</p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>Enter a name for your service in the <uicontrol>Technical service name</uicontrol> field. </cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The technical service name is restricted to 40 characters and must not contain any of the following characters:</p>
          <p><codeph>! " # $ % &amp; ' * + , / : ; &lt; = &gt; ? \ ^ `</codeph></p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <!--<step><cmd>Select the billing system for the technical service you want to register. The billing system is used for calculating the charges for subscriptions to services that are based on the technical service.</cmd><info><p>Your operator is responsible for setting up the available billing systems. The default billing system is the platform's billing system: <codeph>NATIVE_BILLING</codeph>.</p></info></step>-->
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the access type for the technical service you want to register. The access type determines:</cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <ul>
            <li>Whether your application uses the platform for user authentication, and the platform forwards login information to your application (<b>application login</b>).</li>
            <li>Whether your application needs to implement a <b>provisioning service</b>.</li>
          </ul>
          <p>Depending on the access type you select, different entry fields are displayed.</p>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Enter the required information in the relevant entry fields: </cmd>
        <stepresult>
          <ul compact="no">
            <li><uicontrol>Service URL</uicontrol> (login and external access only): URL of the remote interface of your application. Users are forwarded to this URL for service access. Your application should provide some default content for the <uicontrol>Service URL</uicontrol>, since this URL specifies the application's remote interface if a user is already logged in at the platform. <p>The Service URL corresponds to the <codeph>baseUrl</codeph> attribute in the technical service definition XML file. </p><p>Be aware that internet domain names must follow the following rules: <ul>
                  <li>
                    <p>They must start with a letter and end with a letter or number.</p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                    <p>They may contain letters, numbers, or hyphens only. Special characters are not allowed. </p>
                  </li>
                  <li>
                    <p>They may consist of a maximum of 63 characters.</p>
                  </li>
                </ul></p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Provisioning service URL</uicontrol> (all access types except external access): URL of the WSDL document that defines the provisioning service you implemented for your application.<p>The Provisioning service URL corresponds to the <codeph>provisioningUrl</codeph> attribute in the technical service definition XML file. </p></li>
            <li><uicontrol>Login path</uicontrol> (login access only): Path to the token handler, a module of your application that handles login requests containing a user token. The path must be relative to the URL specified as the <uicontrol>Service URL</uicontrol> and start with a slash /. <p>The Login path corresponds to the <codeph>loginPath</codeph> attribute in the technical service definition XML file. </p></li>
          </ul>
        </stepresult>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>To register the service definition, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>The service is added to the list of available services. In a next step, enter detailed descriptive texts and license information on the <uicontrol>Update service definition</uicontrol> page. Then appoint one or more suppliers for the technical service so that marketable services can be defined based on it. </result>
  </taskbody>
  <related-links>
    <linklist>
      <title>Related topics</title>
      <link href="techService_edit.xml"/>
      <link href="techService_export.xml"/>
      <link href="techService_import.xml"/>
      <link href="organization_manageSuppliers.xml"/>
    </linklist>
  </related-links>
</task>
