<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Editing a custom attribute</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>On the <uicontrol>Edit custom attribute</uicontrol> page, you can edit or delete a selected custom attribute.</p>
            <p><b>To edit the custom attribute</b>:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Change the data by editing the fields.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <ul compact="no">
                        <li><uicontrol>Attribute ID</uicontrol>: Identifier or name for the attribute. Attribute IDs are restricted to 40 characters and must not contain any of the following characters: <codeph>! " # $ % &amp; ' * + , / : ; &lt; &gt; \ ^ `</codeph></li>
                        <li><b>Attribute name</b> and <b>Language</b>: Name of the custom attribute in the selected language in which it is offered to the customer.</li>
                        <li><uicontrol>Default value</uicontrol>: Default value of the attribute. The default value is restricted to 255 characters. It is used as long as no specific value for an individual customer or an individual subscription is entered. If the value is to be specified by the customer, the corresponding field is preset with this default value during the subscription process.</li>
                        <li><uicontrol>User option</uicontrol>: Check box to be selected if the attribute is to be offered to a customer's administrator or subscription manager when he subscribes to one of your services. This allows the administrator or subscription manager to enter the value for the attribute.</li>
                        <li><uicontrol>Mandatory</uicontrol>: Check box to be selected if you want to make the field for the attribute value mandatory for the customer's administrator or subscription manager.</li>
                        <li><b>Controller ID</b>: ID of the service controller used to offer IaaS services, for example OpenStack or Amazon Web Services (AWS).</li>
                        <li><b>Encrypted</b>: Check box to be selected if the attribute's value is to be encrypted when stored in the database, as well as in log files and reports. In addition, any value the customer administrator enters in a field for an encrypted attribute will be hidden. If the check box is already selected, you can no longer change this setting.</li>
                    </ul>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To save your changes, click <uicontrol>Save</uicontrol>.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>You are returned to the page for managing custom attributes. The updated definition of the custom attribute is instantly displayed.</p>
            <p>An updated attribute name or an updated default value will be included in the billing data for customers the next time the data is generated. If no value is specified for an attribute, the attribute name will be inserted into the billing data without a value.</p>
            <p><b>To delete the custom attribute</b>:</p>
            <ul compact="no">
                <li>Click <uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> and confirm the deletion. </li>
            </ul>
            <p>The custom attribute is instantly deleted, and you are returned to the <uicontrol>Manage custom attributes</uicontrol> page. The attribute will no longer be included in the billing data for a customer the next time the data is generated.</p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
    <related-links>
        <linklist>
            <title>Related topics</title>
            <link href="organization_manageUdas.xml"/>
        </linklist>
    </related-links>
</task>
