<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd" >
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Importing users</title>
    <taskbody>
        <context>
            <p>On the <uicontrol>Import users</uicontrol> page, you can import users from an external LDAP system and thus register them. In addition, you can define their user roles. The LDAP system is used for authenticating the users when they log in. </p>
            <p>Upon creation or registration of your organization, LDAP-based authentication must have been specified and LDAP connection settings must have been defined.</p>
            <p>The role of your organization determines which roles can be assigned to the users. The user roles control the actions a user is allowed to execute:<ul
                    compact="no">
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Standard_user_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                            /> Every user registered with the platform automatically is a standard user. <ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Additional_user_roles_must_be_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Administrator_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Subscription_manager_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Technology_manager_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Service_manager_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Reseller_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Broker_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_OrgsRoles.xml#concept2311/Marketplace_manager_concept_conbody_section_p_4"
                        /></li>
                </ul></p>
            <p><b>To import users from an external LDAP system</b>:</p>
        </context>
        <steps>
            <step>
                <cmd>Identify the users you want to import.</cmd>
                <info/>
                <stepresult>You can use the following filter criteria: <p>
                        <ul compact="no">
                            <li>Wildcard (*): All users existing in the LDAP system are listed. Be aware that a maximum of 100 users can be listed. Use more specific filter criteria, if necessary, for example, the starting character of user IDs together with a wildcard. </li>
                            <li>Characters and wildcards (*): All users are listed whose user ID matches the specified characters. For example, if you enter <codeph>*o*</codeph>, all users whose user ID contains the character <codeph>o</codeph> are listed. </li>
                            <li>User ID: To import one specific user, enter his ID directly. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p><p>To list all users matching the filter criteria, click <uicontrol>Search</uicontrol>.</p></stepresult>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Select the check boxes for the users you want to import. </cmd>
                <info>If the LDAP attribute from which the email address of a user is read is not mapped to a corresponding value, you have to enter the email addresses of the respective users manually. </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>Assign the required role to the user by selecting the corresponding check box.</cmd>
                <info>
                    <p>The available user roles depend on the role of your organization. If you do not select any check box, the user is automatically assigned the role of a standard user. </p>
                </info>
            </step>
            <step>
                <cmd>To start the import, click <uicontrol>Import</uicontrol>.</cmd>
            </step>
        </steps>
        <result>
            <p>The selected users are imported and registered. After a successful import and registration, the users are sent an email with the URL for accessing the system. They are automatically added to your organization's default organizational unit. The default organizational unit contains all users currently registered for your organization.</p>
            <p>If the user ID of a user to be imported already exists in the platform, the email address of this user (e.g. <codeph>userSmith@organization.com</codeph>) is used as user ID for logging in to the system. If yet another user with the same ID is imported, the new user ID is constructed using the existing ID followed by the "at" sign (@) and the ID of the organization the user belongs to (e.g. <codeph>userSmith@abcdefg</codeph>). The user is sent an email with the respective user ID.</p>
            <p>User data maintained in the external LDAP system such as the password, first name, or last name can only be changed in the external LDAP system. If the data is changed, the platform automatically synchronizes it. Be aware that an automatic synchronization is not possible in case a user ID is changed in the LDAP system. The user has to be imported again.</p>
        </result>
    </taskbody>
    <related-links>
        <linklist>
            <title>Related topics</title>
            <link href="organization_addCustomer.xml"/>
            <link href="user_add.xml"/>
        </linklist>
    </related-links>
</task>
