<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE task PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Task//EN"
                      "task.dtd">
<task id="task634" xml:lang="en-us">
  <title>Exporting billing data</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>On the <uicontrol>Export billing data</uicontrol> page, the following tasks can be performed: </p>
      <ul compact="no">
        <li>
          <p>Export the billing data for one or several customers for a specific time frame. This can be done by resellers or suppliers.</p>
          <p>You can use the exported data as the basis for creating invoices for your customers.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>As a reseller, broker, marketplace owner, or supplier: Export the revenue share data for your organization for a specific time frame. </p>
          <p>As a platform operator: Export the revenue share data for all organizations with a specific role for a specific time frame. </p>
          <p>You can use the exported data as the basis for collecting or paying your shares, depending on your contracts with the other participating parties.</p>
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p>The exported data can be saved to an XML file or opened in an editor of your choice. You can edit the data and work with it as required. For example, you can forward the data to an accounting system.</p>
      <note>
        <p><ph id="For_a_detailed_description_of_task_taskbody_context_note_p">Refer to <xref
              href="../../DevelopersGuide/Reference/r_BillingData.xml"
            /> for a detailed description of the elements and attributes that may occur in the generated XML file.</ph></p>
      </note>
      <p><b>To export billing data for customers</b> (suppliers and resellers): </p>
    </context>
    <steps>
      <step>
        <cmd>In the <uicontrol>Billing data type</uicontrol> field, select <uicontrol>Customer billing data</uicontrol>.</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>The field lists all customer organizations that you have created or that have subscribed to at least one of your services. </p>
          <p>If you are logged in as a supplier, the field also lists your brokers' customers who have subscribed to one of your services.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Select the check boxes of the customers whose billing data you want to export. </cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Specify the start and end date of the time frame for which you want to export the data by clicking the <uicontrol>From</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>To</uicontrol> field and selecting the date in the calendar that is provided.</cmd>
      </step>
      <step>
        <cmd>Choose whether to save the data to a file (<codeph>&lt;date&gt;BillingData.xml</codeph>) or to view it instantly in an editor of your choice.</cmd>
      </step>
    </steps>
    <result>
      <p><b>To export revenue share data for organizations</b> :</p>
      <p>
        <ol compact="no">
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Billing data type</uicontrol> field, select <uicontrol>Revenue share data</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>In the <uicontrol>Organization role</uicontrol> field, select the organization role for which to export the revenue share data. Depending on the roles assigned to your organization, you can select <uicontrol>Supplier</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Broker</uicontrol>, <uicontrol>Reseller</uicontrol>, or <uicontrol>Marketplace owner</uicontrol>.</li>
          <li>Specify the start and end date of the time frame for which you want to export the data by clicking the <uicontrol>From</uicontrol> and <uicontrol>To</uicontrol> field and selecting the date in the calendar that is provided.</li>
          <li>Choose whether to save the data to a file (<codeph>&lt;date&gt;BillingData.xml</codeph>) or to view it instantly in an editor of your choice.</li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </result>
  </taskbody>
</task>
