<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2017 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<concept id="concept_3413BBD173324104B42FB714974CABE7" xml:lang="en-us">
            <title>Managing Billing and Payment</title>
            <conbody>
                        <section>
                                    <p>As a marketplace owner, you usually receive a share of the revenue for the services offered on your marketplace. <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> provides the means to define this revenue share and calculate the actual amounts from the service usage fees.</p>
                                    <p>The operator is responsible for defining the revenue share you are entitled to receive when he creates your marketplace. If required, the operator can change the revenue share later. You are not authorized to change the revenue share yourself.</p>
                                    <p><ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> offers the following billing and payment options that support you in collecting or paying your revenue share, depending on your contracts with the seller organizations and the operator:</p>
                                    <ul>
                                                <li>You can view the revenue share that is defined. </li>
                                                <li>You can retrieve and export information on the actual revenue.</li>
                                    </ul>
                                    <p>For details, refer to the following sections.</p>
                        </section>
                        <section>
                                    <title>Viewing the Revenue Share</title>
                                    <p>You can view the percentage you receive from the total revenue generated by the services offered on your marketplace.</p>
                                    <p>For this purpose, use the <uicontrol>Update marketplace</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Marketplace</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> administration portal. The menu option displays the features and settings that are currently defined for your marketplace. You can view the revenue share you receive as the marketplace owner as well as the revenue shares that brokers and resellers receive who publish services to your marketplace.</p>
                        </section>
                        <section>
                                    <title>Exporting Revenue Share Data</title>
                                    <p>As users work with the services offered on your marketplace, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> automatically calculates the charges based on the related price models. At regular intervals, it generates the billing data for the customers' service usage as well as the revenue share data for each marketplace. Discounts granted by a supplier to his customers are deducted from the revenue shares. </p>
                                    <p>To retrieve information on your actual revenue for a specific time frame, <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                            /> allows you to export the corresponding data. To do this, use the <uicontrol>Export billing data</uicontrol> menu option in the <uicontrol>Account</uicontrol> menu of the <ph
                                                            conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                                                /> administration portal. </p>
                                    <p>The data can be saved to an XML file or opened in an editor of your choice. You can edit it and work with it as required. The data can, for example, be forwarded to an accounting system. You can use it as the basis for collecting your revenue share or paying others, depending on your contracts with the seller organizations and the operator.</p>
                                    <p><ph id="You_find_a_detailed_descripti_concept_conbody_section_p_5">For a detailed description of the elements and attributes that may occur in the XML file, refer to <xref href="../../DevelopersGuide/Reference/r_BillingData.xml"/>.</ph></p>
                        </section>
            </conbody>
</concept>
