<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>

<reference id="reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Customer Billing Data</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>The charges for the usage of a service in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> are calculated based on the price model defined for the service, customer, or subscription. </p>
            <p id="A_supplier_can_export_the_bil_reference_refbody_section_p"
                >A supplier or reseller can export the billing data for one or several of his customers for a specific time. Suppliers also have access to the billing data of customers of broker organizations that sell their services. The exported data can be forwarded, for example, to an accounting system for further processing.</p>
            <p>The result of the export is stored in an XML file, the customer billing data file. The billing data file conforms to the XML schema <codeph>BillingResult.xsd</codeph>, which can be found in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> integration package. </p>
            <p>The billing data file is named <codeph>&lt;date&gt;BillingData.xml</codeph>, where <codeph>&lt;date&gt;</codeph> represents the creation date.</p>
            <p>This appendix describes the meaning of the elements and attributes that may occur in a billing data file. </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>BillingDetails</title>
            <p>Top-level container element of a billing data file. For each subscription, a <codeph>BillingDetails</codeph> element is added to the billing data file. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>BillingDetails</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>Period</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Period_reference_refbody_section_3"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>OrganizationDetails</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/OrganizationDetails_reference_refbody_section_4"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>Subscriptions</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Subscriptions_reference_refbody_section_9"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>OverallCosts</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/OverallCosts_reference_refbody_section_12"
                    />)</ph></li>
            </ul>
            <p>A <codeph>BillingDetails</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <p><codeph><b>key</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>long</codeph>) <ph
                    id="Unique_identifier_allowing_f_reference_refbody_section_2"><ph
                        id="Unique_identifier_allowing_f_reference_refbody_sub_2"
                        >Unique identifier allowing, for example, accounting systems to relate billing data to an invoice. The billing data key is printed on the invoice.</ph> Suppliers and customers may use the billing data key to create a detailed billing report for an existing invoice or subscription. A supplier can retrieve the key from a billing report, a customer gets the billing data key from the corresponding invoice.</ph></p>
            <p><codeph><b>timezone</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Time zone based on the UTC time standard. It reflects the standard server time without daylight saving time. For example, 18:00:00 o'clock on June 1st in Berlin (UTC+1) will be output as follows in the XML file: </p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails <b>timezone="UTC+01:00"</b> key="31122">
  &lt;Period startDate="1370106000000" 
  <b>startDateIsoFormat="2013-06-01T16:00:00.000Z"</b> ..."/>
</codeblock>
            </p>
            <p>The time zone is relevant for price models with costs<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
                />)</ph>. </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Period_reference_refbody_section_3">
            <title>Period</title>
            <p>Specifies the billing period for which the data is exported. The start and end time of the billing period are output according to the start day of the billing period which was defined by the supplier or reseller.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>Period</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul id="startDate_reference_refbody_section_3">
                <li><codeph><b>startDate</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>long</codeph>) Start time of the period. The start time is specified in milliseconds, the starting point for the calculation is <codeph>1970-01-01</codeph>, <codeph>00:00</codeph>. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>startDateIsoFormat</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>dateTime</codeph>) Same as <codeph>startDate</codeph>, but specified in ISO 8601 format (<codeph>YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.fffZ</codeph>) . </li>
                <li><codeph><b>endDate</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>long</codeph>) End time of the period. The end time is specified in milliseconds, the starting point for the calculation is <codeph>1970-01-01</codeph>, <codeph>00:00</codeph>. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>endDateIsoFormat</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>dateTime</codeph>) Same as <codeph>endDate</codeph>, but specified in ISO 8601 format (<codeph>YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.fffZ</codeph>). </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock><b>&lt;Period startDateIsoFormat="2012-08-31T22:00:00.000Z" 
  startDate="1346450400000" 
  endDateIsoFormat="2012-09-30T22:00:00.000Z" 
  endDate="1349042400000"/>
</b></codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="OrganizationDetails_reference_refbody_section_4">
            <title>OrganizationDetails</title>
            <p>Provides details of the customer for which the billing data have been exported. The details may include a <codeph>Udas</codeph> element with custom attributes that store additional information on the customer organization.</p>
            <p>An <codeph>OrganizationDetails</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <p><b>Email</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the email address of the organization (data type <codeph>string</codeph>).</p>
            <p><b>Name</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the name of the organization (data type <codeph>string</codeph>).</p>
            <p><b>Address</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the address of the organization (data type <codeph>string</codeph>).</p>
            <p><b>Paymenttype</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the payment type used for subscriptions of the organization (data type <codeph>string</codeph>).</p>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00">
...
<b>  &lt;OrganizationDetails&gt;
    &lt;Email>info@company.com&lt;/Email>
    &lt;Name>company&lt;/Name>
    &lt;Address>Street&lt;/Address>
    &lt;Paymenttype>INVOICE&lt;/Paymenttype>
  &lt;/OrganizationDetails&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Subscriptions_reference_refbody_section_9">
            <title>Subscriptions</title>
            <p>Contains the billing data for the subscriptions of the customer which are relevant for the current billing period. </p>
            <p>For every subscription of an organization, the <codeph>Subscriptions</codeph> element contains a <codeph>Subscription</codeph> element. In this element, the costs of the affected subscription are specified. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>Subscription</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Unique subscription name. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>purchaseOrderNumber</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Optional reference number as specified by the customer when subscribing to a service.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>A <codeph>Subscription</codeph> element contains a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element with the billing data for the price model of the subscription<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
            />)</ph>. A <codeph>Udas</codeph> element with custom attributes that store additional information on the subscription may also be included<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Udas_reference_refbody_section_27" />)</ph>.</p>
            <p>If a subscription is assigned to an organizational unit at the end of the billing period, the <codeph>Subscription</codeph> element also contains an <codeph>OrganizationalUnit</codeph> element with the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>name</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Required name of the organizational unit to which the subscription is assigned.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>referenceID</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Optional reference ID of the organizational unit to which the subscription is assigned.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Be aware that the organizational units to which the subscription may have been assigned before the generation of the billing data are not shown.</p>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00">
...
<b>  &lt;Subscriptions&gt;
    &lt;Subscription id="Mega Office Basic" purchaseOrderNumber="12345"&gt;
      &lt;OrganizationalUnit name="ProjectTeam" referenceID="123abc"/&gt;
      &lt;PriceModels&gt;
        &lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
...
        &lt;/PriceModel&gt;
      &lt;/PriceModels&gt;      
    &lt;/Subscription&gt;
  &lt;/Subscriptions&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Udas_reference_refbody_section_27">
            <title>Udas</title>
            <p>Contains custom attributes that store additional information on an organization or subscription. This could be, for example, the profit center to which a customer's revenue is to be accounted. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>Udas</codeph> element may be included in an <codeph>OrganizationDetails</codeph> or a <codeph>Subscription</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>For every custom attribute, a <codeph>Uda</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>Udas</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>Uda</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) ID of the custom attribute. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>value</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Value of the custom attribute. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00">
...
  &lt;Subscriptions&gt;
    &lt;Subscription id="Mega Office Basic" purchaseOrderNumber="12345"&gt;
...
<b>      &lt;Udas&gt;
        &lt;Uda id="Profit Center" value="My Company"/&gt;
      &lt;/Udas&gt;
    &lt;/Subscription&gt;
  &lt;/Subscriptions&gt;</b>
...
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7">
            <title>PriceModel</title>
            <p>Contains the billing data for a price model used to calculate the utilization charges for a subscription. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element is included in every subscription element. It contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>UsagePeriod</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/UsagePeriod_reference_refbody_section_3"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>GatheredEvents</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/GatheredEvents_reference_refbody_section_14"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>PeriodFee</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PeriodFee_PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_20"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/UserAssignmentCosts_PriceMod_reference_refbody_section_21"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>OneTimeFee</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/OneTimeFee_reference_refbody_section_23"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>PriceModelCosts</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModelCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    />)</ph></li>
                <li><codeph>Parameters</codeph><ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Parameters_reference_refbody_section_25"
                    />)</ph></li>
            </ul>
            <p>A <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Unique name identifying the price model.</p>
            <p><codeph><b>calculationMode</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Cost calculation option of the price model. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>FREE_OF_CHARGE</codeph> (the service is free of charge), <codeph>PRO_RATA</codeph> (the costs are calculated exactly for the time a service is used, based on milliseconds), <codeph>PER_UNIT</codeph> (the costs are calculated based on fixed time units).</p>
        </section>
        <section id="UsagePeriod_reference_refbody_section_3">
            <title>UsagePeriod</title>
            <p>Specifies the actual period in which a price model is used for calculating the charges of a subscription. </p>
            <p>A usage period usually begins when a customer subscribes to a service and ends when the subscription is terminated. In case a free trial period is defined for the service, the usage period begins when the free trial period has ended. When the customer upgrades or downgrades the subscription, a new usage period is started in which the price model of the new service is applied. If the customer changes elements that determine how the charges for the service are calculated (e.g. the number of assigned users, the service roles of the assigned users, or the parameter values), a new usage period is started in which the updated elements are applied.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>UsagePeriod</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>UsagePeriod</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul conref="#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/startDate_reference_refbody_section_3">
                <li/>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
<b>  &lt;UsagePeriod endDate="1306879200000" 
   endDateIsoFormat="2011-05-31T22:00:00.000Z" 
   startDate="1304755088065" 
   startDateIsoFormat="2011-05-07T07:58:08.065Z"/&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="GatheredEvents_reference_refbody_section_14">
            <title>GatheredEvents</title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for all chargeable events that occurred in the current usage period of the subscription. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_events.xml#reference832/These_include_for_example_l_reference_refbody_section_1"
                /></p>
            <p>A <codeph>GatheredEvents</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>GatheredEvents</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>Event</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>GatheredEventsCosts</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Event</b></p>
            <p>For every event, an <codeph>Event</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>GatheredEvents</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>An <codeph>Event</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Event ID as specified in the technical service definition.</p>
            <p> An <codeph>Event</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>Description</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>SingleCost</codeph>
                </li>
                <li><codeph>NumberOfOccurence</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>CostForEventType</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Description</b></p>
            <p>Contains the description of the event. </p>
            <p><b>SingleCost</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the price for the event as defined in the price model. If an event has stepped prices, this element is omitted. A <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element is included instead<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26"
                />)</ph>. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>SingleCost</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Price for a single event. </p>
            <p><b>NumberOfOccurence</b></p>
            <p>Specifies how often the event occurred.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>NumberOfOccurence</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>long</codeph>) Number of times the event occurred.</p>
            <p><b>CostForEventType</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for the event in the billing period. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>CostForEventType</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the event. The total costs for an event are calculated from the singular costs (<codeph>SingleCost</codeph>) multiplied with the number of occurrences (<codeph>NumberOfOccurence</codeph>). If role-based costs and/or stepped prices are specified for events, these costs are added<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    /> and <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26"
                />)</ph>. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p><b>GatheredEventsCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for all events in the current <codeph>GatheredEvents</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>GatheredEventsCosts</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for events. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;GatheredEvents&gt;
    &lt;Event id="USER_LOGOUT_FROM_SERVICE"&gt;
      &lt;Description xml:lang="en"&gt;Logout from the service.&lt;/Description&gt;
      &lt;SingleCost amount="100.00"/&gt;
      &lt;NumberOfOccurrence amount="3"/&gt;
      &lt;CostForEventType amount="300.00"/&gt;
    &lt;/Event&gt;
...
    &lt;GatheredEventsCosts amount="1200.00"/&gt;
  &lt;/GatheredEvents&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="PeriodFee_PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_20">
            <title>PeriodFee </title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for using the subscription in the given usage period. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_recurringForSub.xml#reference832/For_each_subscription_a_char_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>The calculation of the charges depends on the cost calculation option which was chosen for the price model<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
                /> for details)</ph>. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge per base period according to the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the period fee for the subscription. The factor is calculated from the usage period of the subscription divided by the base period (<codeph>basePeriod</codeph>). The recurring charge is multiplied with this factor to calculate the total costs (<codeph>price</codeph>).</li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total period fee for the subscription. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factor (<codeph>factor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;PeriodFee basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="10.00" factor="0.4020212567204301" price="4.02"/&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="UserAssignmentCosts_PriceMod_reference_refbody_section_21">
            <title>UserAssignmentCosts </title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for the user assignments to the subscription.</p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_recurringForUser.xml#reference832/For_every_user_assigned_to_a_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_recurringForUser.xml#reference832/The_recurring_charge_for_user_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>For this type of charge, stepped prices can be applied: Recurring charges can be defined that depend on the sum of the time units of all user assignments.</p>
            <p>The calculation of the charges depends on the cost calculation option which was chosen for the price model<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
                /> for details)</ph>.</p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_recurringForUser.xml#reference832/With_per_time_unit_calculatio_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge for users per base period according to the price model. If the charge for users has stepped prices, this attribute is omitted.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for the user assignments. The factor is calculated by summing up the factors for each user specified in the <codeph>UserAssignmentCostsByUser</codeph> element. The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>). </li>
                <li><codeph><b>numberOfUsersTotal</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>long</codeph>) Number of users assigned to the subscription in the usage period. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>total</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the user assignments including role-based costs and stepped prices. The value is rounded to two decimal places.<ph audience="doc"> For details on role-based costs and stepped prices, refer to <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                        /> and <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26"
                    />.</ph> </li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for the user assignments. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factor (<codeph>factor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element contains the following subelement. If role-based costs and/or stepped prices are specified, a <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element and/or <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element is also present<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    /> and <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26"
                />)</ph>.</p>
            <p><b>UserAssignmentCostsByUser</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the fraction of the usage period a user was assigned to the subscription. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCostsByUser</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Fraction of the usage period the given user was assigned to the subscription. The factors of the single user assignments are summed up to calculate the total costs for the user assignments.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>userId</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) User ID.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="18000"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;UserAssignmentCosts basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="19.00" 
   factor="0.5337726052867383" numberOfUsersTotal="2" 
   total ="50.00" price="10.14">
     &lt;UserAssignmentCostsByUser factor="1.0499215949820788E-4" 
     userId="admin"/>
     &lt;UserAssignmentCostsByUser factor="0.5336676131272401" 
     userId="miller"/>
   &lt;/UserAssignmentCosts>
</b>...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="OneTimeFee_reference_refbody_section_23">
            <title>OneTimeFee</title>
            <p>Specifies the one-time fee for the subscription.</p>
            <p>A one-time fee defines the amount a customer has to pay for a subscription in the first billing period of the subscription. It is added to the total charges for the first billing period. It is independent of the number of users, events, or other usage data.</p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_onetime.xml#reference832/If_a_one-time_fee_is_defined_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>A <codeph>OneTimeFee</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>OneTimeFee</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the one-time fee. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>baseAmount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) One-time fee as defined in the price model.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>long</codeph>) Factor used for calculating the one-time fee. Since this charge occurs only once, the factor is 1 for the first billing period, and 0 in case the one-time fee has already been charged in a previous billing period. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;OneTimeFee amount="10.00" baseAmount="10.00" factor="1"/&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="PriceModelCosts_reference_refbody_section_24">
            <title>PriceModelCosts</title>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for the subscription in the current usage period. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>PriceModelCosts</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>PriceModelCosts</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>currency</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) ISO code of the currency in which the costs are calculated. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total amount of the costs for the subscription. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="14001"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;PriceModelCosts currency="EUR" amount="990.00"/&gt;
</b>&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Parameters_reference_refbody_section_25">
            <title>Parameters</title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for parameters defined for the service underlying the subscription. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/A_price_model_can_define_pric_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>A price can be defined for every parameter and option, and the price can be charged per subscription or per user assigned to the subscription. <ph
                    id="and_specify_whether_this_pric_reference_refbody_section_1"
                        >Numeric parameters are a multiplier for the price. For boolean parameters, the multiplier is <codeph>1</codeph> if the value is <codeph>true</codeph>. In all other cases, the multiplier is <codeph>0</codeph>.</ph></p>
            <p>The calculation of charges for parameters and options depends on the cost calculation option which was chosen for the price model<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
                /> for details)</ph>.</p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/If_the_charges_for_a_subscrip_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/For_numeric_parameters_stepp_reference_refbody_section_1"
                /></p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_parameters.xml#reference832/The_prices_for_parameters_and_reference_refbody_section_2"/>
            <p>A <codeph>Parameters</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>Parameters</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>Parameter</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>ParametersCosts</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Parameter</b></p>
            <p>For every parameter, a <codeph>Parameter</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>Parameters</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>Parameter</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Parameter ID.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>Parameter</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>ParameterUsagePeriod</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>ParameterValue</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>PeriodFee</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>ParameterCosts</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>Options</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>ParameterUsagePeriod</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the actual usage period for the parameter. </p>
            <p>The usage period for a parameter begins when a customer subscribes to the service with the given parameter definition in the price model and ends when the subscription is terminated. </p>
            <p>In case a free trial period is defined for the service, the usage period for the subscription begins when the free trial period has ended. If a parameter value is changed, a new usage period is started in which the updated value is applied for calculating the costs.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>ParameterUsagePeriod</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul conref="#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/startDate_reference_refbody_section_3">
                <li/>
            </ul>
            <p><b>ParameterValue</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the costs and data type for the parameter.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>ParameterValue</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Costs for the parameter as defined in the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>type</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Data type of the parameter. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>BOOLEAN</codeph>, <codeph>INTEGER</codeph>, <codeph>LONG</codeph>, <codeph>STRING</codeph>, <codeph>ENUMERATION</codeph>, <codeph>DURATION</codeph>.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>PeriodFee</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the costs for using the parameter in the given usage period. If a parameter has stepped prices, a <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge per base period according to the price model. If a parameter has stepped prices, this attribute is omitted.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for using the parameter. The factor is calculated from the usage period divided by the base period (<codeph>basePeriod</codeph>). The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>).</li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for using the parameter. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factors (<codeph>factor</codeph> and <codeph>valueFactor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>valueFactor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>float</codeph>) Factor to calculate the total costs for using the parameter depending on the parameter value. The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>). This factor is set depending on the data type of the parameter. For numeric parameters it is set to the value of the parameter. For boolean parameters, the factor is set to <codeph>1</codeph> if the value is <codeph>true</codeph>. In all other cases, the factor is set to <codeph>0</codeph>. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>UserAssignmentCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the costs for the parameter related to the user assignments of the subscription based on the price per user for the parameter as defined in the price model. If costs for service roles are defined, a <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                /> for details)</ph>. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge for users per base period for the parameter according to the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for using the parameter. The factor is calculated from the parameter usage period divided by the base period (<codeph>basePeriod</codeph>) multiplied with the number of users. The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>).</li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for using the parameter. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factors (<codeph>factor</codeph> and <codeph>valueFactor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places. If stepped prices are defined for user assignments, the costs are given in the <codeph>price</codeph> attribute.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>total</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for using the parameter including role-based costs. The value is rounded to two decimal places.<ph audience="doc"> For details on role-based costs, refer to <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    />.</ph> </li>
                <li><codeph><b>valueFactor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>float</codeph>) Factor to calculate the total costs for using the parameter depending on the parameter value. The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>). This factor is set depending on the data type of the parameter. For numeric parameters it is set to the value of the parameter. For boolean parameters, the factor is set to <codeph>1</codeph> if the value is <codeph>true</codeph>. In all other cases, the factor is set to <codeph>0</codeph>. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>ParameterCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for using the parameter.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>ParameterCosts</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the parameter calculated by summing up the costs specified in the <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> and the <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element for the parameter and its options. If role-based costs and/or stepped prices are specified for the parameter, these are added<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    /> and <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26"
                />)</ph>. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p><b>ParametersCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for all parameters. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>ParametersCosts</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the parameters calculated by summing up the costs of the individual parameters as specified in the <codeph>ParameterCosts</codeph> elements. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Parameters&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;Parameter id="MAX_FOLDER_NUMBER2">
    &lt;ParameterUsagePeriod endDate="1306879200000" 
     endDateIsoFormat="2011-05-31T22:00:00.000Z" 
     startDate="1304755088065" 
     startDateIsoFormat="2011-05-07T07:58:08.065Z"/&gt;
    &lt;ParameterValue amount="200" type="INTEGER"/>
    &lt;PeriodFee basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="0.00" 
     factor="0.5337789669205496" price="0.00" valueFactor="200.0"/>
    &lt;UserAssignmentCosts basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="0.00" 
     factor="0.5337726052867383" total ="0.00" 
     price="0.00" valueFactor="200.0"/>
    &lt;ParameterCosts amount="0.00"/>
  &lt;/Parameter>

...
  &lt;ParametersCosts amount="600.00"/&gt;
</b>&lt;/Parameters&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>Options</title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for parameter options. </p>
            <p>An <codeph>Options</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>Parameter</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>For every option, an <codeph>Option</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>Options</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>An <codeph>Option</codeph> element has the following attribute: </p>
            <p><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Option ID.</p>
            <p>An <codeph>Option</codeph> element contains the following subelements:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>PeriodFee</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph></li>
                <li><codeph>OptionCosts</codeph></li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>PeriodFee</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the costs for using the parameter option in the given usage period. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge per base period according to the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for using the parameter option. The factor is calculated from the usage period divided by the base period (<codeph>basePeriod</codeph>). The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the total costs (<codeph>price</codeph>).</li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for the parameter option. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factor (<codeph>factor</codeph>), and is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>UserAssignmentCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the costs for the parameter option related to the user assignments of the subscription based on the price per user for the option as defined in the price model. If costs for service roles are defined, a <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                />)</ph>. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>basePeriod</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Period on which the charges are based. Can be set to one of the following values: <codeph>MONTH</codeph>, <codeph>WEEK</codeph>, <codeph>DAY</codeph>, <codeph>HOUR</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge for users per base period for the parameter option according to the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for using the parameter option. The factor is calculated from the usage period divided by the base period (<codeph>basePeriod</codeph>). The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>). </li>
                <li><codeph><b>total</b></codeph> - (data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for using the parameter option including role-based costs. The value is rounded to two decimal places.<ph audience="doc"> For details on role-based costs, refer to <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24"
                    />.</ph> </li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for using the parameter option. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factor (<codeph>factor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places. If stepped prices are defined for user assignments, the costs are given in the <codeph>price</codeph> attribute.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>OptionCosts</b></p>
            <p>Specifies the total costs for using the parameter option.</p>
            <p>An <codeph>OptionCosts</codeph> element has the following attribute:</p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total costs for the parameter option calculated by summing up the costs specified in the <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> and the <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Parameter id="MEMORY_STORAGE"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;Options&gt;
    &lt;Option id="2"&gt;
      &lt;PeriodFee basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="100.00" 
       factor="1.0" price="100.00"/&gt;
      &lt;UserAssignmentCosts basePeriod="MONTH" basePrice="0.00" 
       factor="1.0" total ="0.00" price="0.00"/&gt;
      &lt;OptionCosts amount="100.00"/&gt;
    &lt;/Option&gt;
  &lt;/Options&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/Parameter&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="RoleCosts_reference_refbody_section_24">
            <title>RoleCosts</title>
            <p>Specifies the costs for service roles. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_role.xml#reference832/If_defined_for_the_underlying_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>For each role, a price can be defined. This price is added to the base price per user in the cost calculation for a billing period.</p>
            <p>The calculation of the charges for service roles depends on the cost calculation option which was chosen for the price model<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/PriceModel_reference_refbody_section_7"
                /> for details)</ph>. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_role.xml#reference832/If_the_charges_are_calculated_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_role.xml#reference832/If_the_charges_are_calculated_reference_refbody_section_2"/>
            <p>A <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element is contained in a <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> element (as subelement of the <codeph>PriceModel</codeph>, <codeph>Parameters</codeph>, or <codeph>Option</codeph> element).</p>
            <p>A <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element has the following attribute: </p>
            <p><codeph><b>total</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Total amount of costs for the service roles. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</p>
            <p>For every service role, a <codeph>RoleCost</codeph> element is included in the <codeph>RoleCosts</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>RoleCost</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>id</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) ID of the service role.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Recurring charge for the service role according to the price model.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>factor</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for the service role. The factor is calculated as a fraction of the actual usage period. The recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) is multiplied with this factor to calculate the costs (<codeph>price</codeph>). </li>
                <li><codeph><b>price</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for the service role. This value is calculated from the recurring charge (<codeph>basePrice</codeph>) multiplied with the factor (<codeph>factor</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;Parameter id="MEMORY_STORAGE"&gt;
...
<b>  &lt;RoleCosts total="0.00"&gt;
    &lt;RoleCost basePrice="0.00" factor="0.4020087753882915" 
     id="USER" price="0.00"/&gt;
    &lt;RoleCost basePrice="0.00" factor="0.8040175186678614" 
     id="ADMIN" price="0.00"/&gt;
  &lt;/RoleCosts&gt;
</b>...
&lt;/Parameter&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="SteppedPrices_reference_refbody_section_26">
            <title>SteppedPrices</title>
            <p>Specifies the stepped prices for a user assignment, event, or parameter. </p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml#reference832/Stepped_pricing_allows_for_th_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <ul>
                <li
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml#reference832/Number_of_users_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
                <li
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml#reference832/Number_of_events_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
                <li
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml#reference832/Values_of_numeric_parameters_reference_refbody_section_1"
                />
            </ul>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_stepped.xml#reference832/Stepped_pricing_is_independen_reference_refbody_section_1"/>
            <p>A <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element is contained in <codeph>UserAssignmentCosts</codeph> (as subelement of the <codeph>PriceModel</codeph> element), <codeph>Event</codeph>, and <codeph>PeriodFee</codeph> (as subelement of the <codeph>Parameters</codeph> element) elements. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element has the following attribute: </p>
            <p><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Summed up costs for all steps including the last one. </p>
            <p>For every price step, a <codeph>SteppedPrice</codeph> element is included in a <codeph>SteppedPrices</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>SteppedPrice</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>additionalPrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Summed up costs for the previous steps. The costs are calculated from the <codeph>limit</codeph>, <codeph>freeAmount</codeph> and <codeph>basePrice</codeph> attributes of the previous step (<codeph>(limit - freeAmount) * price</codeph>). The <codeph>additionalPrice</codeph> attribute of the first step always has a value of <codeph>0</codeph>. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>basePrice</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Costs for the current step according to the price model. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>freeAmount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>long</codeph>) Amount of units for the current step that are considered as a fixed discount, for example, the number of users that are free of charge. The value corresponds to the value of the <codeph>limit</codeph> attribute in the previous step. The <codeph>freeAmount</codeph> attribute of the first step always has a value of <codeph>0</codeph>.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>limit</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) Step limit as defined in the price model.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>stepAmount</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Summed up costs for the current step. These costs are calculated from the <codeph>basePrice</codeph> and <codeph>stepEntityCount</codeph> attributes of the current step. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>stepEntityCount</b></codeph> - (optional, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Factor used to calculate the costs for the current step. </li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;PriceModel calculationMode="PRO_RATA" id="350001"&gt;
...
  &lt;UserAssignmentCosts basePeriod="MONTH" factor="2.707940780619112" numberOfUsersTotal="4" price="1283.18">
<b>    &lt;SteppedPrices amount="1283.18">
      &lt;SteppedPrice additionalPrice="0.00" basePrice="500.00" 
       freeAmount="0" limit="2" stepAmount="1000.00" stepEntityCount="2"/>
      &lt;SteppedPrice additionalPrice="1000.00" basePrice="400.00" 
       freeAmount="2" limit="3" stepAmount="283.18" 
       stepEntityCount="0.707940780619112"/>
      &lt;SteppedPrice additionalPrice="1400.00" basePrice="300.00" 
       freeAmount="3" limit="null" stepAmount="0.00" stepEntityCount="0"/>
    &lt;/SteppedPrices></b>
  &lt;/UserAssignmentCosts>
...
&lt;/PriceModel&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="OverallCosts_reference_refbody_section_12">
            <title>OverallCosts</title>
            <p>Contains the total amount of the charges to be paid by a customer for all subscriptions in the current billing period. The costs are given in the currency specified in the price model. </p>
            <p>If a discount was specified, the net amount of the costs is given in the <codeph>Discount</codeph> element<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Discount_reference_refbody_section_25"
            />)</ph>. If a VAT rate was defined, it is given in the <codeph>VAT</codeph> element<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                    href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/VAT_reference_refbody_section_26"
                />)</ph>.</p>
            <p>An <codeph>OverallCosts</codeph> element has the following attributes:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>netAmount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Net costs after the net discount has been deducted from the original net costs<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/Discount_reference_refbody_section_25"
                    />)</ph>. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>currency</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>string</codeph>) ISO code of the currency in which the costs are calculated. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>grossAmount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Gross amount of the costs, calculated from the net costs (<codeph>netAmount</codeph>) plus VAT<ph audience="doc"> (see <xref
                        href="r_BillingData.xml#reference_25043B5D1DED4B2F9D5E9B099A9AC69C/VAT_reference_refbody_section_26"
                    />)</ph>. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00">
...
<b>&lt;OverallCosts netAmount="900.00" currency="EUR" grossAmount="1053.00"/>    
&lt;/OverallCosts></b>
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="VAT_reference_refbody_section_26">
            <title>VAT</title>
            <p>Specifies the VAT rate to be applied.</p>
            <p>A supplier can define a basic VAT rate that applies by default to all prices for his customers. In addition to this basic VAT rate, country-specific or even customer-specific VAT rates can be defined. You can:</p>
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/Enable_VAT_rate_support_for_y_task_taskbody_context_p_2_u"/>
                    <li
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/Define_a_default_VAT_rate_tha_task_taskbody_context_p_2_u"/>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/Define_a_country-specific_VAT_task_taskbody_context_p_2_u"
                        /></li>
                    <li><ph
                            conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/Define_a_customer-specific_VA_task_taskbody_context_p_2_u"
                        /></li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/The_VAT_rate_settings_have_th_task_taskbody_context_p_3_ph"
                /></p>
            <ul>
                <li><ph
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/If_VAT_rate_support_is_disabl_task_taskbody_context_ul_li"
                    /></li>
                <li><ph
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/A_customer-specific_VAT_rate_task_taskbody_context_ul_li"
                    /></li>
                <li><ph
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/The_country-specific_VAT_rate_task_taskbody_context_ul_li"
                    /></li>
                <li><ph
                        conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/The_default_VAT_rate_is_used_task_taskbody_context_ul_li"
                    /></li>
            </ul>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../help/tasks/organization_manageVats.xml#task634/The_VAT_rate_does_not_affect_task_taskbody_context_p_4_ph"
                /></p>
            <p>A <codeph>VAT</codeph> element is contained in the <codeph>OverallCosts</codeph> element. </p>
            <p>A <codeph>VAT</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>percent</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>float</codeph>) VAT rate in percent, specified as a decimal number. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>amount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Net amount of VAT to be added to the net costs (<codeph>netAmount</codeph> attribute of the <codeph>OverallCosts</codeph> element). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00"&gt;
...
  &lt;OverallCosts netAmount="900.00" currency="EUR" grossAmount="1053.00"&gt;
    <b>&lt;VAT percent="17.0" amount="153.00"/&gt;</b>
  &lt;/OverallCosts&gt;
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section id="Discount_reference_refbody_section_25">
            <title>Discount</title>
            <p>Specifies the discount granted to the customer. </p>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_discount.xml#reference832/For_each_customer_organizatio_reference_refbody_section_p"
                /></p>
            <p><ph
                    conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_discount.xml#reference832/The_discount_is_defined_as_a_reference_refbody_section_p"
                /></p>
            <p
                conref="../../Shared/reference/r_PriceModelDetails_discount.xml#reference832/A_discount_is_completely_inde_reference_refbody_section_p"/>
            <p>A <codeph>Discount</codeph> element is contained in the <codeph>OverallCosts</codeph> element.</p>
            <p>A <codeph>Discount</codeph> element has the following attributes: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph><b>percent</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>float</codeph>) Percentage of costs to be deducted from the net costs, specified as a decimal number. </li>
                <li><codeph><b>discountNetAmount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Net discount to be deducted from the original net costs (<codeph>netAmountBeforeDiscount</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>netAmountAfterDiscount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Net costs after the net discount (<codeph>discountNetAmount</codeph>) has been deducted from the original net costs (<codeph>netAmountBeforeDiscount</codeph>). The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
                <li><codeph><b>netAmountBeforeDiscount</b></codeph> - (required, data type <codeph>decimal</codeph>) Net costs before the net discount (<codeph>discountNetAmount</codeph>) has been deducted. The value is rounded to two decimal places.</li>
            </ul>
            <p><b>Example</b>:</p>
            <p>
                <codeblock>&lt;BillingDetails key="10002" timezone="UTC+01:00"&gt;
...
  &lt;OverallCosts netAmount="900.00" currency="EUR" grossAmount="1053.00">
<b>    &lt;Discount percent="10.00" discountNetAmount="100.00" 
     netAmountAfterDiscount="900.00"
     netAmountBeforeDiscount="1000.00" /&gt;</b>
    &lt;VAT percent="17.0" amount="153.00"/&gt;
  &lt;/OverallCosts&gt;
&lt;/BillingDetails&gt;</codeblock>
            </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
