<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU LIMITED 2018 -->
<!DOCTYPE reference PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Reference//EN"
                           "reference.dtd" [<!ENTITY % entities PUBLIC '-//XDOC//ENTITIES//FujitsuUserDoc' 'entities.dtd'>
]>
<reference id="Revenue_Share_Data_266" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Revenue Share Data</title>
    <refbody>
        <section>
            <p>In extended usage scenarios, suppliers may involve brokers and resellers in selling their services. The brokers and resellers as well as the platform operator and the owners of the marketplaces on which the services are published, usually receive a share of the revenue for the services. <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> calculates these revenue shares based on the billing data for the customers who use the services.</p>
            <p id="A_supplier_can_export_the_bil_reference_refbody_section_p"
                >Suppliers, brokers, resellers, and marketplace owners can generate reports for their revenue shares and export the revenue share data for a specific time. Operators can export the data for all the suppliers, brokers, resellers, or marketplace owners known to their platform installation. The exported data can be forwarded, for example, to an accounting system for further processing. </p>
            <p>The result of the export is stored in an XML file, the revenue data file. The file conforms to one of the following schemas, depending on the type of the revenue share data: </p>
            <ul>
                <li><codeph>BrokerRevenueShareResult.xsd</codeph> : revenue share data for brokers</li>
                <li><codeph>ResellerRevenueShareResult.xsd</codeph> : revenue share data for resellers</li>
                <li><codeph>MPOwnerRevenueShareResult.xsd</codeph> : revenue share data for marketplace owners </li>
                <li><codeph>SupplierRevenueShareResult.xsd</codeph> : revenue share data for suppliers</li>
            </ul>
            <p>Each of these schemas includes the <codeph>BillingBase.xsd</codeph> with common definitions. All the schemas can be found in the <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"/> integration package. </p>
            <p>The XML files containing the revenue share data are named <codeph>&lt;date&gt;BillingData.xml</codeph>, where <codeph>&lt;date&gt;</codeph> represents the creation date.</p>
            <p>This appendix describes the meaning of the elements and attributes that may occur in the different types of revenue share data file. The first section explains elements and attributes that are common to all revenue share data files. The subsequent sections describe the individual files. </p>
        </section>
    </refbody>
</reference>
