<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>  
<!-- Copyright FUJITSU ENABLING SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY GMBH 2021 -->
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
                         "concept.dtd">
<concept id="Auth" xml:lang="en-us">
    <title>Authentication Mode</title>
    <conbody>
        <section>
            <p>Before starting to install <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                />, you must decide on how users and Web services are to be authenticated. </p>
            <p>The following sections explain the supported scenarios.</p>
        </section>
        <section conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_AuthenticationMode.xml#Auth/auth_internal"/>
        <section><p>It is recommended to use the INTERNAL authentication mode if Web browser single sign-on is not required, and if your customers are to be able to register themselves. </p></section>
        <section conref="../../Shared/concepts/c_AuthenticationMode.xml#Auth/auth_saml"/>
        <section>
            <p>It is recommended to use the SAML_SP authentication mode if you want to operate <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> in a company network and use existing authentication mechanisms that support the SAML 2.0 standard. Customer self-registration is not supported in this case, and should thus be disabled.</p>
            <p>
                <note>When operating <ph conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> in SAML_SP mode, every Web service client must run in a separate domain of the application server.</note>
            </p>
        </section>
        <section><b>Required Information From the IdP Operator:</b><p>When using <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                    /> in SAML_SP mode, additional configuration settings in <ph
                    conref="../../Shared/Product_Name.xml#ProductNameTopic/Product_Abbr"
                /> are required. To be able to specify values for these settings, you require the following: </p><ol
                compact="no">
                <li>A contractual relationship with the IdP operator so that the IdP can allow for Web browser SSO and secure Web service calls using a Security Token Service (STS).</li>
                <li>
                    <p>Ask the IdP operator to provide the following:</p>
                    <p>
                        <ul compact="no">
                            <li>The public key certificate of the IdP system. </li>
                            <li>The Entity ID of the IdP system. He can find out the ID by retrieving the federation metadata in the IdP system. </li>
                            <li>The length of the encryption key used by the IdP system.</li>
                            <li>Information on whether the IdP system can process <codeph>GET</codeph> or <codeph>POST</codeph> authentication requests.</li>
                            <li>For Web browser SSO: the SAML Redirect URL of the IdP as well as the URL of the single logout service endpoint.</li>
                            <li>For STS connections: the STS service endpoint URL as well as the URL pointing to the MEX address (Issuer Metadata Exchange) of the STS. </li>
                        </ul>
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol></section>
    </conbody>
</concept>
